<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>KDE Plasma renaming shortcuts turns them into matlab script</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911</link>
    <description>I recently switched from Whonix 13 to Whonix 14 which uses KDE Plasma. So I&#39;m still getting used to KDE Plasma and its quirks. I changed KDE Plasma&#39;s desktop into the folder view so it behaves similar to KDE in Whonix 13.
 
However if I rename a shortcut on the desktop, the file properties change because when I click on properties it&#39;s associated as a *.MATLAB script. And indeed when I try to open it, it opens up KWrite instead of executing what the shortcut is pointing to.

I tried googling for a fix since it&#39;s not a whonix specific issue, but rather an issue with KDE Plasma, but I&#39;m wondering if anyone else experienced this problem and knows of a solution?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 22:47:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>KDE Plasma renaming shortcuts turns them into matlab script</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixrocker]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I figured it out. Whenever I rename a file on the desktop it loses its .desktop extension for some odd reason. If I re-add the .desktop extention in dolphin or in the konsole then everything is good again.</p>
<p>Honestly I think KDE Plasma unnecessarily complicates simple tasks but I am getting used to it.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 22:47:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5911-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911.rss">KDE Plasma renaming shortcuts turns them into matlab script</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>KDE Plasma renaming shortcuts turns them into matlab script</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixrocker]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I recently switched from Whonix 13 to Whonix 14 which uses KDE Plasma. So I’m still getting used to KDE Plasma and its quirks. I changed KDE Plasma’s desktop into the folder view so it behaves similar to KDE in Whonix 13.</p>
<p>However if I rename a shortcut on the desktop, the file properties change because when I click on properties it’s associated as a *.MATLAB script. And indeed when I try to open it, it opens up KWrite instead of executing what the shortcut is pointing to.</p>
<p>I tried googling for a fix since it’s not a whonix specific issue, but rather an issue with KDE Plasma, but I’m wondering if anyone else experienced this problem and knows of a solution?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 18:51:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5911-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/kde-plasma-renaming-shortcuts-turns-them-into-matlab-script/5911.rss">KDE Plasma renaming shortcuts turns them into matlab script</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
