<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tor state file/folder</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962</link>
    <description>I&#39;m confused after reading about the state file. I have a reason to regenerate it on the odd occasion so it would be good to know if I need to delete the whole state folder or just the state file. In the wiki &quot;Tor Entry Guards&quot; (I can&#39;t add this link) it mentions them interchangeably. I guess it would depend on what the use case is but I think in some cases even if you change your entry guards then you might still be identifiable because of the other things you have cached. Say I go offline for a week then the amount of data I have to fetch when I come back online is a predictable amount as opposed to if I delete the whole state folder and refetch everything. Does this sound right or is it just the state file to worry about?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:21:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Tor state file/folder</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Terket]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks for your help.</p>
<p>There is actually a section of the documentation that runs “sudo rm /var/lib/tor/state”, it’s the section “Fresh Tor Entry Guards by Regenerating the Tor State File”. The instructions that do the whole state folder are Non-Qubes-Whonix only. Qubes-Whonix options include the state file method or creating a clone and copying the state folder back.</p>
<p>I have found a method for Qubes-Whonix that is basically the same as Non-Qubes-Whonix and can replace the state file method.</p>
<p>Before arriving at remote</p>
<ol>
<li>sudo su</li>
<li>systemctl stop tor@default</li>
<li>mkdir /home/user/state-backup</li>
<li>mv /var/lib/tor/* /home/user/state-backup</li>
<li>ls -a /var/lib/tor (verify empty, manually move anything remaining to /home/user/state-backup)</li>
<li>Stop sys-whonix and next time you start it will have a new state folder</li>
</ol>
<p>Before returning home</p>
<ol>
<li>sudo su</li>
<li>systemctl stop tor@default</li>
<li>rm -r /var/lib/tor/*</li>
<li>mv /home/user/state-backup/* /var/lib/tor</li>
<li>ls -a /home/user/state-backup (verify empty, manually move anything remaining to /var/lib/tor)</li>
<li>systemctl restart tor@default</li>
</ol>
<p>Q1) Can you see anything wrong here?<br>
Q2) What is difference between systemctl start/stop tor@default and anon-connection-wizard connect/disable?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15962-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962.rss">Tor state file/folder</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tor state file/folder</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wiki instructions consistently use Tor state folder. Doesn’t delete/move Tor /var/lib/tor/state at any place. Probably wiki should say Tor state folder instead of Tor state file.</p>
<p>Indeed only deleting /var/lib/tor/state in theory might not be enough. Hence replacing of the whole Tor state folder should be safer.</p>
<aside class="onebox allowlistedgeneric" data-onebox-src="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Unspecific">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/a/a4/Whonix-home-favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">

      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Unspecific" target="_blank" rel="noopener" title="07:49PM - 25 July 2022">Whonix – 25 Jul 22</a>
  </header>

  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:250/500;"><img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/7/74/Booster132.png" class="thumbnail" width="250" height="500"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Unspecific" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Information Booster might be Available!</a></h3>

  <p>Utilizing other resources to help solve questions/issues unspecific to Whonix ™.</p>


  </article>

  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>

  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 15:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15962-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962.rss">Tor state file/folder</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tor state file/folder</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Terket]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m confused after reading about the state file. I have a reason to regenerate it on the odd occasion so it would be good to know if I need to delete the whole state folder or just the state file. In the wiki “Tor Entry Guards” (I can’t add this link) it mentions them interchangeably. I guess it would depend on what the use case is but I think in some cases even if you change your entry guards then you might still be identifiable because of the other things you have cached. Say I go offline for a week then the amount of data I have to fetch when I come back online is a predictable amount as opposed to if I delete the whole state folder and refetch everything. Does this sound right or is it just the state file to worry about?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 11:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15962-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tor-state-file-folder/15962.rss">Tor state file/folder</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
