<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware recommendations (Specs) 4 running many whonix VMs simultaneously</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/hardware-recommendations-specs-4-running-many-whonix-vms-simultaneously/1360</link>
    <description>Anyone running a bunch of whonix-VMs simultaneously and willing to share his opinion about recommended hardware specs?
I&#39;d like to be able to run around 10 whonix-workstations at the same time and would like to know what minimum hardware specs should I be looking into cpu (i.e. minimum cpu (i5 or i7, 4-cores or 6 cores or 8!?) minimum ram (8,12,16..or 32?!) and gpu (1 or 2? 1GB ram or 2?.. or even more?).
I think I read in the whonix documentation that hardware that works well for gaming should also work well for virtualization but thats a bit vague. 
I don&#39;t want to do any heavy stuff on the host nor in the VMs (no gaming, no heavy photo-editing, no heavy video-editing). Mainly I want to run a bunch of hidden services (i.e. for alternative socialnetworking like diaspora, friendica, twister. Of course one for each &quot;identity&quot; and one or more VM for the standard, datamining socialnetworks (facebook, twitter,google+). 1-2 VMs for webservers (hidden services)(i.e. blogging under various identities), A secure-drop HS, maybe another globaleaks-HS, Several HS for different &quot;cryptocurrency identities&quot; and so on. I guess you get the idea. Of course not all VMs would run always at the same time, but a bunch of them would and several would get fired up if needed and afterwards shut down.

I know hardware recommendations are never easy, so let&#39;s specify what the hardware should be able to handle comfortably:
- running around 10 whonix-workstations at the same time
- no gaming, no heavy photo-edditing, no heavy video-edditing
- no huge traffic for the hidden services

Thx y&#39;all</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 07:33:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/hardware-recommendations-specs-4-running-many-whonix-vms-simultaneously/1360.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Hardware recommendations (Specs) 4 running many whonix VMs simultaneously</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Lilly]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Anyone running a bunch of whonix-VMs simultaneously and willing to share his opinion about recommended hardware specs?<br>
I’d like to be able to run around 10 whonix-workstations at the same time and would like to know what minimum hardware specs should I be looking into cpu (i.e. minimum cpu (i5 or i7, 4-cores or 6 cores or 8!?) minimum ram (8,12,16…or 32?!) and gpu (1 or 2? 1GB ram or 2?.. or even more?).<br>
I think I read in the whonix documentation that hardware that works well for gaming should also work well for virtualization but thats a bit vague.<br>
I don’t want to do any heavy stuff on the host nor in the VMs (no gaming, no heavy photo-editing, no heavy video-editing). Mainly I want to run a bunch of hidden services (i.e. for alternative socialnetworking like diaspora, friendica, twister. Of course one for each “identity” and one or more VM for the standard, datamining socialnetworks (facebook, twitter,google+). 1-2 VMs for webservers (hidden services)(i.e. blogging under various identities), A secure-drop HS, maybe another globaleaks-HS, Several HS for different “cryptocurrency identities” and so on. I guess you get the idea. Of course not all VMs would run always at the same time, but a bunch of them would and several would get fired up if needed and afterwards shut down.</p>
<p>I know hardware recommendations are never easy, so let’s specify what the hardware should be able to handle comfortably:</p>
<ul>
<li>running around 10 whonix-workstations at the same time</li>
<li>no gaming, no heavy photo-edditing, no heavy video-edditing</li>
<li>no huge traffic for the hidden services</li>
</ul>
<p>Thx y’all</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/hardware-recommendations-specs-4-running-many-whonix-vms-simultaneously/1360/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/hardware-recommendations-specs-4-running-many-whonix-vms-simultaneously/1360/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 07:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1360-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/hardware-recommendations-specs-4-running-many-whonix-vms-simultaneously/1360.rss">Hardware recommendations (Specs) 4 running many whonix VMs simultaneously</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
