<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Had it all set up....then BIG GOOF!</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472</link>
    <description>Okay, I managed to get the default PGP client working and everything was all set up,  However, I feel I have made a tragic mistake.  Being new to whonix I followed the pw change for the gateway to a new pw (which I thought I remembered) then I noticed on the second run it auto logged me in I was unaware that it always auto logs you in so I was thinking that the gateway pw change didn&#39;t take so I changed it again and it allowed me to change it again.  Now when I try to adjust the firewall settings it actually asks me for the gateway pw and I have been trying to type in all possible combinations of the passwords I have chosen yet none of them seem to take.  Is there any kind of work around for this??  I mean I guess I could just use it as is and not have pw permissions but is there any kind of solution for this??  God I feel so foolish.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:32:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Had it all set up....then BIG GOOF!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Easy:<br>
Start fresh. Delete/re-get the image.</p>
<p>Harder:<br>
As per <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/About#Based_on_Debian">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/About#Based_on_Debian</a> these passwords can be reset by booting from a (virtual) boot cd and then accessing the system disk.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 09:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1472-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472.rss">Had it all set up....then BIG GOOF!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Had it all set up....then BIG GOOF!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ouch787]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Okay, I managed to get the default PGP client working and everything was all set up,  However, I feel I have made a tragic mistake.  Being new to whonix I followed the pw change for the gateway to a new pw (which I thought I remembered) then I noticed on the second run it auto logged me in I was unaware that it always auto logs you in so I was thinking that the gateway pw change didn’t take so I changed it again and it allowed me to change it again.  Now when I try to adjust the firewall settings it actually asks me for the gateway pw and I have been trying to type in all possible combinations of the passwords I have chosen yet none of them seem to take.  Is there any kind of work around for this??  I mean I guess I could just use it as is and not have pw permissions but is there any kind of solution for this??  God I feel so foolish.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 06:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1472-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/had-it-all-set-up-then-big-goof/1472.rss">Had it all set up....then BIG GOOF!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
