<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Whonixcheck issues, slowness</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonixcheck-issues-slowness/3120</link>
    <description>I had to reinstall Whonix. Now whonixcheck is really unstable and slow compared to the previous installation. I was so happy about whonix 13 and how much quicker and smoother it ran but now I&#39;m facing more issues with whonixcheck. Too often do I get Socks errors, errors on whonix news, on the update status. It&#39;s nothing, because when I run it a second time or debug it, it&#39;s totally fine. As I mentioned it is a lot slower. 
Also apt-get update often gives me an errod about hash-sum mismatch amongst others. After a few tries incl. --fix-missing it&#39;s fine. 
It&#39;s not anything ubearable but I&#39;d like to know how there can be such a difference given it&#39;s the same system with the same set up. 

thanks!</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 13:37:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonixcheck-issues-slowness/3120.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Whonixcheck issues, slowness</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[winibub]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I had to reinstall Whonix. Now whonixcheck is really unstable and slow compared to the previous installation. I was so happy about whonix 13 and how much quicker and smoother it ran but now I’m facing more issues with whonixcheck. Too often do I get Socks errors, errors on whonix news, on the update status. It’s nothing, because when I run it a second time or debug it, it’s totally fine. As I mentioned it is a lot slower.<br>
Also apt-get update often gives me an errod about hash-sum mismatch amongst others. After a few tries incl. --fix-missing it’s fine.<br>
It’s not anything ubearable but I’d like to know how there can be such a difference given it’s the same system with the same set up.</p>
<p>thanks!</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonixcheck-issues-slowness/3120/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonixcheck-issues-slowness/3120/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 13:37:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-3120-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonixcheck-issues-slowness/3120.rss">Whonixcheck issues, slowness</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
