<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>(Help) Surespot security and how to talk via mobile in a safe way?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603</link>
    <description>Hey guys, one of my friends suggest me to get surespot on my phone in order to chat with him in a safe way. However you may already noticed, I&#39;m paranoid. 

I don&#39;t trust my mobile device at all when it comes anonymity. 

If you do, what do you use via mobile to talk in a safe, private way, that doesn&#39;t leave traces on your mobile (like temp data or shit like that)?

Do you think surespot is safe? Btw this is their website: https://www.surespot.me/

I prefer 100 times talk behind Whonix with pidgin + otr of course...</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 23:18:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>(Help) Surespot security and how to talk via mobile in a safe way?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>i dont think u will find any phone that provide anonymity. not because of the apps but because of the phone operating system itself.</p>
<p>Android OS? made by google so u can imagine …(even if u gonna say its open source , there is no company claimed to give u anonymity. security maybe but not anonymity. for example:- blackphone?)</p>
<p>Sailfish OS ? used to be on jolla phones = not much different than google but its better for sure. anonymity ? i dont think so. read their policies.</p>
<p>IOS ? made by apple so u can imagine …(closed source = no way of anonymity)</p>
<p>Windows Phone? made by microsoft so u can imagine …(closed source = no way of anonymity)</p>
<p>QNX OS? made by BlackBerry…(closed source = no way of anonymity)</p>
<p>Tizen OS? made by tizen in association with samsung &amp;intel …(all the companies mentioned here have no relation with user privacy/anonymity. and the SDK (Software development kit) of the OS is closed source = no way of anonymity)</p>
<p>Ubuntu Touch OS? made by Canonical Ltd … (Canonical feed on your information , u can read articles about ubuntu and privacy. canonical = microsoft)</p>
<p>regarding the app itself , i heard about it but didnt read much about its company so i dunno regarding the app safety. but it has similar features like TOX chat. which i have read much about and i really advice users to use  it. (dont relay on it for high private conversation because the app still under heavy development).</p>
<p>also dont forget to use on ur phone = Orbot +Orwall (orbot firewall).</p>
<p>so u can be anonymous with ur apps but not with ur phone OS.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 23:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1603-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603.rss">(Help) Surespot security and how to talk via mobile in a safe way?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(Help) Surespot security and how to talk via mobile in a safe way?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[JohnWillie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys, one of my friends suggest me to get surespot on my phone in order to chat with him in a safe way. However you may already noticed, I’m paranoid.</p>
<p>I don’t trust my mobile device at all when it comes anonymity.</p>
<p>If you do, what do you use via mobile to talk in a safe, private way, that doesn’t leave traces on your mobile (like temp data or shit like that)?</p>
<p>Do you think surespot is safe? Btw this is their website: <a href="https://www.surespot.me/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.surespot.me/</a></p>
<p>I prefer 100 times talk behind Whonix with pidgin + otr of course…</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 15:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1603-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/help-surespot-security-and-how-to-talk-via-mobile-in-a-safe-way/1603.rss">(Help) Surespot security and how to talk via mobile in a safe way?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
