<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Acknowledging Authorship</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760</link>
    <description>I&#39;m torn over the issue of whether to include my real identity in the sort of software that we discuss here, such as a Phantom client.

I&#39;m a very private person, but the future of the software product is very important.

I feel that a software product&#39;s future is best assured by having real people attached to it. Consider what happened to Truecrypt, developed by a secret team: who knows if they were gotten at, as an explanation of the somewhat bizarre end to the product&#39;s career.

Tor is on firmer ground, but still there is the legitimate concern over how it arose in the first place, as a US government project.

Bitcoin? Well, the authorship of the original paper was pseudonymous; that is, the protocol and a demonstration program. Like Tor, it is used widely but one wonders if someday it turns out to be a trap because its author knew something that he never let on about.

The whole question gives me a headache, when I&#39;d rather be thinking about technical matters.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 22:27:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledging Authorship</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Somehow this sounds like what I could have written a while ago.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 22:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-760-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760.rss">Acknowledging Authorship</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Acknowledging Authorship</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dennis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m torn over the issue of whether to include my real identity in the sort of software that we discuss here, such as a Phantom client.</p>
<p>I’m a very private person, but the future of the software product is very important.</p>
<p>I feel that a software product’s future is best assured by having real people attached to it. Consider what happened to Truecrypt, developed by a secret team: who knows if they were gotten at, as an explanation of the somewhat bizarre end to the product’s career.</p>
<p>Tor is on firmer ground, but still there is the legitimate concern over how it arose in the first place, as a US government project.</p>
<p>Bitcoin? Well, the authorship of the original paper was pseudonymous; that is, the protocol and a demonstration program. Like Tor, it is used widely but one wonders if someday it turns out to be a trap because its author knew something that he never let on about.</p>
<p>The whole question gives me a headache, when I’d rather be thinking about technical matters.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2014 18:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-760-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/acknowledging-authorship/760.rss">Acknowledging Authorship</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
