<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>New policies on Whonix website?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909</link>
    <description>Required to accept cookies policies, privacy policies and other scary stuff. Why the change?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 04:30:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Website</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>New policies on Whonix website?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempr]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#ExportWarranties" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl-faq.html#ExportWarranties</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Some distributors of GPLed software require me in their umbrella EULAs or as part of their downloading process to “represent and warrant” that I am located in the US or that I intend to distribute the software in compliance with relevant export control laws. Why are they doing this and is it a violation of those distributors’ obligations under GPL?</p>
<p>This is not a violation of the GPL. <strong>Those distributors</strong> (almost all of whom are commercial businesses selling free software distributions and related services) <strong>are trying to reduce their own legal risks</strong>, not to control your behavior. Export control law in the United States <em>might</em> make them liable if they knowingly export software into certain countries, or if they give software to parties they know will make such exports. By asking for these statements from their customers and others to whom they distribute software, <strong>they protect themselves in the event they are later asked by regulatory authorities</strong> what they knew about where software they distributed was going to wind up. <strong>They are not restricting what you can do with the software</strong>, only <strong>preventing themselves from being blamed with respect to anything you do</strong>. Because <strong>they are not placing additional restrictions on the software</strong>, they do not violate section 10 of GPLv3 or section 6 of GPLv2.</p>
<p>The FSF opposes the application of US export control laws to free software. Not only are such laws incompatible with the general objective of software freedom, they achieve no reasonable governmental purpose, because free software is currently and should always be available from parties in almost every country, including countries that have no export control laws and which do not participate in US-led trade embargoes. Therefore, no country’s government is actually deprived of free software by US export control laws, while no country’s citizens <em>should</em> be deprived of free software, regardless of their governments’ policies, as far as we are concerned. Copies of all GPL-licensed software published by the FSF can be obtained from us without making any representation about where you live or what you intend to do. At the same time, the FSF understands the desire of commercial distributors located in the US to <strong>comply with US laws</strong>. They have a right to choose to whom they distribute particular copies of free software; exercise of that right does not violate the GPL unless they add contractual restrictions beyond those permitted by the GPL.</p>
</blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 08:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-6909-4</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909.rss">New policies on Whonix website?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>New policies on Whonix website?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Malor]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This it’s strange</p>
<pre><code>Restricted Territories
    Cuba
    Iran
    North Korea
    Sudan
    Syria
    or any other country to which the United States, the United Kingdom or the European Union embargoes goods or imposes similar sanctions
</code></pre>
<p>Torproject helps people from Iran but here is restricted -<br>
</p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/tor-quote-iran-stories.png" title="tor-quote-iran-stories.png" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="https://blog.torproject.org/sites/default/files/inline-images/tor-quote-iran-stories.png" alt="" width="690" height="345"></a></div><br>
<a href="https://blog.torproject.org/how-has-tor-helped-you-send-us-your-story" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://blog.torproject.org/how-has-tor-helped-you-send-us-your-story</a><p></p>
<p>Isn’t Whonix sold to some United States, the United Kingdom or the European Union country ?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 08:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-6909-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909.rss">New policies on Whonix website?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>New policies on Whonix website?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Compliance with new laws, improved legal protections for the Whonix project.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 10:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-6909-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909.rss">New policies on Whonix website?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>New policies on Whonix website?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[yirgit]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Required to accept cookies policies, privacy policies and other scary stuff. Why the change?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-6909-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/new-policies-on-whonix-website/6909.rss">New policies on Whonix website?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
