<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>[Release] Whonix-Installer and UI</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/release-whonix-installer-and-ui/3389</link>
    <description>Disclaimer: Please remember that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Windows_Hosts&quot;&gt;Windows is &lt;strong&gt;NOT &lt;/strong&gt;a secure host operating system for a variety of reasons&lt;/a&gt;. This Installer was mainly created to make it easy for people to experience Whonix first hand without the requirement of installing an entirely new OS. Under no circumstances, use Windows for sensitive work.

&amp;nbsp;

After almost a year of active development, we are releasing the Whonix-Installer which will provide a simple and familiar way for Windows users to gain access to Whonix and its massive capabilities as well as toolset.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/installer.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-2218&quot; src=&#39;/uploads/default/original/1X/76e8b95898ee5f95d585b4f09e6960ee02f145d2.png&#39; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;206&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

Currently, the Whonix-Installer for Windows is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://sourceforge.net/projects/nsisbi/&quot;&gt;nsisbi&lt;/a&gt;, a fork of the often used &quot;Nullsoft Scriptable Install System&quot;, which was required to circumvent the general size limit of 2Gb usually enforced by &quot;NSIS&quot;. Even with that though, a bit of additional modification was required to include all the files required for Whonix into one simple to use &quot;.exe file&quot;. That&#39;s why for the foreseeable future, a disk-space of 8Gb is required during installation, as the Gateway and Workstation required additional compression, since even &quot;nsisbi&quot; has a single file size limit of 4Gb. Thus, during installation, both Gateway and Workstation take temporarily double the disk space, during the decompression process.

Adding to this however, the Whonix-Installer can be used regardless of whether you&#39;ve installed VirtualBox previously or not. Any older virtual machines should be unmodified by using the Whonix-Installer.

Furthermore, a small, simple user interface, named &quot;Whonix-UI&quot; or alternatively &quot;Whonix for Windows&quot;/&quot;Whonix.exe&quot; has been created to make starting and terminating of both the Gateway and Workstation as simple as possible. It is still very much in the early stages of its development, which is part of the reason for its rather basic appearance though functionally works as intended. By pressing the &quot;Start Whonix Button&quot;, both the Gateway and Workstation are launched and by pressing the &quot;Stop Whonix Button&quot; they are terminated. While Whonix is being used, the window prevents itself from being closed, as to prevent issues.

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/UI.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-2217&quot; src=&#39;/uploads/default/original/1X/2104847cde69f4e1b9acd2a18480ba752dc72df3.png&#39; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;297&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

If you&#39;d like to try the UI with your existing installation of Whonix, you may simply drag-and-drop it into the folder in which you&#39;ve installed VirtualBox.
&lt;h3&gt;Download Links:&lt;/h3&gt;
The Whonix-Installer may be downloaded from here:

https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Windows_Quick_Start

The Whonix-UI can be found separately here:
 https://github.com/Whonix/Whonix-Windows-UI</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 11:53:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>News</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/release-whonix-installer-and-ui/3389.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>[Release] Whonix-Installer and UI</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Disclaimer: Please remember that <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Windows_Hosts" rel="nofollow noopener">Windows is <strong>NOT </strong>a secure host operating system for a variety of reasons</a>. This Installer was mainly created to make it easy for people to experience Whonix first hand without the requirement of installing an entirely new OS. Under no circumstances, use Windows for sensitive work.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After almost a year of active development, we are releasing the Whonix-Installer which will provide a simple and familiar way for Windows users to gain access to Whonix and its massive capabilities as well as toolset.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whonix.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/installer.png" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//forums.whonix.org/uploads/default/original/1X/76e8b95898ee5f95d585b4f09e6960ee02f145d2.png" alt="" width="300" height="206"></a></p>
<p>Currently, the Whonix-Installer for Windows is based on <a href="https://sourceforge.net/projects/nsisbi/" rel="nofollow noopener">nsisbi</a>, a fork of the often used “Nullsoft Scriptable Install System”, which was required to circumvent the general size limit of 2Gb usually enforced by “NSIS”. Even with that though, a bit of additional modification was required to include all the files required for Whonix into one simple to use “.exe file”. That’s why for the foreseeable future, a disk-space of 8Gb is required during installation, as the Gateway and Workstation required additional compression, since even “nsisbi” has a single file size limit of 4Gb. Thus, during installation, both Gateway and Workstation take temporarily double the disk space, during the decompression process.</p>
<p>Adding to this however, the Whonix-Installer can be used regardless of whether you’ve installed VirtualBox previously or not. Any older virtual machines should be unmodified by using the Whonix-Installer.</p>
<p>Furthermore, a small, simple user interface, named “Whonix-UI” or alternatively “Whonix for Windows”/“Whonix.exe” has been created to make starting and terminating of both the Gateway and Workstation as simple as possible. It is still very much in the early stages of its development, which is part of the reason for its rather basic appearance though functionally works as intended. By pressing the “Start Whonix Button”, both the Gateway and Workstation are launched and by pressing the “Stop Whonix Button” they are terminated. While Whonix is being used, the window prevents itself from being closed, as to prevent issues.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whonix.org/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/UI.png" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//forums.whonix.org/uploads/default/original/1X/2104847cde69f4e1b9acd2a18480ba752dc72df3.png" alt="" width="297" height="300"></a></p>
<p>If you’d like to try the UI with your existing installation of Whonix, you may simply drag-and-drop it into the folder in which you’ve installed VirtualBox.</p>
<h3>Download Links:</h3>
The Whonix-Installer may be downloaded from here:
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Windows_Quick_Start" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Whonix</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/e/ee/Windows_logo_-_2012.svg.png" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="200" height="200">

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Windows_Quick_Start" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Windows Quick Start</a></h3>

<p>Whonix ™ Windows Installer - FREE</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>The Whonix-UI can be found separately here:<br>
<a href="https://github.com/Whonix/Whonix-Windows-UI" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/Whonix/Whonix-Windows-UI</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/release-whonix-installer-and-ui/3389/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/release-whonix-installer-and-ui/3389/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 22:53:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-3389-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/release-whonix-installer-and-ui/3389.rss">[Release] Whonix-Installer and UI</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
