<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Firefox vs. Tor Browser fonts</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/firefox-vs-tor-browser-fonts/9782</link>
    <description>Workstation: set to connect using the Tor before VPN method.
Browser: firefox-esr.
Problem: a certain language doesn&#39;t get displayed properly on Firefox (instead of the letters, I see squares with numbers).

I looked at https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Language - I think the KDE instructions are obsolete. 

Searching elsewhere, I run `sudo apt-cache search firefox-esr-l10n`, found the package I need and installed it. It didn&#39;t change a thing.
I also added the language as an alternative in the firefox preferences, no change. 
I&#39;ve used the `dpkg-reconfigure locales` to add it to the system, didn&#39;t help.
I added it as an input language, as explained in https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Keyboard_Layout (Probably unrelated). I could then switch to this language and type, but didn&#39;t help with my issue.

All that didn&#39;t get firefox to display the fonts correctly.

Then I launched Tor-Browser, and I found out it&#39;s ok there! it displays everything perfectly. Just not on firefox.

I then restored the workstation to its previous state, before all of the modifications above. None of them were necessary for Tor-Browser to do the trick. No modifications required. Works out of the box.

Looking for differences, I noticed Tor-Browser uses the Arimo font as default while firefox uses Dejavu serif.

Any idea how to make that work on firefox?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 05:17:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/firefox-vs-tor-browser-fonts/9782.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Firefox vs. Tor Browser fonts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pucor]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Workstation: set to connect using the Tor before VPN method.<br>
Browser: firefox-esr.<br>
Problem: a certain language doesn’t get displayed properly on Firefox (instead of the letters, I see squares with numbers).</p>
<p>I looked at <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Language" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Language</a> - I think the KDE instructions are obsolete.</p>
<p>Searching elsewhere, I run <code>sudo apt-cache search firefox-esr-l10n</code>, found the package I need and installed it. It didn’t change a thing.<br>
I also added the language as an alternative in the firefox preferences, no change.<br>
I’ve used the <code>dpkg-reconfigure locales</code> to add it to the system, didn’t help.<br>
I added it as an input language, as explained in <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Keyboard_Layout" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Keyboard_Layout</a> (Probably unrelated). I could then switch to this language and type, but didn’t help with my issue.</p>
<p>All that didn’t get firefox to display the fonts correctly.</p>
<p>Then I launched Tor-Browser, and I found out it’s ok there! it displays everything perfectly. Just not on firefox.</p>
<p>I then restored the workstation to its previous state, before all of the modifications above. None of them were necessary for Tor-Browser to do the trick. No modifications required. Works out of the box.</p>
<p>Looking for differences, I noticed Tor-Browser uses the Arimo font as default while firefox uses Dejavu serif.</p>
<p>Any idea how to make that work on firefox?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/firefox-vs-tor-browser-fonts/9782/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/firefox-vs-tor-browser-fonts/9782/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 05:17:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-9782-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/firefox-vs-tor-browser-fonts/9782.rss">Firefox vs. Tor Browser fonts</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
