<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Whonix failproof?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611</link>
    <description>First of all i want to say thanks to Patrick and all contributors of whonix for this great project! Revolution!
I have been using whonix for a while, but i&#39;m not computer guy so i want to ask some questions to help calm my mind.

It&#39;s possible that because of some script fails in gateway when updating,installing or whatever, gateway begins to route all traffic without tor ? It&#39;s possible that this thing can happen, or that&#39;s impossible by gateway design ?

After the last torbrowser update, torbrowsers file structure was changed. So i start thinking, it&#39;s possible if in the future tor-browser gets so changed it configuration that it not works correctly with whonix ? Let&#39;s say new version of torbrowser comes out and it not ready for whonix config and we have tor over tor case ? In other words can changes in future, make fail rinetd listener ?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 22:38:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Whonix failproof?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="611">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/i/c77e96/40.png" class="avatar"> ilovefruits:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s possible that because of some script fails in gateway when updating,installing or whatever, gateway begins to route all traffic without tor ? It’s possible that this thing can happen, or that’s impossible by gateway design ?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>While one can be never 100% certain about anything, I am very certain that routing traffic over clearnet won’t ever happen.</p>
<p>[Technically: Because whether Whonix-Gateway is offline, Whonix-Gateway firewall not load at all, Tor not running on Whonix-Gateway - there will just be no service then. You could even run some random VM that uses internal network “Whonix” and runs on Whonix-Gateway’s IP. Only if that random VM did something that is not the default in Linux, activate IP forwarding, then clearnet traffic would be possible.]</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="1" data-topic="611">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/i/c77e96/40.png" class="avatar"> ilovefruits:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>After the last torbrowser update, torbrowsers file structure was changed. So i start thinking, it’s possible if in the future tor-browser gets so changed it configuration that it not works correctly with whonix ? Let’s say new version of torbrowser comes out and it not ready for whonix config and we have tor over tor case ? In other words can changes in future, make fail rinetd listener ?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Two upgraded could interfere here:</p>
<ul>
<li>As long we’re using Debian stable, it is unlikely that rinetd received an upgrade that prevent the listener from being created.</li>
<li>Suppose rinetd does not work: When Tor Browser gets an upgrade an choses to ignore the TOR_SKIP_LAUNCH then Tor over Tor could happen.</li>
<li>Suppose rinetd works: When Tor Browser gets an upgrade an choses to ignore the TOR_SKIP_LAUNCH environment variable + changed default listener ports from 9050/9051//9150/9151 to something else, then Tor over Tor could happen.</li>
</ul>
<p>To make it more unlikely, always look how a copy of latest TBB alpha works inside Whonix-Workstation. If a single user did that, and reported, there would have been no surprise as we had.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 22:38:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-611-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611.rss">Whonix failproof?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix failproof?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[ilovefruits]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>First of all i want to say thanks to Patrick and all contributors of whonix for this great project! Revolution!<br>
I have been using whonix for a while, but i’m not computer guy so i want to ask some questions to help calm my mind.</p>
<p>It’s possible that because of some script fails in gateway when updating,installing or whatever, gateway begins to route all traffic without tor ? It’s possible that this thing can happen, or that’s impossible by gateway design ?</p>
<p>After the last torbrowser update, torbrowsers file structure was changed. So i start thinking, it’s possible if in the future tor-browser gets so changed it configuration that it not works correctly with whonix ? Let’s say new version of torbrowser comes out and it not ready for whonix config and we have tor over tor case ? In other words can changes in future, make fail rinetd listener ?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 17:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-611-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-failproof/611.rss">Whonix failproof?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
