<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Some Background on the Tor Foundation</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801</link>
    <description>I use the Tor network every day and, indeed, I&#39;m using it right now. However, I also like to get the biggest picture possible on the world, so when I encountered this podcast I listened to it with interest. It takes a skeptical stance towards Tor on the basis of its sources of funding and the strange associations of some of its people as well as the people connected to it.

https://porkinspolicyreview.wordpress.com/2014/08/01/porkins-policy-radio-episode-26-peeling-the-onion-behind-tor-eff-and-john-perry-barlow/

As a couple of examples of data that particularly give me pause (I&#39;m not saying these are objectively most significant, just that they strike me):

1. The Tor Foundation currently gets 90% of its funding from the U.S. Government.

2. Jacob Applebaum often promotes the line that Tor helps (peaceful, freedom-loving) &quot;dissidents&quot; in Syria who are in danger from the &quot;genocide&quot; being waged by the Syrian government.

3. The Tor employees are paid very generous salaries.


1. and 3. mean that there is an incentive to avoid stating the bald truth regarding the U.S. government: that it is the biggest threat to peace and freedom in the world at present. A view such as mine, that the USG needs to be completely dismantled, is one that simply could never be spoken, nor even thought, by a Tor foundation employee. That money is blood money, like all taxes, taken from productive people at gunpoint.

2. He&#39;s repeating the NATO narrative regarding Syria, but the situation in Syria is not quite as simple as that, with NATO-backed militias being trained in Turkey and being brought over from Libya. Very strange, coming from an apparently intelligent man.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 18:31:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Some Background on the Tor Foundation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The Tor Foundation gets 90% of its funding from the U.S. Government because the project can’t survive from user donations (as you demonstrated).  Applebaum talks about this in the CCC video. They would love to not take government money but there is are no alternative (calling bitcoin millionaires).</p>
<p>Tor people have always been open about funding and rehashing the same shit over and over and over again gets tiresome.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/4</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 18:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-801-4</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801.rss">Some Background on the Tor Foundation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Some Background on the Tor Foundation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dennis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>None. But your comment is a non-sequitur, since the answer to your question has nothing to do with anything.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 17:03:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-801-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801.rss">Some Background on the Tor Foundation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Some Background on the Tor Foundation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>How much money have you contributed to the Tor Foundation since you started using Tor?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 14:41:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-801-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801.rss">Some Background on the Tor Foundation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Some Background on the Tor Foundation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Dennis]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I use the Tor network every day and, indeed, I’m using it right now. However, I also like to get the biggest picture possible on the world, so when I encountered this podcast I listened to it with interest. It takes a skeptical stance towards Tor on the basis of its sources of funding and the strange associations of some of its people as well as the people connected to it.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://s1.wp.com/i/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://porkinspolicyreview.com/2014/08/01/porkins-policy-radio-episode-26-peeling-the-onion-behind-tor-eff-and-john-perry-barlow/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" title="02:28AM - 02 August 2014">Porkins Policy Review – 2 Aug 14</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:480/360;"><img src="https://img.youtube.com/vi/Z_7GqurT7KQ/0.jpg" class="thumbnail" width="480" height="360"></div>

<h3><a href="https://porkinspolicyreview.com/2014/08/01/porkins-policy-radio-episode-26-peeling-the-onion-behind-tor-eff-and-john-perry-barlow/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Porkins Policy Radio episode 26 Peeling the onion behind Tor, EFF, and John...</a></h3>

<p>On this week’s episode we peel back some of the layers behind the TOR Project, the Electronic Frontier Foundation, and a man at the center of both, John Perry Barlow.&nbsp; We take a look at Tor&amp;#…</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>As a couple of examples of data that particularly give me pause (I’m not saying these are objectively most significant, just that they strike me):</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The Tor Foundation currently gets 90% of its funding from the U.S. Government.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jacob Applebaum often promotes the line that Tor helps (peaceful, freedom-loving) “dissidents” in Syria who are in danger from the “genocide” being waged by the Syrian government.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>The Tor employees are paid very generous salaries.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>and 3. mean that there is an incentive to avoid stating the bald truth regarding the U.S. government: that it is the biggest threat to peace and freedom in the world at present. A view such as mine, that the USG needs to be completely dismantled, is one that simply could never be spoken, nor even thought, by a Tor foundation employee. That money is blood money, like all taxes, taken from productive people at gunpoint.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>He’s repeating the NATO narrative regarding Syria, but the situation in Syria is not quite as simple as that, with NATO-backed militias being trained in Turkey and being brought over from Libya. Very strange, coming from an apparently intelligent man.</p>
</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2015 13:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-801-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/some-background-on-the-tor-foundation/801.rss">Some Background on the Tor Foundation</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
