<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Do i leak my ip?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134</link>
    <description>hye, i was connected to my hosting server from whonixworkstation. Accidentally i press &#39;x&#39; on Arm in gateway, it restart tor internal state. Does i just leak my ip? Because at that time when i press x on gateway i was connected to my server. I thinking if i stop tor connection in gateway than my ip was leaked, because i was still connected to server while the tor was off for few seconds. I&#39;m right ? I hope someone will understand my English and what i&#39;m asking =) ty</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 14:22:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Do i leak my ip?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Probably not. Turning off Tor in Whonix-Gateway does not result in Whonix-Workstation being able to establish non-torified connections.</p>
<p>‘Connection’ is a loose term. TCP is specifically designed to overcome short periods of even physical disconnect. Connections are considered ‘open’ for a while even after a physical disconnect until ‘timeout’ is reached. Any client applications, browsers, ssh, etc. as well as server applications don’t instantly ‘close’ the connection if some package cannot be transmitted. They’re re-transmitted until ‘timeout’ is reached. Maybe read more about TCP. Or <a href="https://mosh.mit.edu">https://mosh.mit.edu</a> is interesting, works similarily. It takes the “keep connection open” to the “extreme”. Even during longer connection breakup it will re-establish and not log you out.</p>
<p>[hr]</p>
<p>Something to avoid anyhow. (An external observer seeing your Tor connection down as well as your server connection down.) (Related to <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Warning#Confirmation_attacks.)">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Warning#Confirmation_attacks.)</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 14:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1134-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134.rss">Do i leak my ip?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Do i leak my ip?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[sunflower]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>hye, i was connected to my hosting server from whonixworkstation. Accidentally i press ‘x’ on Arm in gateway, it restart tor internal state. Does i just leak my ip? Because at that time when i press x on gateway i was connected to my server. I thinking if i stop tor connection in gateway than my ip was leaked, because i was still connected to server while the tor was off for few seconds. I’m right ? I hope someone will understand my English and what i’m asking =) ty</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1134-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/do-i-leak-my-ip/1134.rss">Do i leak my ip?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
