<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Keyboard not working inside kvm</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494</link>
    <description>I use virtualbox with Whonix on my host pc once that&#39;s running I SSH into my dedicated server from there I&#39;ve installed KVM virtual machine with Whonix which I access via a vncserver, the problem comes here.

Once I&#39;m connected to my dedicated server via VNC I load KVM WHonix and it won&#39;t pick up my keyboard strokes my mouse works fine but my keyboard won&#39;t work at all, I know I could just as easily use another virutalbox as I tested that and it works but the point is to host a hidden service from the dedicated server and I think KVM would be more reliable for that.

I also tested KVM on my host machine after the issue arose and the keyboard works so I don&#39;t think it&#39;s whonix issue, maybe it&#39;s a vnc issue but I was hoping someone on here has experienced this and found a work around. Right now I&#39;m using a virtual keyboard for it and it&#39;s so slow.

Just in case I can&#39;t find a solution, how stable would virtualbox hosting a fairly popular hidden service be?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 22:59:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Keyboard not working inside kvm</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[entr0py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Unless someone has experienced this before, the next step would be to isolate the cause by seeing if you experience the same issues with plain Debian images (non-Whonix). If so, you can get help from the VNC people.</p>
<p>Also, there are other remote desktop protocols you can try, such as NX or SSH (X forwarding).</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 22:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-2494-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494.rss">Keyboard not working inside kvm</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Keyboard not working inside kvm</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TheLegend2016]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I use virtualbox with Whonix on my host pc once that’s running I SSH into my dedicated server from there I’ve installed KVM virtual machine with Whonix which I access via a vncserver, the problem comes here.</p>
<p>Once I’m connected to my dedicated server via VNC I load KVM WHonix and it won’t pick up my keyboard strokes my mouse works fine but my keyboard won’t work at all, I know I could just as easily use another virutalbox as I tested that and it works but the point is to host a hidden service from the dedicated server and I think KVM would be more reliable for that.</p>
<p>I also tested KVM on my host machine after the issue arose and the keyboard works so I don’t think it’s whonix issue, maybe it’s a vnc issue but I was hoping someone on here has experienced this and found a work around. Right now I’m using a virtual keyboard for it and it’s so slow.</p>
<p>Just in case I can’t find a solution, how stable would virtualbox hosting a fairly popular hidden service be?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 16:42:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-2494-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/keyboard-not-working-inside-kvm/2494.rss">Keyboard not working inside kvm</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
