<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Intimate Tracking with Session Replay Scripts</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/intimate-tracking-with-session-replay-scripts/4553</link>
    <description>The data freaks never rest:

  https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2017/11/websites_use_se.html

&gt; You may know that most websites have third-party analytics scripts that record which pages you visit and the searches you make. But lately, more and more sites use &quot;session replay&quot; scripts. These scripts record your keystrokes, mouse movements, and scrolling behavior, along with the entire contents of the pages you visit, and send them to third-party servers. Unlike typical analytics services that provide aggregate statistics, these scripts are intended for the recording and playback of individual browsing sessions, as if someone is looking over your shoulder.

&gt; The stated purpose of this data collection includes gathering insights into how users interact with websites and discovering broken or confusing pages. However the extent of data collected by these services far exceeds user expectations; text typed into forms is collected before the user submits the form, and precise mouse movements are saved, all without any visual indication to the user. This data can&#39;t reasonably be expected to be kept anonymous. In fact, some companies allow publishers to explicitly link recordings to a user&#39;s real identity.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 21:34:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/intimate-tracking-with-session-replay-scripts/4553.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Intimate Tracking with Session Replay Scripts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[torjunkie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The data freaks never rest:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2017/11/websites_use_se.html">https://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2017/11/websites_use_se.html</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>You may know that most websites have third-party analytics scripts that record which pages you visit and the searches you make. But lately, more and more sites use “session replay” scripts. These scripts record your keystrokes, mouse movements, and scrolling behavior, along with the entire contents of the pages you visit, and send them to third-party servers. Unlike typical analytics services that provide aggregate statistics, these scripts are intended for the recording and playback of individual browsing sessions, as if someone is looking over your shoulder.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The stated purpose of this data collection includes gathering insights into how users interact with websites and discovering broken or confusing pages. However the extent of data collected by these services far exceeds user expectations; text typed into forms is collected before the user submits the form, and precise mouse movements are saved, all without any visual indication to the user. This data can’t reasonably be expected to be kept anonymous. In fact, some companies allow publishers to explicitly link recordings to a user’s real identity.</p>
</blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/intimate-tracking-with-session-replay-scripts/4553/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/intimate-tracking-with-session-replay-scripts/4553/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 21:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-4553-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/intimate-tracking-with-session-replay-scripts/4553.rss">Intimate Tracking with Session Replay Scripts</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
