<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Why is ICQ considered unsafe through tor?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096</link>
    <description>Hi, I have a question. 
I have heard from some that using ICQ is &quot;unsafe&quot;. And by default on whonix, pidgin does not list the icq protocol as it&#39;s consider unsafe. Why is it unsafe?

I don&#39;t use regular ICQ of course; I use pidgin to connect on whonix through tor. Why is this considered unsafe? I am not worried so much as in a privacy sense, but as anonymity. People/ governments looking in on my conversations is not a concern of mine, only that they do not know the origin/ my ip address.

To me it doesn&#39;t seem too unsafe for my uses. Anything I may be missing about it?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 08:05:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Why is ICQ considered unsafe through tor?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Good question.</p>
<p>Not just about ICQ, but any non-free protocol…</p>
<ul>
<li>Sometimes no or bad account security. Settings such as ‘default: don’t use encryption’, ‘default: use encryption if available’ or not supporting encryption at all.</li>
<li>Encourages use of original, proprietary client by user and/or recipient.</li>
<li>Intention to privacy violation with announcement by terms of agreement.</li>
<li>Centralized, all trust [not to try to exploit] in one server that is governed by people who are blunt about not being trustworthy.</li>
<li>Short maximum message lengths that resulted in OTR developers choosing weaker key lengths than we could otherwise computationally use for better security. These protocols must die.</li>
<li>Protocol needed to be reverse engineered.</li>
<li>Includes fancy (protocol) features or fancy (protocol or messenger) features may be added.</li>
<li>These protocols are of no use. Why bother with them.</li>
<li>Too many protocols to research, audit, support. Better to have anonymity/privacy/security focused distributions concentrate on open, useful alternatives.</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096/2</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 08:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1096-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096.rss">Why is ICQ considered unsafe through tor?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Why is ICQ considered unsafe through tor?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixx]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi, I have a question.<br>
I have heard from some that using ICQ is “unsafe”. And by default on whonix, pidgin does not list the icq protocol as it’s consider unsafe. Why is it unsafe?</p>
<p>I don’t use regular ICQ of course; I use pidgin to connect on whonix through tor. Why is this considered unsafe? I am not worried so much as in a privacy sense, but as anonymity. People/ governments looking in on my conversations is not a concern of mine, only that they do not know the origin/ my ip address.</p>
<p>To me it doesn’t seem too unsafe for my uses. Anything I may be missing about it?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 02:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1096-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/why-is-icq-considered-unsafe-through-tor/1096.rss">Why is ICQ considered unsafe through tor?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
