<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Workstation keeps causing my pc to crash</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814</link>
    <description>Hello, I&#39;m not sure if this is related to a hardware issue or a Whonix issue.

I previously used many versions of whonix and never had an issue. The pc I&#39;m running it on is only 4GB ram, but as I mentioned, all previous versions I had used worked fine.

I recently installed Ubuntu 19.04 and installed virtualbox. I initially used whonix 14 and it worked fine. But after upgrading to 14, the VM&#39;s run fine on the initial setup, but after the updates are performed, when I restart the workstation at a different time, my whole PC freezes. Does anyone know what can cause this? Previous versions worked fine. Is there log files stored anywhere? Thanks.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 15:50:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Workstation keeps causing my pc to crash</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Haven’t looked into Ubuntu for years, because…</p>
<p>(<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Host_Operating_System_Selection#Recommended_GNU.2FLinux_Distribution" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Host_Operating_System_Selection#Recommended_GNU.2FLinux_Distribution</a>)</p>
<p>I guess nowadays Ubuntu is using systemd as init system and thereby journalctl for logs.</p>
<p>So this is more a question for your host operating system (Ubuntu) and/or VirtualBox. Nothing that Whonix does should be capable of crashing the host computer. Otherwise these by definition are Ubuntu and/or VirtualBox bugs.</p>
<p>Our instructions for viewing logs work on Debian (and Whonix, since it is a derivative of Debian). Dunno if they would work on Ubuntu too. Rather than doing them in a VM (which you could try too), you could try them on the host. See:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#System_Logs" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#System_Logs</a></p>
<p>Maybe you are “lucky” and could watch systemd journal log when this issue is happening?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Watch_Systemd_Journal_Log_of_Current_Boot" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Watch_Systemd_Journal_Log_of_Current_Boot</a></p>
<p>Otherwise if above does not help, you could Enable Persistent Systemd Journal Log:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Enable_Persistent_Systemd_Journal_Log" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Enable_Persistent_Systemd_Journal_Log</a></p>
<p>(Dunno if Ubuntu by default uses persistent systemd journal log or not.)</p>
<p>And then after freeze and after reboot, Check Systemd Journal Log of Previous Boot:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Check_Systemd_Journal_Log_of_Previous_Boot" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Check_Systemd_Journal_Log_of_Previous_Boot</a></p>
<p>Please also read <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Free_Support_Principle" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Free_Support_Principle</a>.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 15:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-7814-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814.rss">Workstation keeps causing my pc to crash</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Workstation keeps causing my pc to crash</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[David888]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, I’m not sure if this is related to a hardware issue or a Whonix issue.</p>
<p>I previously used many versions of whonix and never had an issue. The pc I’m running it on is only 4GB ram, but as I mentioned, all previous versions I had used worked fine.</p>
<p>I recently installed Ubuntu 19.04 and installed virtualbox. I initially used whonix 14 and it worked fine. But after upgrading to 14, the VM’s run fine on the initial setup, but after the updates are performed, when I restart the workstation at a different time, my whole PC freezes. Does anyone know what can cause this? Previous versions worked fine. Is there log files stored anywhere? Thanks.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 18:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-7814-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/workstation-keeps-causing-my-pc-to-crash/7814.rss">Workstation keeps causing my pc to crash</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
