<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Guard entry node</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774</link>
    <description>Lets assume someone runs a tor hidden service and they are paranoid about guard entry nodes, if one was to run his/her own guard entry node am I correct in thinking this would make the hidden service more secure overall and it would rule out one possible attack method?

Now I&#39;ve never ran any kind of node before, I&#39;m aware I&#39;m going to sound like a newbie because I am and it&#39;s all a learning process to me but am I also correct in thinking I would need to set up a relay and let it run for 8 days before it can become a guard?

If I found a hosting provider which allows relays and I ran only the relay on a VPS what specs would be ideal for this ?

It would be ran on a seprate server to my hidden service as well as seperate provider paid via tumbled BTC.

Lastly as it would be just a relay and a guard node, would this be ok to run a home pc or is the VPS method best as I wouldn&#39;t want to attract and kind of attention, I know exit nodes can cause issues sometimes but I&#39;m unsure about relays/guard nodes.

Thank you.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 16:15:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Guard entry node</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Better to ask this on tor-talk, since unrelated to Whonix. (As per <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Support.)">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Support.)</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 16:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-2774-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774.rss">Guard entry node</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Guard entry node</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Temple]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Lets assume someone runs a tor hidden service and they are paranoid about guard entry nodes, if one was to run his/her own guard entry node am I correct in thinking this would make the hidden service more secure overall and it would rule out one possible attack method?</p>
<p>Now I’ve never ran any kind of node before, I’m aware I’m going to sound like a newbie because I am and it’s all a learning process to me but am I also correct in thinking I would need to set up a relay and let it run for 8 days before it can become a guard?</p>
<p>If I found a hosting provider which allows relays and I ran only the relay on a VPS what specs would be ideal for this ?</p>
<p>It would be ran on a seprate server to my hidden service as well as seperate provider paid via tumbled BTC.</p>
<p>Lastly as it would be just a relay and a guard node, would this be ok to run a home pc or is the VPS method best as I wouldn’t want to attract and kind of attention, I know exit nodes can cause issues sometimes but I’m unsure about relays/guard nodes.</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 01:17:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-2774-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/guard-entry-node/2774.rss">Guard entry node</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
