<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>confuring the CLI</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556</link>
    <description>I know the CLI version of whonix is for advanced users but I don&#39;t think My PC has the resources to run the GUI adequately. Everything seemed to be going fine and I was presented with the Whonix welcome screen. My PC just froze with a blank black screen and had to force a reboot. Where can I find any documentation on how to set up the CLI version to use Tor and whatever else needs to be configured. I don&#39;t need to understand it, I just need to copy paste the commands.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 09:30:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>confuring the CLI</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>use light wight stable secure gnu/linux distro like Debian and install kvm or virtualbox inside it. im running whonix on debian host with PC made before 12 years ago with 4G ram.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 09:30:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-7556-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556.rss">confuring the CLI</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>confuring the CLI</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixnewbieloser]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I know the CLI version of whonix is for advanced users but I don’t think My PC has the resources to run the GUI adequately. Everything seemed to be going fine and I was presented with the Whonix welcome screen. My PC just froze with a blank black screen and had to force a reboot. Where can I find any documentation on how to set up the CLI version to use Tor and whatever else needs to be configured. I don’t need to understand it, I just need to copy paste the commands.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 13:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-7556-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/confuring-the-cli/7556.rss">confuring the CLI</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
