<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mempo Project</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806</link>
    <description>has anyone here heard of the Mempo project?? what do you think??

it looks interesting and they list whonix, tails, qubes, genoo, debian in a comparison matrix similar style to the one whonix publishes.

http://mempo.org

maybe they should be considered in the whonix comparison matrix?? https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Comparison_with_Others

&lt;blockquote&gt;Mempo Project - Hardened Privacy
Mempo project aims to provide most secure and yet comfortable out-of-the-box computer for Desktop and Server, to professionals, business, journalists, and every-day users avoiding PRISM-like spying.

 Mempo Project is the answer to increasing surveillance of people, and endangered freedom of speech - as well to other IT attacks, cracking by hackers, viruses.
Even professional tools are not secure if there exist way around them for an attacker.

Therefore - in Mempo, the best Privacy &amp; Security tools are used together on all levels from kernel to Apps; preconfigured for VM+Tor+VPN, for virtualization and compartment - all available in one-click fashion as Full Installable OS, Live-CD, or separate programs (sources and .deb files + deb-repo).
Do I need Mempo?
Basically no one is really using the potential of existing security and privacy apps because of time and effort, and professional solutions are fixing given issue - but leaving other small holes.

Most people do not even know about hardware level attacks, root-kits, cold-boot, hacking NIC PCI cards, bugs in e.g. Xen, fire-wire attack, etc.

But is your computer immune (to the extent of currently available software) to known attacks?

Well. If you do use... theoretically unexploitable micro-kernel system like GNU Hurd on OpenRISC or at least GrSecurity max-settings kernel; on custom open-hardware mobo/BIOS/firmware, using PGP/post-QC where needed, with per-app files access-lists, everything is on separate VM on separate user with firewalled tunnels in between, all compiled from source after you meet all the developers on PGP signing-party - then yeah OK, in this case this Project can not offer you much :-)
In any other case - continue below for details.&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 17:12:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[qubenix]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="9" data-topic="806">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/ego/40/45_1.png" class="avatar"> Ego:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>(like that TAILS includes a Bitcoin client out of the box)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The Tails bitcoin client is effectively broken.</p>
<p>They are on Electrum 1.9.8 which produces high S signatures about 50% of the time allowing for the recent malleability attack on the network. Bitcoin Core no longer relays these transactions with high S sigs, so Tails users are having very bad issues and no idea how to fix it. Furthermore when they try to install a newer Electrum using the instructions on Electrums site, they are successful…until reboot. They they have to reinstall every reboot. Advanced users can download to Persistent and run from source, but kids just want to hit the icon.</p>
<p>I’m not sure why Tails team doesn’t want to leave Debians repos to get the newer version, or if they plan to. If you want to see the drama ensuing currently head over to <a href="https://reddit.com/r/darknetmarket" rel="nofollow noopener">https://reddit.com/r/darknetmarket</a> or <a href="https://reddit.com/r/tails" rel="nofollow noopener">https://reddit.com/r/tails</a>. It’s rampant.</p>
<hr>
<p>Other than that I agree with the current assessment of Mempo. Don’t mean to confuse the conversation just had to mention about Electrum as I seen it being mentioned around a lot.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/11</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 17:12:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-11</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixwizard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“Ego, post:9, topic:806”]Good day,</p>
<p>sorry, but as far as I’ve read and understood their current documentation, I’m unable to tell which major improvements Mempo offers compared to using Whonix together with Qubes, aside from their allegedly hardened kernel. Furthermore, their comparison is very old (Qubes for example already has a LiveUSB version), doesn’t include a lot of far better configurations (like Qubes + Whonix with a type 2 hypervisor (XEN)), as well as other facts (like that TAILS includes a Bitcoin client out of the box) and said hardened kernel seems to be everything but usable. In that regard I have to say that the “dream the guys behind Mempo dreamed up” is, to a certain degree, already real, so, as long as they don’t make an active effort of realising the things unique to their concept, I have to object with your “sci-fi comparison”. Or, am I missing some special, new, never before seen feature?</p>
<p>Have a nice day,</p>
<p>Ego[/quote]</p>
<p>The sci-fi comparison was just a short about how categorically sci-fi films have technology that modern scientists and techies strive for, nothing terribly important. I’m a fan of mempo, but not for some exclusive property other than that’s the one project I came across that has a theoretical layout of the most secure out of the box experience. That experience is all I want, for everyone. Taking what you said into account, I’d like to compile a current OS bundle that achieves the same purpose.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/10</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 18:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-10</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Good day,</p>
<p>sorry, but as far as I’ve read and understood their current documentation, I’m unable to tell which major improvements Mempo offers compared to using Whonix together with Qubes, aside from their allegedly hardened kernel. Furthermore, their comparison is very old (Qubes for example already has a LiveUSB version), doesn’t include a lot of far better configurations (like Qubes + Whonix with a type 2 hypervisor (XEN)), as well as other facts (like that TAILS includes a Bitcoin client out of the box) and said hardened kernel seems to be everything but usable. In that regard I have to say that the “dream the guys behind Mempo dreamed up” is, to a certain degree, already real, so, as long as they don’t make an active effort of realising the things unique to their concept, I have to object with your “sci-fi comparison”. Or, am I missing some special, new, never before seen feature?</p>
<p>Have a nice day,</p>
<p>Ego</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/9</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 11:44:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-9</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixwizard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“Patrick, post:7, topic:806”][quote author=whonixwizard link=topic=330.msg11007#msg11007 date=1445627977]</p>
<aside class="quote">
<blockquote>
<p>… So Patrick perhaps now you must think about creating some OS based on vpn chains. That tor is becoming uselss. First they set up porn sites to spoil the dark web and now they went to their next phase i.e. technically implemented shadowbanning and blocking onion sites from running.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>If you have the technical expertise, have you checked out mempo?<br>
[/quote]<br>
Everything said here:<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/forum/index.php/topic,886.0.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/forum/index.php/topic,886.0.html</a></p>
<p>It’s a nice dream. But anyone can sketch a jack of all trades device.<br>
Anyone can sketch superman. He must be able to fly. Oh no. He also must be able to fly through the universe. Oh, and he needs light speed. Easy to make up more stuff.<br>
We’re not of sketches and ideas. It’s not hard to take all the great things out there and to write up a dream about putting it together.<br>
It needs people to do the actual work. Or people pay the required money to make it work. Or who help to collect the money to make it happen. Something like this.<br>
But writing up the dream alone won’t do anything.[/quote]</p>
<p>I can agree with you until that last sentence. Sure <span class="bbcode-i">only</span> writing it shows a lack of initiative, maybe a lack of capability, but having the creativity to write down the dream in the first place- it reminds me of sci-fi films, and how more technical people can watch the movies and get their own ideas on it.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/8</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 23:51:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-8</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“whonixwizard, post:6, topic:806”][quote author=nixx link=topic=330.msg11006#msg11006 date=1445599440]<br>
… So Patrick perhaps now you must think about creating some OS based on vpn chains. That tor is becoming uselss. First they set up porn sites to spoil the dark web and now they went to their next phase i.e. technically implemented shadowbanning and blocking onion sites from running.<br>
[/quote]</p>
<p>If you have the technical expertise, have you checked out mempo?[/quote]<br>
Everything said here:<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/forum/index.php/topic,886.0.html" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://www.whonix.org/forum/index.php/topic,886.0.html</a></p>
<p>It’s a nice dream. But anyone can sketch a jack of all trades device.<br>
Anyone can sketch superman. He must be able to fly. Oh no. He also must be able to fly through the universe. Oh, and he needs light speed. Easy to make up more stuff.<br>
We’re not of sketches and ideas. It’s not hard to take all the great things out there and to write up a dream about putting it together.<br>
It needs people to do the actual work. Or people pay the required money to make it work. Or who help to collect the money to make it happen. Something like this.<br>
But writing up the dream alone won’t do anything.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 20:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-7</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixwizard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="5" data-topic="312">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/n/9dc877/40.png" class="avatar"><a href="//forums.whonix.org/t/some-tor-exit-nodes-have-started-to-block-access-to-certain-web-sites/312/5">Some TOR exit nodes have started to block access to certain web sites</a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p>… So Patrick perhaps now you must think about creating some OS based on vpn chains. That tor is becoming uselss. First they set up porn sites to spoil the dark web and now they went to their next phase i.e. technically implemented shadowbanning and blocking onion sites from running.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>If you have the technical expertise, have you checked out mempo?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 19:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-6</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixwizard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I have searched to little avail on information about the mempo project, and I fear it could die in this thread.</p>
<p>This is an excellent project, with a beautiful philosophy that I think any decentralized, anonymous, private, security (DAPS  ;)) minded computer user should appreciate.</p>
<pre><code>   [b][[/b]  link to the project: https://wiki.debian.org/Mempo  [b]][/b]
</code></pre>
<p>Mempo brings a lot of potential for an every day, secure, and very anonymous way to virtually interact with others on the Internet, as well as perform daily computer functions; document processing, video editing, video games- …okay that last one may be a stretch right now, you got me. It’s in a semi-crude state, I get it.</p>
<p>-Not a jab at the dev, I give kudos to the innovative thinking and criticism to the initiative-</p>
<p>I believe it can be improved upon. I think it’s a fascinating piece of technology waiting patiently for someone to grab it, but that’s got to be acted on by the community now. The dev is not active, and the community suffered because of this, and the community is dwindling down toward its own death if we don’t take the intitiative.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/5</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2015 01:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-5</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group quote-modified" data-username="whovexnode" data-post="3" data-topic="806">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v4/letter/w/a8b319/40.png" class="avatar"> whovexnode:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>[quote]Mempo is now ready to be apt-get installed on top of your Debian - from our repository, follow install instructions there: <a href="http://deb.mempo.org">deb.mempo.org</a> [i2p][/quote]</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>They just have a kernel in the deb repo. That’s about it.<br>
<a href="http://deb.mempo.org/debian/pool/main/l/" class="onebox" target="_blank">http://deb.mempo.org/debian/pool/main/l/</a></p>
<p>[hr]</p>
<p>They surely have good marketing.</p>
<p>Low activity on github:<br>
</p><aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://github.com/mempo" target="_blank">GitHub</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/5312072?s=400&amp;v=4" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://github.com/mempo" target="_blank">mempo - Overview</a></h3>

<p>mempo has 13 repositories available. Follow their code on GitHub.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<p></p>
<p>Checked this project over a year ago. Nothing much has happened since then.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 05:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-4</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whovexnode]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>yeh, still looks like early days for them but also looks like they’ve got some hardened debian system out there</p>
<blockquote>Mempo is now ready to be apt-get installed on top of your Debian - from our repository, follow install instructions there: deb.mempo.org [i2p]</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://deb.mempo.org" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://deb.mempo.org</a></p>
<blockquote>deb.mempo.org - repository for hardened debian
<p>This is the official Download and Install page for Mempo Project - Hardened Privacy as Debian Repository. [trust] [sig] [pub] [i2p] [USK@all-html] [USK@all-txt]</p>
<p>Currently we have here the Grsecurity hardened (and deterministic-build) kernels for Debian and soon other Packages and Security tools.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://p.suchdig.com/p/fnb-mempo_product_philosophy_pdf.pdf" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://p.suchdig.com/p/fnb-mempo_product_philosophy_pdf.pdf</a></p>
<blockquote>Mempo Project: Hardened Privacy
Products and Philosophy (2014.04)
Mempo is a Hardened Debian, secured kernel, privacy applications, simple robust X environment
(LXDE default).
GOAL: provide most secure and yet comfortable out-of-the-box computer for Desktop and Server,
to professionals, business, journalists, and every-day users avoiding PRISM-like spying.
PRODUCTS:
we provide Mempo Project as following products:
1) MempoDeb – an addon (.deb of privacy apps and hardened kernel) added to installed Debian
2) Mempo – is a full system installable from scratch, a copy of Debian but hardened
3) MempoBox – will be providing pre-installed Mempo on custom, ideally open hardware
Provided in Desktop and Server variants, for amd64 (possibly for ARM, i386).
Full Mempo is planned for mid-end 2014, and MempoBox for 2014/2015 depending on kick-starter
startup donations.</blockquote>
<blockquote>FAQ-1: To clear any initial miss-conceptions or questions: Mempo is:
<pre><code>Light and fast
Easy for non-technicals
Modular addons
Learning from Tails, Qubes-OS, Hardened-Gentoo
...but providing more
Prefering GrSec+PAX over SE Linux
Usable like regular Debian
Developed inside Debian.org
Usable on all Linux
Usable on home-made PC
As Primary OS
As packets
As Live-CD
Flash/Wine/etc compatible (VM)
At stage of prototyping
To deliver custom hardware
Always BSD/GPL/0-CC licensed
Giving back to FOSS
Cooperative!
To be crowdfunded
Apolitical
User education focused&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</code></pre>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://github.githubassets.com/favicons/favicon.svg" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://github.com/mempo" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">GitHub</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <img src="https://avatars0.githubusercontent.com/u/5312072?s=400&amp;v=4" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="400" height="400">

<h3><a href="https://github.com/mempo" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">mempo - Overview</a></h3>

<p>mempo has 13 repositories available. Follow their code on GitHub.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

</blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 05:37:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>For now it’s just hot air. No releases. No user base.</p>
<p>Their comparison table makes me laugh. No paranoia lead developers besides mempo.</p>
<p>For now it’s just an interesting dream.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 03:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mempo Project</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whovexnode]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>has anyone here heard of the Mempo project?? what do you think??</p>
<p>it looks interesting and they list whonix, tails, qubes, genoo, debian in a comparison matrix similar style to the one whonix publishes.</p>
<p><a href="http://mempo.org" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://mempo.org</a></p>
<p>maybe they should be considered in the whonix comparison matrix?? <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Comparison_with_Others" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Comparison_with_Others</a></p>
<blockquote>Mempo Project - Hardened Privacy
Mempo project aims to provide most secure and yet comfortable out-of-the-box computer for Desktop and Server, to professionals, business, journalists, and every-day users avoiding PRISM-like spying.
<p>Mempo Project is the answer to increasing surveillance of people, and endangered freedom of speech - as well to other IT attacks, cracking by hackers, viruses.<br>
Even professional tools are not secure if there exist way around them for an attacker.</p>
<p>Therefore - in Mempo, the best Privacy &amp; Security tools are used together on all levels from kernel to Apps; preconfigured for VM+Tor+VPN, for virtualization and compartment - all available in one-click fashion as Full Installable OS, Live-CD, or separate programs (sources and .deb files + deb-repo).<br>
Do I need Mempo?<br>
Basically no one is really using the potential of existing security and privacy apps because of time and effort, and professional solutions are fixing given issue - but leaving other small holes.</p>
<p>Most people do not even know about hardware level attacks, root-kits, cold-boot, hacking NIC PCI cards, bugs in e.g. Xen, fire-wire attack, etc.</p>
<p>But is your computer immune (to the extent of currently available software) to known attacks?</p>
<p>Well. If you do use… theoretically unexploitable micro-kernel system like GNU Hurd on OpenRISC or at least GrSecurity max-settings kernel; on custom open-hardware mobo/BIOS/firmware, using PGP/post-QC where needed, with per-app files access-lists, everything is on separate VM on separate user with firewalled tunnels in between, all compiled from source after you meet all the developers on PGP signing-party - then yeah OK, in this case this Project can not offer you much <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"><br>
In any other case - continue below for details.</p>
</blockquote>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 02:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-806-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/mempo-project/806.rss">Mempo Project</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
