<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Use of useragent changers triggers unsolvable hcaptcha</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803</link>
    <description>Ok so this might be a bit non whonix related but it&#39;s still in the realm of anonymity. I REALLY want to use whonix as my main OS but I also want to have accounts on websites that wont get banned/denied because of the TOR usage. So I install myself firefox-esr and i decide that it would be less triggering for websites if i have non tor proxy and a &quot;normal&quot; browser useragent. So i get myself a chameleon browser extention and I set it to  Windows 10 with Chrome 91 (doesnt get more normie than that).
Imediately when I try to go to blackhat world i get either &quot;Checking your browser before accessing&quot; and it just stays there or i get &quot; One more step Please complete the security check to access blackhatworld com&quot;  
And the hcaptcha becomes unsolvable, meaning that no mather how many times i solve it it doesnt let me pass(happens to few sites and with few it doesnt)
I also use cookiecleaner and webrtc block.
Is there a setting that I&#39;ve missed?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 14:58:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Use of useragent changers triggers unsolvable hcaptcha</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Changing fingerprint doesn’t help much. Tor exit relay IP is already a major giveaway.</p>
<p>Related documentation chapter:<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser#Bypass_Tor_Censorship">Bypass Tor Censorship</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 14:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-11803-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803.rss">Use of useragent changers triggers unsolvable hcaptcha</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Use of useragent changers triggers unsolvable hcaptcha</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[rage1]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Ok so this might be a bit non whonix related but it’s still in the realm of anonymity. I REALLY want to use whonix as my main OS but I also want to have accounts on websites that wont get banned/denied because of the TOR usage. So I install myself firefox-esr and i decide that it would be less triggering for websites if i have non tor proxy and a “normal” browser useragent. So i get myself a chameleon browser extention and I set it to  Windows 10 with Chrome 91 (doesnt get more normie than that).<br>
Imediately when I try to go to blackhat world i get either “Checking your browser before accessing” and it just stays there or i get " One more step Please complete the security check to access blackhatworld com"<br>
And the hcaptcha becomes unsolvable, meaning that no mather how many times i solve it it doesnt let me pass(happens to few sites and with few it doesnt)<br>
I also use cookiecleaner and webrtc block.<br>
Is there a setting that I’ve missed?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 10:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-11803-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/use-of-useragent-changers-triggers-unsolvable-hcaptcha/11803.rss">Use of useragent changers triggers unsolvable hcaptcha</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
