<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Shared Clipboard on Whonix-Gateway &quot;Host To Guest&quot;</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/shared-clipboard-on-whonix-gateway-host-to-guest/4173</link>
    <description>Hello,

I noticed while checking the settings of my Whonix-Gateway that the Shared Clipboard is enabled, and set to &quot;Host To Guest&quot;.  I felt that this was insecure, and disabled it.

I might just be paranoid, but I don&#39;t like the idea of my copy-paste buffer being accessible to the VM.  I would rather it be disabled by default with instructions made available on enabling it - and only when necessary.  I know that is exactly the [policy](https://www.whonix.org/wiki/VirtualBox/Guest_Additions#Clipboard_Sharing) already for Whonix-Workstation, but I think it should be the case for both systems.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 03:30:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>VirtualBox</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/shared-clipboard-on-whonix-gateway-host-to-guest/4173.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Shared Clipboard on Whonix-Gateway &quot;Host To Guest&quot;</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[hocfbszlsnx]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello,</p>
<p>I noticed while checking the settings of my Whonix-Gateway that the Shared Clipboard is enabled, and set to “Host To Guest”.  I felt that this was insecure, and disabled it.</p>
<p>I might just be paranoid, but I don’t like the idea of my copy-paste buffer being accessible to the VM.  I would rather it be disabled by default with instructions made available on enabling it - and only when necessary.  I know that is exactly the <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/VirtualBox/Guest_Additions#Clipboard_Sharing" rel="nofollow noopener">policy</a> already for Whonix-Workstation, but I think it should be the case for both systems.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/shared-clipboard-on-whonix-gateway-host-to-guest/4173/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/shared-clipboard-on-whonix-gateway-host-to-guest/4173/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 03:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-4173-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/shared-clipboard-on-whonix-gateway-host-to-guest/4173.rss">Shared Clipboard on Whonix-Gateway &quot;Host To Guest&quot;</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
