<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Deleting a Whonix ova file</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358</link>
    <description>The Whonix .ova files used for the workstation and gateway (called &quot;open virtualization format archive&quot;) are each larger than 1.5 GB. Is it a problem to delete either of these after the workstation and gateway have been installed, or are they integral to operation and storage within the virtual environments? Would deleting them cause any adverse consequences?

So for example, if one saves files in the &quot;dolphin&quot; file mangager of a workstation and then deletes the &quot;Whonix-workstation-11.0.0.3.0.ova&quot; that he/she downloaded, will this also delete the files stored in the &quot;dolphin&quot; manager? Can a .ova file be downloaded, have a workstation environment extracted from it, and then be deleted?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 13:02:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Deleting a Whonix ova file</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Can be deleted. Deleting them does not influence already imported VMs.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 13:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1358-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358.rss">Deleting a Whonix ova file</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Deleting a Whonix ova file</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dgjhpbn2]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>The Whonix .ova files used for the workstation and gateway (called “open virtualization format archive”) are each larger than 1.5 GB. Is it a problem to delete either of these after the workstation and gateway have been installed, or are they integral to operation and storage within the virtual environments? Would deleting them cause any adverse consequences?</p>
<p>So for example, if one saves files in the “dolphin” file mangager of a workstation and then deletes the “Whonix-workstation-11.0.0.3.0.ova” that he/she downloaded, will this also delete the files stored in the “dolphin” manager? Can a .ova file be downloaded, have a workstation environment extracted from it, and then be deleted?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 04:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1358-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/deleting-a-whonix-ova-file/1358.rss">Deleting a Whonix ova file</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
