<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532</link>
    <description>for long time i was searching for real secure OS to be installed on my hard drive. i didnt find any until i have faced Qubes OS. i dont want to explain anything , u can know about it by going to their website:- www.qubes-os.com 

but the real security when the hardware and software meetings at the same point. 

qubes-os going to be installed by default inside laptops called &quot;librem&quot; from &quot;purism&quot;.

they have fantastically fast laptops they can give u laptop with 32GB ram &amp; i7 processor &amp; 1TB SSD and much more.

Note:- the qubes-purism not yet done. u can say it still in the alpha stages but we hope it will be completed. c this :- https://twitter.com/Puri_sm/status/644963433293717504

purism main website:- https://puri.sm/

make your dream laptop (c the right side of the screen):- https://www.crowdsupply.com/purism/librem-15</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 03:10:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Purism]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks Patrick I no longer work for Purism and I don’t really know what they’re up to. I’m sorry I’m still seemingly out there in cyberspace putting my good name on this project and convincing my influencers to write about him or back the projects.</p>
<p>Not surprised Qubes has backed down.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/12">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/12</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 03:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-12</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Update: the Qubes partnership with Purism is apparently inactive.</p>
<p>(Not due to libreboot criticism. Don’t want to imply any connection.)</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/11">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/11</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 02:08:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-11</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Update: Pursim hardware doesnt seems to be as privacy respected as the company claims. mentioned by libreboot:</p>
<p><a href="https://libreboot.org/faq.html#will-the-purism-laptops-be-supported" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://libreboot.org/faq.html#will-the-purism-laptops-be-supported</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/10">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/10</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 18:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-10</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>wow , thank you very much for your explanation , i really appreciate all your efforts for typing this. great news before sleep <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/+1.png?v=5" title=":+1:" class="emoji" alt=":+1:"> <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/rose.png?v=5" title=":rose:" class="emoji" alt=":rose:">.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 23:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-9</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Purism]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Qubes and Purism announced a partnership today – Qubes will be preinstalled on Librem laptops along with (Debian/Linux-kernel-based) PureOS:</p>
<pre><code>                Purism partners with Qubes,  offering Purism’s freedom-focused hardware bundled together with Qubes’ security-focused operating system.
</code></pre>
<p>Purism, maker of the privacy, security-focused Librem laptops<br>
forms a partnership with the security-focused operating system Qubes OS,<br>
to ensure users are as protected from modern-day security threats as<br>
possible. Conventional security approaches such as antivirus and malware<br>
detection programs are no longer enough to keep out sophisticated<br>
attackers; Qubes OS isolates the operating system’s components allowing<br>
for a more optimal security model than Microsoft Windows or Apple OSX<br>
can provide.</p>
<p>San Francisco, CA and Poland – (PRWEB) December 08, 2015</p>
<p>In the midst of growing concerns about identity theft, Internet<br>
privacy, cybersecurity and digital rights, Purism, maker of the privacy,<br>
security, and freedom-focused Librem laptops has announced a<br>
partnership with the security-focused operating system Qubes OS, to<br>
ensure users are as protected from modern-day security threats as<br>
possible.</p>
<p>This partnership will continue to evolve to push security for<br>
users in a positive direction within the hardware manufacturing process.</p>
<p>Qubes OS provides security through “compartmentalization.” If a<br>
user’s browser is compromised while visiting a website, for example, the<br>
attacker does not gain access to other information or programs on the<br>
system, such as sensitive documents, passwords, photos or personal data.<br>
Conventional security approaches such as antivirus and malware<br>
detection programs are no longer enough to keep out sophisticated<br>
attackers.</p>
<p>Qubes OS isolates the operating system’s components allowing<br>
for a more optimal security model than Microsoft Windows or Apple OSX<br>
can provide.</p>
<p>In addition, Qubes comes with Whonix-powered Tor integration,<br>
enabling the user to easily route network traffic through the Tor<br>
anonymity network. Given these features, combining Qubes with Purism<br>
Librem laptops is a natural fit – and users will benefit by being able<br>
to order Qubes OS preinstalled on the Librem 13.</p>
<p>“We are pleased to partner with the Purism team both in offering a<br>
certified Qubes OS laptop today, and in the future improving the<br>
functionality and security of Purism laptops to ensure that users can<br>
have the best of freedom, security and privacy in one convenient<br>
package,” said Joanna Rutkowska, well-known security researcher and<br>
founder of the Qubes OS project.</p>
<p>“We are ecstatic about the partnership between Purism and Qubes so we<br>
can bring together our goals of privacy, security and freedom in<br>
hardware with the best approach in software security. This union<br>
represents the ideal approach to protecting users by default, without<br>
sacrificing convenience or usability,” said Todd Weaver, CEO of Purism.<br>
“Qubes OS is a natural fit with the Purism Librem laptops in both<br>
functionality and ideology.”</p>
<p>The Librem: Privacy-Respecting Hardware</p>
<p>Purism’s goal with the Librem laptop is to offer a high-end computer<br>
with a simple, out-of-the-box, privacy-enhancing experience. The Librem<br>
laptop computer features privacy “kill switches” to physically shut off<br>
the camera, microphone and data connection, deterring data thieves,<br>
spies, cyberstalkers and hackers.</p>
<p>Librem 13:</p>
<p>The new Librem 13 is now shipping. It can be ordered at <a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/purism/librem-13" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.crowdsupply.com/purism/librem-13</a>, for a base price of $1649 US, including Qubes OS.<br>
Orders are shipped on a first-come, first-served basis in the order<br>
they were received. There is an additional shipping charge of $80 for<br>
orders outside the USA.</p>
<p>CrowdSupply will accept all forms of international currency including Bitcoin.</p>
<p>About Qubes OS:</p>
<p>Qubes OS is a security-oriented free and open source operating system<br>
for personal computers. Recognizing there can be no perfect, bug-free<br>
computing environment, Qubes aims instead to secure typical workflows<br>
through controlled interaction and minimize the attack surface for<br>
adversaries through compartmentalization.</p>
<p>Its architecture is built to enable a user to define different<br>
security environments or “domains” on their computer based on their<br>
threat model and manage their interaction with each other. This allows<br>
the user to control the level of access an application has to other<br>
information, protecting confidential work both from compromise and from<br>
exfiltration.</p>
<p>It can run Debian, Fedora, Whonix, and even Windows-based applications within this environment. For more information, visit: <a href="https://www.qubes-os.org" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.qubes-os.org</a></p>
<p>About Purism:</p>
<p>Purism’s goal is to manufacture secure, freedom, and<br>
privacy-respecting computers, leading the way in protecting your digital<br>
life by making security and privacy simpler — so protecting your<br>
privacy is easier than giving it up.</p>
<p>Purism is devoted to providing the<br>
highest quality hardware available, with the goal that the user’s data<br>
is kept private and is secure from hacking, malware, spyware, identity<br>
theft and other threats that cannot be prevented with antivirus or<br>
malware detection alone. Purism is based in San Francisco, California,<br>
and its products are assembled in the United States from components<br>
manufactured and sourced internationally.</p>
<p>Privately held and privately<br>
funded, Purism has raised over $861,000 to date solely with crowd<br>
funding, making the Librem laptops one of the top three most successful<br>
crowd funded PC hardware projects in history, according to ZDNet, and<br>
the <span class="hashtag">#1</span> crowd funded hardware project on Crowd Supply.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/8</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 23:29:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-8</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Good day,</p>
<p>yes, the Russians are developing their own CPUs, like the elbrus using an ancient 65nm structure. However, these seem to be far from finished and even if they were available and supported in a reasonable manner, I wouldn’t trust the Russians over the Americans, in areas like technology. In other areas (politics, economy, etc.) Russia is objectively the “lesser evil” over the US, however, in the area of technology and government surveillance, I think they are just as bad. In the case of the CPUs, the only question is, who rather should have access, the Russian Federation, or the United states.</p>
<p>Have a nice day,</p>
<p>Ego</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/7</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 17:30:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-7</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Hiberts]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hi,<br>
I maybe can’t help you but last year I heard that Russia Federation was being to tranfer the informatics environment out of Intel tecnhology ( x86 and x64 ) because a Russian expert supposed a hardware backdoor .<br>
I remember that Putin is being change the all national security system to arm architecture .<br>
Do you know more about this ?</p>
<p>( of course, lefting out conflict USA-Russia, our interest is informatics environment )</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/6</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2015 16:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-6</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>(qubes-os.org not .com)</blockquote>
<p>yeah, thnx for the correction.  <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<blockquote>Good find, this is definitely a really cool partnership and product. I will definitely be looking more into this, I have a current laptop and no need for a new one, but I know a few people that will love this.</blockquote>
<p>its not just having laptop, for example most laptops doesnt give TPM (used in anti evil protection) in BIOS or even sometimes VT-x. but with librem it is a must to c these options there.</p>
<p>for more about hardware compatibility:- <a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/hcl/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.qubes-os.org/hcl/</a></p>
<p>and here is the same , i will look forward to buy one in the future  ;).</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/5</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 19:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-5</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixwizard]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>(<a href="http://qubes-os.org" rel="nofollow noopener">qubes-os.org</a> not .com)</p>
<p>Good find, this is definitely a really cool partnership and product. I will definitely be looking more into this, I have a current laptop and no need for a new one, but I know a few people that will love this.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/4</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 18:41:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-4</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>yeah true it is a good one , the moment to be 99.999% sure that u r safe even from NSA is to have heavy duty laptop with fully open source hardware.</p>
<p>purism provide secure BIOS and chips that dont initiate program installing without the user awareness. but it still using intel for example for their processor.</p>
<p>so i think the perfect future form is to have Qubes-Whonix + librem fully opened source = i think its going to be best anon-secure laptop ever made for the public.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 22:11:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Ego]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Good day,</p>
<p>seeing Purism and Qubes team up is definitely a good thing. Personally, I’ve staid away from the Librem campaign in fear of the device simply not being produced at all, like it has happened with a lot of interesting crowd funding campaigns, but they seem to currently ship the promised devices, so I might look into buying one, even though, to be honest, against every security concept imaginable I currently have my eyes laid on the new Surface line.</p>
<p>Have a nice day,</p>
<p>Ego</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 19:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[TNT_BOM_BOM]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>for long time i was searching for real secure OS to be installed on my hard drive. i didnt find any until i have faced Qubes OS. i dont want to explain anything , u can know about it by going to their website:- <a href="http://www.qubes-os.com" rel="nofollow noopener">www.qubes-os.com</a></p>
<p>but the real security when the hardware and software meetings at the same point.</p>
<p>qubes-os going to be installed by default inside laptops called “librem” from “purism”.</p>
<p>they have fantastically fast laptops they can give u laptop with 32GB ram &amp; i7 processor &amp; 1TB SSD and much more.</p>
<p>Note:- the qubes-purism not yet done. u can say it still in the alpha stages but we hope it will be completed. c this :- <a href="https://twitter.com/Puri_sm/status/644963433293717504" rel="nofollow noopener">https://twitter.com/Puri_sm/status/644963433293717504</a></p>
<p>purism main website:- <a href="https://puri.sm/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://puri.sm/</a></p>
<p>make your dream laptop (c the right side of the screen):- <a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/purism/librem-15" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.crowdsupply.com/purism/librem-15</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 19:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1532-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/the-new-erra-of-software-hardware-security-born/1532.rss">The New Erra of Software/Hardware Security Born</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
