<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Any games over Tor using Whonix as game server?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/any-games-over-tor-using-whonix-as-game-server/3939</link>
    <description>I&#39;m thinking about running some kind of game server over Tor. Since games usually require UDP I know they wont work on the whonix workstation but I think some really simple games should work. Like chess or a multiplayer text adventure. Don&#39;t think this has been attempted or done before so maybe I can contribute in this area

Edit: I&#39;m looking into chess servers but it seems FICS makes nobody want to run their own. I&#39;ll see if I can instead of hosting my own play there instead. Would be fun though to run a chess server from an .onion

I will look into this code https://github.com/Milek7/telnet-games some day. Not really a chess server but I&#39;ll check out what its about. **Checked it out, found no straightforward way to install it.**

This is https://github.com/ivailozd/TicTacToe and I&#39;m gonna check it out. The 3 .java files are considered &quot;Perl5 modules&quot;. **I may try this some day if I realize how to do run it**

When thinking about playable games like nethack https://nethackwiki.com/wiki/Public_server http://nethack3dzllmbmo.onion is mentioned</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 09:01:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/any-games-over-tor-using-whonix-as-game-server/3939.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Any games over Tor using Whonix as game server?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[avatargiga]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I’m thinking about running some kind of game server over Tor. Since games usually require UDP I know they wont work on the whonix workstation but I think some really simple games should work. Like chess or a multiplayer text adventure. Don’t think this has been attempted or done before so maybe I can contribute in this area</p>
<p>Edit: I’m looking into chess servers but it seems FICS makes nobody want to run their own. I’ll see if I can instead of hosting my own play there instead. Would be fun though to run a chess server from an .onion</p>
<p>I will look into this code <a href="https://github.com/Milek7/telnet-games" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/Milek7/telnet-games</a> some day. Not really a chess server but I’ll check out what its about. <strong>Checked it out, found no straightforward way to install it.</strong></p>
<p>This is <a href="https://github.com/ivailozd/TicTacToe" rel="nofollow noopener">https://github.com/ivailozd/TicTacToe</a> and I’m gonna check it out. The 3 .java files are considered “Perl5 modules”. <strong>I may try this some day if I realize how to do run it</strong></p>
<p>When thinking about playable games like nethack <a href="https://nethackwiki.com/wiki/Public_server" rel="nofollow noopener">https://nethackwiki.com/wiki/Public_server</a> <a href="http://nethack3dzllmbmo.onion" rel="nofollow noopener">http://nethack3dzllmbmo.onion</a> is mentioned</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/any-games-over-tor-using-whonix-as-game-server/3939/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/any-games-over-tor-using-whonix-as-game-server/3939/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 13:20:59 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-3939-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/any-games-over-tor-using-whonix-as-game-server/3939.rss">Any games over Tor using Whonix as game server?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
