<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>PaSh for parallelizing shell scripts</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755</link>
    <description>https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-PaSh

https://binpa.sh/

&gt; The Linux Foundation announced today they will be hosting the PaSh project that is focused on automatically parallelizing POSIX shell scripts.
&gt; 
&gt; PaSh is focused on optimizing shell scripts for faster performance in areas around data science, engineering, economists, and more. The apparent Linux Foundation focus is on industrial use-cases.
&gt; 
&gt; The Linux Foundation explained in this [announcement](https://linuxfoundation.org/press-release/linux-foundation-to-host-the-pash-project-accelerating-shell-scripting-with-automated-parallelization-for-industrial-use-cases/), &quot;*To accelerate shell scripts, PaSh provides a source-to-source parallelizing compiler, a program that takes as input a programmer’s shell script and returns a new program that is significantly faster than the original program. Since PaSh is source-to-source, it allows the optimized shell script to be inspected and executed using the same tools, in the same environment, and with the same data as the original script. A small runtime library and associated annotations on programs commonly used in shell scripts complete the picture, providing the PaSh compiler with high-performance primitives and supporting its key functions.*&quot;

***

Could be a great benefit for our bash programs , but I wonder if there are any unforeseen security implications.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 07:54:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Development</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>PaSh for parallelizing shell scripts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Simplified: These aren’t providing attack surface or are performance critical.</p>
<p>Perhaps Debian and/or systemd would one day integrate with PaSh. In case o Debian, not that likely. Debian APT is still pretty much serialized installing packages and doesn’t have much parallelization. Compiled shell scripts might speed it up a bit but actually I find the cleartext Debian package maintenance scripts very useful for exploration and bug triage.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755/2</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 07:54:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-12755-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755.rss">PaSh for parallelizing shell scripts</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>PaSh for parallelizing shell scripts</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[HulaHoop]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-PaSh" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.phoronix.com/scan.php?page=news_item&amp;px=Linux-Foundation-PaSh</a></p>
<p><a href="https://binpa.sh/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://binpa.sh/</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Linux Foundation announced today they will be hosting the PaSh project that is focused on automatically parallelizing POSIX shell scripts.</p>
<p>PaSh is focused on optimizing shell scripts for faster performance in areas around data science, engineering, economists, and more. The apparent Linux Foundation focus is on industrial use-cases.</p>
<p>The Linux Foundation explained in this <a href="https://linuxfoundation.org/press-release/linux-foundation-to-host-the-pash-project-accelerating-shell-scripting-with-automated-parallelization-for-industrial-use-cases/">announcement</a>, “<em>To accelerate shell scripts, PaSh provides a source-to-source parallelizing compiler, a program that takes as input a programmer’s shell script and returns a new program that is significantly faster than the original program. Since PaSh is source-to-source, it allows the optimized shell script to be inspected and executed using the same tools, in the same environment, and with the same data as the original script. A small runtime library and associated annotations on programs commonly used in shell scripts complete the picture, providing the PaSh compiler with high-performance primitives and supporting its key functions.</em>”</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>Could be a great benefit for our bash programs , but I wonder if there are any unforeseen security implications.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 13:18:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-12755-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/pash-for-parallelizing-shell-scripts/12755.rss">PaSh for parallelizing shell scripts</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
