<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>[Question] System compromisation</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296</link>
    <description>So in the latest Whonix updates the option to change wallpaper has been removed in order to minimize the risk of system&#39;s compromisation. (via fingerprinting i guess)

**My question comes in 2 parts:**

* Is it possible in a compromised system, that custom wallpaper to be used against you?

* What if i already have the metadata removed?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 18:14:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>[Question] System compromisation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>emarex via Whonix Forum:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>So in the latest Whonix updates the option to change wallpaper has been removed</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Default wallpaper changed. Option to change wallpaper wasn’t removed<br>
intentionally by Whonix.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>in order to minimize the risk of system’s compromisation. (via fingerprinting i guess)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wrong assumption. Wallpaper gateway vs workstation was changed to make<br>
it harder to visually confuse host vs gateway vs workstation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>My question comes in 2 parts:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Is it possible in a compromised system, that custom wallpaper to be used against you?</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>If the system is already compromised, then the wallpaper is the least of<br>
the worries. In theory a specifically crafted image could exploit the<br>
system and gain remote code execution by using that image as a<br>
wallpaper. I haven’t heard that happening in practice yet but it would<br>
be conceivable for targeted attacks as the code processing the wallpaper<br>
may or may not be scrutinized as much.</p>
<p>In theory, metadata removal might help to reduce attack surface when<br>
viewing images in image viewers or using images as wallpapers. Because<br>
that is probably what an attacker excepts to happen when sharing<br>
malicious images designed to exploit vulnerabilities. Some buffer<br>
overflow bug might happen during processing of the metadata. I would<br>
speculate it is less likely having an attacker targeting metadata<br>
removal tools such as <code>mat2</code> than popular image viewers.</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>What if i already have the metadata removed?</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Why would you bother changing the wallpaper in first place? Consider a<br>
VM might be compromised at some point. Best to drop anything non-essential.</p>
<p>Metadata removal is not a magic bullet.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Metadata" target="_blank" title="10:56PM - 11 July 2020">Whonix – 11 Jul 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:523/197;"><img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/9/94/Mat.png" class="thumbnail" width="523" height="197"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Metadata" target="_blank">Metadata - Whonix</a></h3>

<p>Anonymize Files - Clear Metadata - Remove Location Tracking - Use the Metadata Anonymisation Toolkit v2 (MAT2)</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>A wallpaper isn’t a special kind of image. It’s just a normal image used<br>
as wallpaper.</p>
<p>I don’t see any use case of removing metadata (hiding data such as<br>
location data, where image was made) from an image and then at the same<br>
time using that image as wallpaper (making it more visible for anyone<br>
shoulder surfing).</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 18:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-10296-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296.rss">[Question] System compromisation</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>[Question] System compromisation</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[emarex]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So in the latest Whonix updates the option to change wallpaper has been removed in order to minimize the risk of system’s compromisation. (via fingerprinting i guess)</p>
<p><strong>My question comes in 2 parts:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Is it possible in a compromised system, that custom wallpaper to be used against you?</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>What if i already have the metadata removed?</p>
</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 15:43:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-10296-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/question-system-compromisation/10296.rss">[Question] System compromisation</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
