<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>2 Questions? There were 2 levels of support but how much &amp; VOIP</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/2-questions-there-were-2-levels-of-support-but-how-much-voip/15987</link>
    <description>1)So there are 2 support options.  But it says pick an appropriate amount I believe.  so, I just select whatever option I want to pay?   Then that is $100 every 30 days, right?  That is the first question. Am I misunderstanding?  Is something not fully loading - how much do I pay. 

2) whonix --- /wiki/VoIP Up until about 40 minutes ago, until I read that.  I thought myself and another person would somehow use whonix and skype to make fairly secure video calls.  I have personally been hacked twice over many years.   Paypal/Bank.  Both times money was returned and I was told to not ask more questions, just take the money be happy.  They did not allow me to ask if I did anything wrong or should do anything better.  Refunded, helped me.  Then told me keep using our stuff, bye.......  Since them I use TOR.  It might be coincidental.  But I&#39;ve had no more issues.

After a bit of reading. It seems it will either be impossible to make video calls using a TOR/Whonix or rock the boat.  It feels like it might &#39;violate&#39; terms of service or &quot;expected use&quot; policies.   If I use it for video it takes up too many resources.  I&#39;d be happy to pay for premium support here and on tor(It does not exist there I know) but donate there..  However, I still think I would be told:  &quot;It is not possible.  Or &quot;we can&#39;t really help you&quot;.
-- Low Quality with occasional poor is not great but tolerable.  Upper Low/Medium
-- Short Duration and Frequency 1 60 minute call once a month

Am I correct in above statements?  Is there anything I can do, I tried to dig on my own for a little on my own.  also still curious about whonix support costs. I am sure I will need it for other things.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 12:41:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/2-questions-there-were-2-levels-of-support-but-how-much-voip/15987.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>2 Questions? There were 2 levels of support but how much &amp; VOIP</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[BobTimToe]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>1)So there are 2 support options.  But it says pick an appropriate amount I believe.  so, I just select whatever option I want to pay?   Then that is $100 every 30 days, right?  That is the first question. Am I misunderstanding?  Is something not fully loading - how much do I pay.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li>whonix — /wiki/VoIP Up until about 40 minutes ago, until I read that.  I thought myself and another person would somehow use whonix and skype to make fairly secure video calls.  I have personally been hacked twice over many years.   Paypal/Bank.  Both times money was returned and I was told to not ask more questions, just take the money be happy.  They did not allow me to ask if I did anything wrong or should do anything better.  Refunded, helped me.  Then told me keep using our stuff, bye…  Since them I use TOR.  It might be coincidental.  But I’ve had no more issues.</li>
</ol>
<p>After a bit of reading. It seems it will either be impossible to make video calls using a TOR/Whonix or rock the boat.  It feels like it might ‘violate’ terms of service or “expected use” policies.   If I use it for video it takes up too many resources.  I’d be happy to pay for premium support here and on tor(It does not exist there I know) but donate there…  However, I still think I would be told:  "It is not possible.  Or “we can’t really help you”.<br>
– Low Quality with occasional poor is not great but tolerable.  Upper Low/Medium<br>
– Short Duration and Frequency 1 60 minute call once a month</p>
<p>Am I correct in above statements?  Is there anything I can do, I tried to dig on my own for a little on my own.  also still curious about whonix support costs. I am sure I will need it for other things.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/2-questions-there-were-2-levels-of-support-but-how-much-voip/15987/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/2-questions-there-were-2-levels-of-support-but-how-much-voip/15987/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 12:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15987-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/2-questions-there-were-2-levels-of-support-but-how-much-voip/15987.rss">2 Questions? There were 2 levels of support but how much &amp; VOIP</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
