<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Whonix/KVM installed but can&#39;t find VM running OS</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228</link>
    <description>I installed KVM and Whonix. I chose KVM over Virtualbox because that&#39;s what https://www.whonix.org/wiki/KVM recommended. I used that page as my guide. I got all the way down to the GUI method of starting up, namely,

Start Menu -&gt; Applications -&gt; System -&gt; Virtual Machine Manager

I then turned on the Whonix-Gateway and Whonix-Workstation from the Virtual Machine Manager window.

Now I&#39;m stuck. I can&#39;t figure out what to do next! Where&#39;s the tor broswer? Where is the virtual machine running Whonix? I don&#39;t see any window that looks like a virtual machine running an operating system. I just have 2 icons on the left side of the window (Whonix-Gateway and Whonix-Worstation) and two small graphs on the right side. What do I do next?

I&#39;ve searched for the next step for a long time. I&#39;m stumped. I know I&quot;m missing something basic, but I can&#39;t figure out what. Would someone give me a tip on what to do next to get a virtual machine with tor browser? Thank you.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 13:08:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>KVM</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Whonix/KVM installed but can&#39;t find VM running OS</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[parminides]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>After a good night’s sleep and a fresh mind, I was able to figure it out. There were some error messages in the workstation console that I forgot to mention last night: “cannot display graphical console” and “no module named SpiceClientGtk.” I didn’t realize their significance last night, but this morning I found an Ubuntu forum that advised installing a missing package:</p>
<p>sudo apt-get install python-spice-client-gtk</p>
<p>That did the trick! I have a workstation.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 13:08:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-3228-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228.rss">Whonix/KVM installed but can&#39;t find VM running OS</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix/KVM installed but can&#39;t find VM running OS</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[parminides]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I installed KVM and Whonix. I chose KVM over Virtualbox because that’s what <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/KVM" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/KVM</a> recommended. I used that page as my guide. I got all the way down to the GUI method of starting up, namely,</p>
<p>Start Menu -&gt; Applications -&gt; System -&gt; Virtual Machine Manager</p>
<p>I then turned on the Whonix-Gateway and Whonix-Workstation from the Virtual Machine Manager window.</p>
<p>Now I’m stuck. I can’t figure out what to do next! Where’s the tor broswer? Where is the virtual machine running Whonix? I don’t see any window that looks like a virtual machine running an operating system. I just have 2 icons on the left side of the window (Whonix-Gateway and Whonix-Worstation) and two small graphs on the right side. What do I do next?</p>
<p>I’ve searched for the next step for a long time. I’m stumped. I know I"m missing something basic, but I can’t figure out what. Would someone give me a tip on what to do next to get a virtual machine with tor browser? Thank you.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 03:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-3228-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-kvm-installed-but-cant-find-vm-running-os/3228.rss">Whonix/KVM installed but can&#39;t find VM running OS</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
