<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Security risks connecting USB drive with Workstation?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709</link>
    <description>In reviewing security documentation I&#39;ve seen reference to these 2 security issues with using a USB drive with Workstation:

1. serial number may leak into Whonix environment.
2. attacker could remotely flash the drive.

Could anyone elaborate on these risks by answering any of these questions:

-what are the possible bad results if the USB drive&#39;s serial number is exposed in Whonix? How could that lead to de-anonymization?
-I&#39;m not sure what &quot;flashing&quot; is. What could be the bad results of an attacker flashing the USB drive while connected to Whonix?
-do you have to be de-anonymized before these USB problems could occur?
-does tunneling Whonix through a VPN reduce the risk of these USB vulnerabilities?

Thanks.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 01:19:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>VirtualBox</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Security risks connecting USB drive with Workstation?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Lidecker78:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>-what are the possible bad results if the USB drive’s serial number<br>
is exposed in Whonix? How could that lead to de-anonymization?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes, if these serial numbers are stored somewhere else also. They<br>
could be limited to a specific geographical area. Or they might even<br>
have a trail to who sold it. And the seller might have a trail to whom<br>
it was sold.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>-I’m not sure what “flashing” is. What could be the bad results of<br>
an attacker flashing the USB drive while connected to Whonix?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Flashing means overwriting the firmware. Which is, simply put, like<br>
the operating system running on a device. On the USB stack in this<br>
case. Malware could be flashed on the firmware while the USB is still<br>
functional. Once reconnecting the USB to the host</p>
<blockquote>
<p>-do you have to be de-anonymized before these USB problems could<br>
occur?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In most cases, the VM needs to be already compromised.</p>
<p>Reading USB serials though non-code exploration level exploits, bugs<br>
or new fancy [browser or similar] features is also thinkable. [Like<br>
webrtc allows to read the users <em>local</em> IP address.]</p>
<blockquote>
<p>-does tunneling Whonix through a VPN reduce the risk of these USB<br>
vulnerabilities?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>No.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709/2</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 01:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1709-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709.rss">Security risks connecting USB drive with Workstation?</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Security risks connecting USB drive with Workstation?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Lidecker78]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>In reviewing security documentation I’ve seen reference to these 2 security issues with using a USB drive with Workstation:</p>
<ol>
<li>serial number may leak into Whonix environment.</li>
<li>attacker could remotely flash the drive.</li>
</ol>
<p>Could anyone elaborate on these risks by answering any of these questions:</p>
<p>-what are the possible bad results if the USB drive’s serial number is exposed in Whonix? How could that lead to de-anonymization?<br>
-I’m not sure what “flashing” is. What could be the bad results of an attacker flashing the USB drive while connected to Whonix?<br>
-do you have to be de-anonymized before these USB problems could occur?<br>
-does tunneling Whonix through a VPN reduce the risk of these USB vulnerabilities?</p>
<p>Thanks.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 23:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1709-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/security-risks-connecting-usb-drive-with-workstation/1709.rss">Security risks connecting USB drive with Workstation?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
