<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>No, it can&#39;t be tor</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668</link>
    <description>Something is really wrong with Whonix Gateway 16. It&#39;s unbearably, frustratingly how slow internet speed through it is! Like from five thousand bytes to 35kBps at most!
I don&#39;t live in censored area, on the contrary - so it&#39;s not the ISP.
It&#39;s not the tor network/entry-guards congestion 
Here&#39;s why they aren&#39;t.

Using WGw15 in virtualbox. Speed - from 0.5-2MBps. Never ever had problems with this and previous version&#39;s speed. Upgraded vm in-place without single issue. Consequence - catastrophic speed. Lost my WGw15 vm.
Imported ova Whonix16 appliance, fresh new install, again catastrophic speed. Shutdown. Import Whonix 15 appliance, routing all the traffic through WGw15, normal speed, 0.5-2MBps. WGw16 vm deleted, using WGw15. Let&#39;s start WGw16 from time to time, let&#39;s start in parallel with WGw15, comparing speeds. No changes. For days, weeks...
It&#39;s not about WS. Many of my vm&#39;s are routed through WG and all of them act the same as WS, regarding connection speed through WGw15/16, no matter they run in parallel or not.

Not enough?
No problem. Let&#39;s install Qubes 4.1 beta 1 after a month. It comes with Whonix15. Popups everywhere it is deprecated. Speed 0.5-2MBps, though.
Ok, let&#39;s backup all whonix based cubes. Let&#39;s upgrade in-place now. &quot;INFO: OK. (release-upgrade version: 1.5) Release upgrade success.&quot; for both GW and WS.

And, you guess, again this time in Qubes OS, speed from 0.005-0.035MBps. Let&#39;s restore WGw15. Oh, geez, how fast it can looks 0.5-2MBps...


Please help, please! Please give some idea that doesn&#39;t include bridges or/and entry guards, because obviously it&#39;s not about that. I don&#39;t want to use anything else than Whonix (exept Kicksecure for clearnet) prefferably in Qubes, i just have no choice.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 16:26:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>No, it can&#39;t be tor</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[qw16]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hey guys, thanks a lot for your responses. I have to study all of you mentioned without sub-questions ( I don’t want to spinoff the topic), and will be back. Considering my level of Linux competence (from Newbie to mildly regular user), probably it will need several days.<br>
It’s just frustrating: release-upgrading debian-10 qube in-place lasted for 6hours, while just before that I upgraded in-place both WGw and WS in 15 minutes or so in parallel, all via sys-whonix(15, of course)!</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/4</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 16:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-12668-4</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668.rss">No, it can&#39;t be tor</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>No, it can&#39;t be tor</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Debugging this could be complex. The steps / information required are the same as already in documentation, please have a look here:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#Connectivity_Troubleshooting">Connectivity Troubleshooting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Troubleshooting#ICMP_Fix">ICMP Fix</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor#Connectivity_Troubleshooting">Tor Connectivity Troubleshooting</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Last resort being <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor#Tor_Generic_Bug_Reproduction">Tor Generic Bug Reproduction</a>.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/3</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 13:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-12668-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668.rss">No, it can&#39;t be tor</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>No, it can&#39;t be tor</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[torjunkie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>What about if you set up a sys-whonix-text in Whonix-16 with new guards? My recollection was that not all guards are equal in this regard.</p>
<p>Unlikely to be a Whonix-16 wide issue, or many other users would have mentioned it already, several weeks after release.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 10:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-12668-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668.rss">No, it can&#39;t be tor</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>No, it can&#39;t be tor</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[qw16]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Something is really wrong with Whonix Gateway 16. It’s unbearably, frustratingly how slow internet speed through it is! Like from five thousand bytes to 35kBps at most!<br>
I don’t live in censored area, on the contrary - so it’s not the ISP.<br>
It’s not the tor network/entry-guards congestion<br>
Here’s why they aren’t.</p>
<p>Using WGw15 in virtualbox. Speed - from 0.5-2MBps. Never ever had problems with this and previous version’s speed. Upgraded vm in-place without single issue. Consequence - catastrophic speed. Lost my WGw15 vm.<br>
Imported ova Whonix16 appliance, fresh new install, again catastrophic speed. Shutdown. Import Whonix 15 appliance, routing all the traffic through WGw15, normal speed, 0.5-2MBps. WGw16 vm deleted, using WGw15. Let’s start WGw16 from time to time, let’s start in parallel with WGw15, comparing speeds. No changes. For days, weeks…<br>
It’s not about WS. Many of my vm’s are routed through WG and all of them act the same as WS, regarding connection speed through WGw15/16, no matter they run in parallel or not.</p>
<p>Not enough?<br>
No problem. Let’s install Qubes 4.1 beta 1 after a month. It comes with Whonix15. Popups everywhere it is deprecated. Speed 0.5-2MBps, though.<br>
Ok, let’s backup all whonix based cubes. Let’s upgrade in-place now. “INFO: OK. (release-upgrade version: 1.5) Release upgrade success.” for both GW and WS.</p>
<p>And, you guess, again this time in Qubes OS, speed from 0.005-0.035MBps. Let’s restore WGw15. Oh, geez, how fast it can looks 0.5-2MBps…</p>
<p>Please help, please! Please give some idea that doesn’t include bridges or/and entry guards, because obviously it’s not about that. I don’t want to use anything else than Whonix (exept Kicksecure for clearnet) prefferably in Qubes, i just have no choice.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 23:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-12668-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/no-it-cant-be-tor/12668.rss">No, it can&#39;t be tor</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
