<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Sigh..another post about customizing Tor Browser in a Qubes-Whonix template</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976</link>
    <description>I for the life of me cannot get my security settings and changes to &#39;about:config&#39; to persist after creating an I2P-Whonix workstation disposable template. I have read and re-read the Whonix documentation and the previous forum discussions on this topic. The exact point of failure is after I turn the AppVM into the disp template using the commands &quot;qvm-prefs exampleappvmname template_for_dispvms True&quot; and &quot;qvm-features exampleappvmname appmenus-dispvm 1&quot;. 

The TLDR rundown of the steps I take are:

* Clone the whonix-ws-16 template
* Install and configure I2P-Java according to docs
* Close template and build an AppVM based on it [b](without a NetVM attached)[/b]
* Start Tor Browser in the freshly built AppVM and configure the settings I need
* Close the AppVM and clone it, giving it some title with &quot;dvm&quot; tacked on
* Run those 2 commands previously stated in Dom0
* Start a disposable VM from the Applications Menu and manually add sys-whonix as the NetVM in the Qubes Manager

During my troubleshooting of this issue, I have found that the customization I do to Tor Browser persists in the actual disposable VM template, but [b]not[/b] in the dispvm&#39;s that are made out of the template. And changes I make to another browser, like Firefox for example, do persist in each new dispvm, like intended. 

I think I am narrowing down the issue being related to &#39;~.tb&#39; not being generated until after Tor Browser is started, which is a problem when each dispvm is brand new and Tor Browser has not had the chance to start yet. My next guess in solving this issue is to customize the settings I need in the proper config files located somewhere in &#39;/var&#39; in the original I2P-Whonix template, before I create the AppVMs based on it.. Does that sound right? Some tips on how to properly edit those config files would be greatly appreciated, since I [i]think[/i] the &#39;~.tb&#39; directory is generated from the cache files in &#39;/var&#39;.

Am I on the right track or completely off base? Any and all help / feedback is welcome. I just want to start my I2P-Whonix dispvms without having to configure every setting every time in Tor Browser!!

Thank you.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 06:39:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Qubes-Whonix</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Sigh..another post about customizing Tor Browser in a Qubes-Whonix template</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Did you see yet these wiki chapters?</p>
<p>For technical background:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser/Advanced_Users#Tor_Browser_Update:_Technical_Details">Tor Browser Advanced Topics chapter Tor Browser_Update:_Technical_Details in Whonix wiki</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser/Advanced_Users#Qubes-specific">Tor Browser Advanced Topics chapter Qubes-specific in Whonix wiki</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And then the user documentation:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Qubes#Qubes_Persistence">Qubes-Whonix ™ Overview chapter Qubes Persistence in Whonix wiki</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser/Advanced_Users#Disposable_Template_Customization">Tor Browser Advanced Topics chapter Disposable Template Customization in Whonix wiki</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Which option did you choose?</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser/Advanced_Users#Option_1:_Disposable_Template_Method">Option 1: Disposable Template Method</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser/Advanced_Users#Option_2:_Template_Method">Option 2: Template Method</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser/Advanced_Users#Option_3:_Manual_Method">Option 3: Manual Method</a></li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976/2</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 06:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15976-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976.rss">Sigh..another post about customizing Tor Browser in a Qubes-Whonix template</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Sigh..another post about customizing Tor Browser in a Qubes-Whonix template</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[dr_feelgood]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I for the life of me cannot get my security settings and changes to ‘about:config’ to persist after creating an I2P-Whonix workstation disposable template. I have read and re-read the Whonix documentation and the previous forum discussions on this topic. The exact point of failure is after I turn the AppVM into the disp template using the commands “qvm-prefs exampleappvmname template_for_dispvms True” and “qvm-features exampleappvmname appmenus-dispvm 1”.</p>
<p>The TLDR rundown of the steps I take are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Clone the whonix-ws-16 template</li>
<li>Install and configure I2P-Java according to docs</li>
<li>Close template and build an AppVM based on it <span class="bbcode-b">(without a NetVM attached)</span>
</li>
<li>Start Tor Browser in the freshly built AppVM and configure the settings I need</li>
<li>Close the AppVM and clone it, giving it some title with “dvm” tacked on</li>
<li>Run those 2 commands previously stated in Dom0</li>
<li>Start a disposable VM from the Applications Menu and manually add sys-whonix as the NetVM in the Qubes Manager</li>
</ul>
<p>During my troubleshooting of this issue, I have found that the customization I do to Tor Browser persists in the actual disposable VM template, but <span class="bbcode-b">not</span> in the dispvm’s that are made out of the template. And changes I make to another browser, like Firefox for example, do persist in each new dispvm, like intended.</p>
<p>I think I am narrowing down the issue being related to ‘~.tb’ not being generated until after Tor Browser is started, which is a problem when each dispvm is brand new and Tor Browser has not had the chance to start yet. My next guess in solving this issue is to customize the settings I need in the proper config files located somewhere in ‘/var’ in the original I2P-Whonix template, before I create the AppVMs based on it… Does that sound right? Some tips on how to properly edit those config files would be greatly appreciated, since I <span class="bbcode-i">think</span> the ‘~.tb’ directory is generated from the cache files in ‘/var’.</p>
<p>Am I on the right track or completely off base? Any and all help / feedback is welcome. I just want to start my I2P-Whonix dispvms without having to configure every setting every time in Tor Browser!!</p>
<p>Thank you.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976/1</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 22:02:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15976-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/sigh-another-post-about-customizing-tor-browser-in-a-qubes-whonix-template/15976.rss">Sigh..another post about customizing Tor Browser in a Qubes-Whonix template</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
