<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172</link>
    <description>So, I&#39;m using W-Workstation 8 in VirtualBox and something weird happened recently.

Workstation has crashed once or twice on me while I have been doing normal browsing things.  In VirtualBox after Workstation crashes the status changes to &quot;Aborted&quot;

The last time it happened I decided I&#39;d take a look at the log and see what was up.  What I found was a little weird and I was wondering if anyone has seen anything similar.  

I don&#39;t have the exact log at the moment, and I will return next time / if it crashes again.. but regardless - this was a little creepy.

One of the last errors before the system went down read something like

&quot; [attempted screen capture failed] blabhlabhalh {123} blahbalh &quot;
I am no programmer by any stretch and pardon my poor representation of the error log.  Like I said, if it happens again I will try to get the exact error here.  Regardless, why whonix is trying to capture my screen at the same time of this hiccup confuses me a bit.  I guess the refreshing part of this is that the &#39;screen capture was FAILED&#39;

Is anyone familiar with this.  Are the NASA astronauts trying to see what I&#39;m up to here on my whonix box?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:40:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If NSA was involved, I would assume that you wouldn’t notice.</p>
<p>This sounds like a bug in VirtualBox. (Because VMs such as Whonix should not be able to cause VirtualBox status aborted and if they were, it would be a bug in VirtualBox. [Nonetheless we should add a workaround if that is possible.] Also damaged hardware could cause this. Could you try running memtest please?</p>
<p>Perhaps you accidentally pressed some key combination which VirtualBox uses to create a screenshot and then some bug in VirtualBox’s screenshot function causes this bug?</p>
<p>Are you wiling to tell us, what host operating system (and version) and what VirtualBox version you are using?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172/3</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 00:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-172-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172.rss">Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixguy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Okay going to hack out a little of what is on the same line</p>
<p>aRC=VBOX_E_IPRT_ERROR “NUMBERS 23948723987” aComponent={Display} aText={Could not take a screenshot (VERR_NOT_SUPPORTED)}, preserve=false</p>
<p>I might be climbing out on a limb here… but why would whonix try to take a screen shot before it crashes?  Also, if this isn’t a ‘literal’ screen shot error, I apologize.  Just thought it was a little odd!</p>
<p>Several lines down there is some other fishy and suspect things that I’m seeing now that I’m taking a second look.<br>
Guest Log : BIOS Boots from floppy and CDROM failed.</p>
<p>Also something about Audio: set_record_source  (not implemented)</p>
<p>Then the requests to power down the machine… starts with “Running” to “Suspending” to “suspended” to “powering_off”</p>
<p>IDK.</p>
<p>Someone tell me I’m crazy.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 20:05:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-172-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172.rss">Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[whonixguy]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>So, I’m using W-Workstation 8 in VirtualBox and something weird happened recently.</p>
<p>Workstation has crashed once or twice on me while I have been doing normal browsing things.  In VirtualBox after Workstation crashes the status changes to “Aborted”</p>
<p>The last time it happened I decided I’d take a look at the log and see what was up.  What I found was a little weird and I was wondering if anyone has seen anything similar.</p>
<p>I don’t have the exact log at the moment, and I will return next time / if it crashes again… but regardless - this was a little creepy.</p>
<p>One of the last errors before the system went down read something like</p>
<p>" [attempted screen capture failed] blabhlabhalh {123} blahbalh "<br>
I am no programmer by any stretch and pardon my poor representation of the error log.  Like I said, if it happens again I will try to get the exact error here.  Regardless, why whonix is trying to capture my screen at the same time of this hiccup confuses me a bit.  I guess the refreshing part of this is that the ‘screen capture was FAILED’</p>
<p>Is anyone familiar with this.  Are the NASA astronauts trying to see what I’m up to here on my whonix box?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 16:51:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-172-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-workstation-8-crash-attempted-screen-shot-failed-in-error-log/172.rss">Whonix-Workstation 8 Crash - Attempted Screen Shot Failed In Error Log?!</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
