<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>(landing) page urls</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125</link>
    <description>I like to create a few ( location / language /[url=https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en]user[/url] ) specific landing pages. A word by word translation is ineffective for example for the main page and for the donation page. Such as the US version of Whonix&#39;s homepage would talk about given rights in constitution. The German version would talk about [url=https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grundrecht_auf_Gew%C3%A4hrleistung_der_Vertraulichkeit_und_Integrit%C3%A4t_informationstechnischer_Systeme]IT Grundrecht[/url]  (constitutional guarantee of confidentiality and integrity of IT systems). Or the German version of the donation page would advertise services other than paypal, which are better than paypal but only available inside Germany.

Lately, I&#39;ve been thinking if https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page is a good url at all. I guess &quot;wiki&quot; is a positive mental association and can be kept. What about &quot;Main_Page&quot;?

For the German version of the main page, I&#39;ve been thinking to use either
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/de
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/de
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/Deutsch
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/Ger
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/US
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/US
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/homepage/US
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/Journalists ([url=https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist]similar content[/url])
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/journalists ([url=https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist]similar content[/url])
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/US/journalists ([url=https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist]similar content[/url])
- https://www.whonix.org/wiki/DE/journalists ([url=https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist]similar content[/url])

(The url https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de is already taken by our translation extension. [Word for word translations work well for other pages such as the download page. That extension is useful there.])

Any ideas on this how this urls should be named?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 13:04:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Website</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I guess fortasse doesn’t mind about url naming schema.</p>
<p>But from existing discussions I can tell, that <a href="http://subdomain.domain.org">subdomain.domain.org</a> is generally more difficult to implement (needs DNS changes) than <a href="http://domain.org/something">domain.org/something</a>. <a href="http://subdomain.domain.org">subdomain.domain.org</a> would also clash with our hidden service, because hidden services don’t support subdomains.</p>
<p>It would be up to these landing pages to ensure that their internal links to other pages are functional. I don’t see a problem here. I had these landing pages only in mind as additions for cases were word by word translations doesn’t work well, not as replacement for the translate extension.</p>
<p>For most pages the translate extension should work fine as soon as figured out how to use it. And the translate extension seems like the only maintainable way to keep the more technical explanations up to date once the English version has been changed.</p>
<p>I create a stub for the German homepage:<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Deutsch/Homepage" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Deutsch/Homepage</a><br>
The url name can still be changed. Essentially, that’s all. I do not plan on creating <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Deutsch/Dokumentation">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Deutsch/Dokumentation</a>. That would be a pain to manually maintain as soon as content of <a href="http://whonix.org/wiki/Documentation">whonix.org/wiki/Documentation</a> changes. When <a href="http://whonix.org/wiki/Documentation">whonix.org/wiki/Documentation</a> gets translated to German, I will add a link to <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Deutsch/Homepage">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Deutsch/Homepage</a>. I don’t plan on having that many unique landing pages. Only were word by word translations are too lame.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/9">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/9</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 13:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-9</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[JasonJAyalaP]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I like it. It’s best to customize your message to your audience. I also like trying an alternative to the paragraph-for-paragraph translator module we still haven’t mastered.</p>
<p>But it will add issues…</p>
<p>Aesthetically, I like <a href="http://website.com/language/page;">website.com/language/page;</a> but <a href="http://lang.website.com/">lang.website.com/</a> is fine too. It could be one is easier to implement than the other.</p>
<p><a href="http://website.com/language">website.com/language</a> should take you to <a href="http://website.com/language/index">website.com/language/index</a> (or main or whatever)</p>
<p><a href="http://website.com">website.com</a> takes you to Autodetect/Main</p>
<p><a href="http://website.com/language/page">website.com/language/page</a> for a page that doesn’t have that language…? Show English/page</p>
<p>But how to do links work? I’m try to avoid too much work for fortasse and complexity in the wiki. I’m sure there are other issues we’ll run into it. We need fortasse’s opinion.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/8">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/8</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 21:50:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-8</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>For donation just add a German type payment with a comment "Germany" only.</blockquote>
That would add more text for both, international and German readers. For such a page, as for many pages, it is important to be as concise as possibly for best efficiency.
<blockquote>Mixing philosophy and politics with Whonix is not needed IMO, especially since laws work differently in theory then  in practice.</blockquote>
I feel it urgent to spread the good news and to end the ignorance, that anonymity isn't some kind level 5 (higher number, lower level) hierarchic law and also not a loophole where no law against has been issued yet, but already recognized as a most fundamental right.
<p>The struggle for keeping anonymity tools legal in western countries is ongoing. More and more countries ban anonymity tools. Whonix isn’t neutral, it already is a political statement “pro privacy, you have the right”. Since I won’t have time to build up another initiative to support anonymity staying legal, I do what I can, and advertise it in places I am around. When anonymity tools get banned, I don’t want to have to tell myself, that it was me who did nothing.</p>
<blockquote>No auto recognition, no guessing.</blockquote>
Well, that would be step two. Isn't the scope of this topic, which is about (landing) page urls. When these are implemented, we can start to think about auto recognition. The server wouldn't have to ask, the browser shuts out this information to the world anyway with every request and without whonix.org storing that information, of course. But this is a bit theoretic for now. I don't know if we have someone capable to implement it and I don't know if enough browsers are still sending this information. And this discussion is independent from the outcome of this thread above.
<blockquote>Free choice.</blockquote>
Choices won't be limited. And internal in/out from/to such pages will be clearly available.
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/7">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/7</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 13:08:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-7</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“Patrick, post:5, topic:125”][quote author=Occq link=topic=116.msg882#msg882 date=1394131789]<br>
I dislike the idea of any kind website personalization based on location.[/quote]<br>
Why?[/quote]<br>
Because my first though is tracking. I don’t like websites making personalization decisions for me. That choice should be mine only.</p>
<blockquote>[quote author=Occq link=topic=116.msg882#msg882 date=1394131789]What are the benefits?[/quote]
Advantages are written in the original post:
<p>“A word by word translation is ineffective for example for the main page and for the donation page. Such as the US version of Whonix’s homepage would talk about given rights in constitution. The German version would talk about IT Grundrecht  (constitutional guarantee of confidentiality and integrity of IT systems). Or the German version of the donation page would advertise services other than paypal, which are better than paypal but only available inside Germany.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I still don’t see the benefits. For donation just add a German type payment with a comment “Germany” only. Mixing philosophy and politics with Whonix is not needed IMO, especially since laws work differently in theory then  in practice.</p>
<blockquote>[quote author=Occq link=topic=116.msg882#msg882 date=1394131789]website privacy concern problems can't be associated to security projects like Whonix.[/quote]
Sure. I don't see how page privacy would suffer by this.
<p>Well, maybe you mean this. When you are on <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page</a> it’s the English version by default. Now, when one clicks for example on <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de</a> or <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/fr" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/fr</a> (wiki translate extension), our webhost could guess that someone would rather read the German/French version of that page. Weighting to risk, i.e. never reading something in your native language and therefore misunderstanding something vs. not letting the server know that someone is rather interested in the native language is a choice everyone has to make. While I still was anonymous, I most times used the latter option and if not, I used new identity quickly afterwards. Anyhow, as long as the link has a fair name, i.e. includes /de /German or something like that in its name, I don’t see how it can be any worse than with wiki translate extension.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Offer DE/FR options but let the user choose if he wants it. No auto recognition, no guessing. Free choice.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/6">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/6</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 10:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-6</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="4" data-topic="125">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/o/49beb7/40.png" class="avatar"> Occq:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I dislike the idea of any kind website personalization based on location.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Why?</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="4" data-topic="125">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/o/49beb7/40.png" class="avatar"> Occq:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>What are the benefits?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Advantages are written in the original post:</p>
<p>“A word by word translation is ineffective for example for the main page and for the donation page. Such as the US version of Whonix’s homepage would talk about given rights in constitution. The German version would talk about IT Grundrecht  (constitutional guarantee of confidentiality and integrity of IT systems). Or the German version of the donation page would advertise services other than paypal, which are better than paypal but only available inside Germany.”</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="4" data-topic="125">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/o/49beb7/40.png" class="avatar"> Occq:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>website privacy concern problems can’t be associated to security projects like Whonix.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Sure. I don’t see how page privacy would suffer by this.</p>
<p>Well, maybe you mean this. When you are on <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page</a> it’s the English version by default. Now, when one clicks for example on <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de</a> or <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/fr">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/fr</a> (wiki translate extension), our webhost could guess that someone would rather read the German/French version of that page. Weighting to risk, i.e. never reading something in your native language and therefore misunderstanding something vs. not letting the server know that someone is rather interested in the native language is a choice everyone has to make. While I still was anonymous, I most times used the latter option and if not, I used new identity quickly afterwards. Anyhow, as long as the link has a fair name, i.e. includes /de /German or something like that in its name, I don’t see how it can be any worse than with wiki translate extension.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/5">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/5</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 02:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-5</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I dislike the idea of any kind website personalization based on location.</p>
<p>What are the benefits?</p>
<p>I don’t see the gains and website privacy concern problems can’t be associated to security projects like Whonix.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/4">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/4</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 18:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-4</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>No worries about privacy here. Geolocation based IP won’t be our way. I guess a big share of our users are Tor users, so using IP to detect the location would be futile. Since we’re using apache-mod-removeip, our web apps don’t get to see IP addresses anyway, so can’t be used for geolocation.</p>
<p>What could be done is using what the browser tells us, if a regular browser tells us the user is US/DE user, they can be redirected to the respective landing pages. Should be legitimate and there shouldn’t be privacy concerns here. But that would only be a small later improvement. Didn’t have this ind mind for now.</p>
<p>Those landing pages also wouldn’t necessarily need to be advertised on the main page.</p>
<p>It would be sufficient if they were available on search engines for the audience they’re targeting or if local communities (ex: localized linux blogs/forums) would be aware of these localized landing page and prefer that link over others.</p>
<p>I need to ask fortasse how difficult it would be to implement (de/us).whonix.org. <a href="http://us.whonix.org">us.whonix.org</a> could most likely just be a redirection to <a href="http://whonix.org/wiki/landing/us">whonix.org/wiki/landing/us</a> so we still need to figure out what domain naming schema should be used.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/3">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/3</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 18:09:36 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-3</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Some thoughts:</p>
<p>I think we do not want to use geolocation/tracking, i.e. re-directing the user automatically upon browser fingerprint, geoIP, you name it? I at least would dislike that. Wouldn’t make to much sense anyways as our users use Tor (hopefully).</p>
<p>Now, what about following the approach Wikipedia is implementing?<br>
A landing page at <a href="https://www.wikipedia.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.wikipedia.org/</a> - we could also link forums, blog (i.e english-only resources) there? - maybe some custom coded static html at <a href="https://www.whonix.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/</a> ?</p>
<p>Then<br>
<a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Hauptseite" rel="nofollow noopener">https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Hauptseite</a> &gt; <a href="https://de.whonix.org/wiki/Hauptseite" rel="nofollow noopener">https://de.whonix.org/wiki/Hauptseite</a><br>
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page" rel="nofollow noopener">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page</a> &gt; <a href="https://en.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page" rel="nofollow noopener">https://en.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page</a></p>
<p>for the language-specific wikis?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/2">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/2</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 17:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-2</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>(landing) page urls</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I like to create a few ( location / language /<a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en" data-bbcode="true">user</a> ) specific landing pages. A word by word translation is ineffective for example for the main page and for the donation page. Such as the US version of Whonix’s homepage would talk about given rights in constitution. The German version would talk about <a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grundrecht_auf_Gew%C3%A4hrleistung_der_Vertraulichkeit_und_Integrit%C3%A4t_informationstechnischer_Systeme" data-bbcode="true">IT Grundrecht</a>  (constitutional guarantee of confidentiality and integrity of IT systems). Or the German version of the donation page would advertise services other than paypal, which are better than paypal but only available inside Germany.</p>
<p>Lately, I’ve been thinking if <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page</a> is a good url at all. I guess “wiki” is a positive mental association and can be kept. What about “Main_Page”?</p>
<p>For the German version of the main page, I’ve been thinking to use either</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/de">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/de</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/de">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/de</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/Deutsch">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/Deutsch</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/Ger">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/Ger</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/US">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/US</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/US">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/US</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/homepage/US">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/homepage/US</a></li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/Journalists">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/Journalists</a> (<a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist" data-bbcode="true">similar content</a>)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/journalists">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/landing/journalists</a> (<a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist" data-bbcode="true">similar content</a>)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/US/journalists">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/US/journalists</a> (<a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist" data-bbcode="true">similar content</a>)</li>
<li>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/DE/journalists">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/DE/journalists</a> (<a href="https://www.torproject.org/about/torusers.html.en#journalist" data-bbcode="true">similar content</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>(The url <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Main_Page/de</a> is already taken by our translation extension. [Word for word translations work well for other pages such as the download page. That extension is useful there.])</p>
<p>Any ideas on this how this urls should be named?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125/1</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 15:14:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-125-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/landing-page-urls/125.rss">(landing) page urls</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
