<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Disabling default sys-net traffic necessary when moving networks?</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/disabling-default-sys-net-traffic-necessary-when-moving-networks/15896</link>
    <description>I am trying to understand the Fingerprint wiki. There is a recommendation to prevent non-Tor connections when moving between networks. I don&#39;t understand what this achieves? I understand that any non-Tor connections that uniquely  identify somebody (such as visiting obscurewebsite dot com or facebook dot com) should be prevented, but the recommendation seems to mean that we should disable all clearnet traffic. I am a Qubes user so this would mean even default sys-net traffic. If you were to do this then an ISP adversary would not be able to tell what OS you are using but only creating Tor traffic is a fingerprint equally as identifiable as the fingerprint of the OS default clearnet traffic. 

I think the best you can do when moving networks is remove your state file but your OS will always be visible. 

The only other reason I can think of for this recommendation is to prevent the attack where an adversary is able to link Tor and non-Tor traffic but this isn&#39;t something specific to moving networks. 

I can not link but it is /wiki/Fingerprint</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 05:03:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Qubes-Whonix</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/disabling-default-sys-net-traffic-necessary-when-moving-networks/15896.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Disabling default sys-net traffic necessary when moving networks?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[movingnetworks]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I am trying to understand the Fingerprint wiki. There is a recommendation to prevent non-Tor connections when moving between networks. I don’t understand what this achieves? I understand that any non-Tor connections that uniquely  identify somebody (such as visiting obscurewebsite dot com or facebook dot com) should be prevented, but the recommendation seems to mean that we should disable all clearnet traffic. I am a Qubes user so this would mean even default sys-net traffic. If you were to do this then an ISP adversary would not be able to tell what OS you are using but only creating Tor traffic is a fingerprint equally as identifiable as the fingerprint of the OS default clearnet traffic.</p>
<p>I think the best you can do when moving networks is remove your state file but your OS will always be visible.</p>
<p>The only other reason I can think of for this recommendation is to prevent the attack where an adversary is able to link Tor and non-Tor traffic but this isn’t something specific to moving networks.</p>
<p>I can not link but it is /wiki/Fingerprint</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/disabling-default-sys-net-traffic-necessary-when-moving-networks/15896/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/disabling-default-sys-net-traffic-necessary-when-moving-networks/15896/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 05:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-15896-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/disabling-default-sys-net-traffic-necessary-when-moving-networks/15896.rss">Disabling default sys-net traffic necessary when moving networks?</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
