<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67</link>
    <description>[html]&lt;h1&gt;Download&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; http://sourceforge.net/projects/whonixdevelopermetafiles/files/whonix-7.7.8.6/Whonix-Gateway-7.7.8.6.ova/download&quot;&gt;Whonix-Gateway for VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot; http://sourceforge.net/projects/whonixdevelopermetafiles/files/whonix-7.7.8.6/Whonix-Gateway-7.7.8.6.ova.asc/download&quot;&gt;Whonix-Gateway for VirtualBox signature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/whonixdevelopermetafiles/files/whonix-7.7.8.6/Whonix-Workstation-7.7.8.6.ova/download&quot;&gt;Whonix-Workstation for VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/whonixdevelopermetafiles/files/whonix-7.7.8.6/Whonix-Workstation-7.7.8.6.ova.asc/download&quot;&gt;Whonix-Workstation signature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;KVM / Qemu&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entirely untested! This is only useful if you have a developers mindset!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time .qcow2 images are available (as .tar.gz, qcow2 image and signature must be unpacked):

&lt;a href=&quot; http://sourceforge.net/projects/whonixdevelopermetafiles/files/whonix-7.7.8.6/&quot;&gt; http://sourceforge.net/projects/whonixdevelopermetafiles/files/whonix-7.7.8.6/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have unfinished(!) instructions for KVM:

&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.whonix.org/wiki/KVM&quot;&gt; https://www.whonix.org/wiki/KVM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still a few blockers before using Whonix with KVM can be

considered sane:

&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/KVM&quot;&gt; https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/KVM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please help out solving them. Whonix also needs a maintainer to

support using Whonix with KVM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;If you want to upgrade existing Whonix version&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, upgrading from existing Whonix version (0.5.6, 7, etc.) to

7.7.8.0 (and 8 when it’s released) will not be possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;If you want to build images from source code&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/BuildDocumentation_8&quot;&gt;https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/BuildDocumentation_8&lt;/a&gt; and use git

tag 7.7.8.7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(7.7.8.7 only contains a minor build script fix. Is otherwise same as 7.7.8.6.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Physical Isolation users&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use Debian stable instead of testing, use git tag 7.7.8.7 and see

&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Physical_Isolation&quot;&gt;https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Physical_Isolation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Changelog between Whonix 7 and Whonix 7.7.8.6 (testers-only version)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* Whonix is now based on Debian stable instead of Debian testing.

* In new installations, automatic updates of Whonix’s debian packages

are disabled by default. During first start, users can decide if they

want to enable Whonix’s APT repository or want to leave it disabled.

* Fixed Whonix’s Tor Browser download and start script for TBB 3.5.

* Fixed physical isolation build script.

* Verifiable Builds. Whonix now has a feature which allows the community

to check that Whonix .ova releases are verifiably created from project’s

own source code. Also made ade Whonix’s APT repository verifiable (even

deterministic!). Please see

https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Verifiable_Builds for details.

* Made Whonix build script configurable (can now build terminal-only

Whonix-Gateway’s and/or Whonix-Workstations; 64 bit builds and more)

* Improved Whonix News’s security. All Whonix News Files are now inside

one tarball, which is signed. This stops leaking how many users are

using a particular version.

* whonixcheck’s Whonix News download now checks if Whonix News are still

valid (currently up to 4 weeks) and therefore detects indefinite freeze

and replay attacks.

* whonix_repository tool now has a graphical user interface; added more

command line switches.

* Set default locale to en_US.UTF-8.

* Simplified custom user installation of TorChat, thanks to dummytor.

(Protecting from Tor over Tor.)

* Removed apper and synaptic from default installation, because they are

too confusing / have too many bugs, do not always work in all cases for

all users, #104, can still be manually installed if wanted, see also https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/Automatic_Updates

* whonixcheck: more configuration options, any function can now be

disabled, this is useful for users who wish to disable control port

filter proxy, they can disable the check_tor_bootstrap function

* whonixcheck: added protection against possibly malicious strings from

check.torproject.org (in case of a bug, compromise of check.tpo server

or CA compromise), IP strings are now max 50 characters long. User will

be warned in case the limit is exceeded.

* Whonix-Workstation: no longer installing Tor Browser by default, this

simplified implementing verifiable builds (#113), installing iceweasel

by default, which can be used to download Tor Browser, added local

iceweasel browser homepage saying that iceweasel should not be used for

anything other than downloading Tor Browser, unless one knows what one

is doing.

* Removed galternatives from whonix-workstation-default-applications

because galternatives has been (temporarily) removed from Debian testing

* Building Whonix from frozen repository, from snapshot.debian.org to

make the build script more resistant from upstream changes and also to

make Whonix verifiable.

* The Whonix Team can now use separate keys for Whonix’s APT Repository

and Whonix News.

* Added technical documentation about keys in Whonix

whonix_shared/usr/share/whonix/keys/readme.

* new man page: man/whonix_shared/sdwdate.8.ronn

* Deactivated Maximizing Windows by dragging them to the top of the

screen to prevent users from accidentally maximizing their browser

window when they are using resolutions higher than 1024×768. See

https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Higher_Screen_Resolution ;

https://github.com/Whonix/Whonix/issues/110 and

https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/ticket/7255 for more

information. #108

* added udisks to whonix-shared-packages-recommended for mounting

removable drives

* KDE settings changes, set to oxygen as suggested by scarp in

“[Whonix-devel] Plastique kwin style &amp; Widget Style”

* whonixcheck: increased timeout for the tor bootstrap.py utility from 5

to 10 seconds to make it compatible with slow systems as per bug reporthttps://www.whonix.org/wiki/Special:AWCforum/st/id248/whonixcheck%3A_tor_bootstrap_statu….html

* whonixcheck: Whonix News File is now deterministic

* whonixcheck: Whonix News added timeout for gpg and tar

* added secure-delete, because it contains sfill, which can be used to

zero out free space, which is required for disk shrinking

* Deactivated running update-command-not-found during build, since not

deterministic (verifiable). Manually running is of course still possible.

* whonix_shared/etc/apt/sources.list.d/torproject.list: removed the “deb

http://deb.torproject.org/torproject.org tor-0.2.4.x-jessie main”

repository, since that repository has been removed by The Tor Project

(Tor is now in their Debian testing repository, which is already added)

* fixed a bug reported by scarp,

whonix_shared/usr/share/whonix/postinst.d/70_disable_kdm_autostart: was

not disabling other display managers other than kdm. Now using the more

generic

/usr/lib/whonix/display-manager-dpkg-post-invoke.

* msgcollector: fix race condition not always closing progress bar when

it reached 100%

* Whonix-Gateway: Workaround for http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=732578 https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Download#Connection_Issues_-_Tor_stops_working_after_an_Upgrade_and_needs_a_Workaround  Set in /etc/default/tor:

USE_AA_EXEC=”no” Can be commented out when that bug gets fixed.

* optionally (opt-in) building qcow2 images, first rudimentary

implementation, build target (VirtualBox or qcow2 or both) should

probably be configurable in whonix_build script (#122)

* Whonix News Blog Download / Whonix News: Whonix News Blogs (Whonix

Feature Blog and Whonix Important Blog) are now deployed over the same

mechanism as Whonix News.

* Whonix-Workstation: better implementation of dummytor using

config-package-dev (might break compatibility with Whonix 7)

* removed adrelanos’ old key; removed

whonix_shared/usr/share/whonix/postinst.d/70_legacy (breaks

compatiblity with Whonix 7)

* Re-implemented uwt and dummytor using config-package-dev instead of

custom dpkg-diversions. Breaks compatibly with Whonix 7.

* Removed rawdog and pandoc since no longer required.

* moved misc scripts (Scripts for managing Whonix’s offical repository

and Whonix News; debug scripts; developer documentation and deprecated

code) to https://github.com/Whonix/whonix-developer-meta-files

* whonixcheck: do not show output of gpg for Whonix News verification

* whonixcheck: do not start whonixcheck, if whonixsetup hasn’t finished yet

* whonixcheck: new –verbose / –debug options

* whonixcheck: Check that /proc/sys/net/ipv4/ip_forward and

/proc/sys/net/ipv6/ip_forward aren’t set to 1 to prevent users from

shooting their own feet.

* whonixsetup: start whonixcheck at the end of whonixsetup on

Whonix-Workstation

* torbrowser: hide output of gpg import; ask “Start Tor Browser yes/no”

after upgrading”

* torbrowser: added timeout to gpg to prevent endless data attacks

* torbrowser/whonixcheck: alternative method detecting locally installed

Tor Browser version. When $tbb_folder/Docs/version does not exist, i.e.

when the user manually downloaded Tor Browser, try to detect version

number from ~/tor-browser_en-US/Docs/sources/versions.; comment

* desktop: higher resolution icons for whonix_repository, whonixcheck,

contribute and donate, whonix gateway firewall, tb recommend, important

blog and torbrowser

* qcow2 images: added metadata preallocation

* qcow2 images: added “-o cluster_size=2M” to “qemu-img” for better performance

* build script: fix “sudo: unable to resolve host debian”

* build script: added –no-options to gpg to avoid conflict with user’s

gpg config files

* build script: added benchmarking

* build script: whonix_build_both: support extra parameter

* build script: got rid of grml_config by using grml-debootstrap’s new

environment variables feature

* build script: skip backup-img-after-grml-debootstrap and

backup-img-after-meta-package-install build steps by default, can be

re-enabled by builder

* build script: allow running build-steps.d/2400_convert-img-to-qcow2 without root

* verifiable builds: new build step build-steps.d/2350_cleanup; Get rid

of /dev folder inside the vm image. This is only required for verifiable

builds. Otherwise this could be skipped. For example,Â Â Â Â  “sudo

sha512sum /dev/xconsole” or “sudo sha512sum /dev/initctl” would run

forever. The /dev folder gets recreated by the kernel upon first boot.

* Improved messages.

* Lots of smaller fixes.

* Code refactoring.

* For more details, see the git log.&lt;/p&gt;
[/html]</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 22:52:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I don’t find such issues funny. I am not sure, I would have come to the idea, what the actual cause is.</p>
<p>Thanks for reporting. I created a troubleshooting chapter on the physical isolation page.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Physical_Isolation#Troubleshooting" target="_blank" title="05:06PM - 01 May 2020">Whonix – 1 May 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:640/472;"><img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/9/98/Digital-art-191226640.jpg" class="thumbnail" width="640" height="472"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Physical_Isolation#Troubleshooting" target="_blank">Build Documentation: Physical Isolation</a></h3>

<p>Security by Isolation. Using Whonix ™ with Physical Isolation on Bare Metal for Better Security.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Those hints may help someone save some time since you shared these possibly sources of errors with us.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/94">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/94</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 22:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-94</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>rofl … I promise: if you considered my previous post funny, now comes comedy! So, without any further ado … Here it comes (I’m telling the story in a third person perspective as I consider it funnier that way):</p>
<p>OK, so, the situation is: Cerberus recognized (after hours) that he/she either needs a crossover cable or a switch, swap the card within one of the rigs or find a way to configure the kernel module(s). Status quo, see above.</p>
<p>Ok, fine. 1st decision? We’re pros right? -&gt; so, kernel module. What a bad idea! Some time later into the process: %RfgHN/$Ws network cards. LOL.</p>
<p>2nd decision? A switch is lame right? -&gt; so, swapping the card in the workstation host. Again, bad idea!</p>
<p>1st try: Cerberus finds an old network card that he/she knows supports Auto-MDIX (let me mention here that one card is usually enough here to auto-sense). Now, Cerberus disassembles the workstation host, swaps cards, put it all together again, switch on -&gt; hardware dead! LOL.</p>
<p>2nd try: Searching for cards is on the agenda, again. Cerberus finds another card, searches the web for Auto-MDIX support -&gt; positive! Nice! disassembling the workstation host for a second time, swapping cards, switching on -&gt; link detected. Yeah! Problem solved? Unfortunately NO as the gateway side couldn’t care less -&gt; no link. WTF? I still don’t know how this can happen but obviously the DFS§$wghr5 cards may work with a card attached that supports Auto-MDIX (see test-laptop) but not with another one (that also is supposed to support it and shows “link up”). Great!</p>
<p>Now? 3rd decision? Switch (btw, the most easiest - Cerberus does not have a crossover cable - but least appreciated solution here). Worked on first try! Could have been easy.</p>
<p>Hope you have a good laugh! <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/93">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/93</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 01:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-93</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><span class="mention">@adrelanos</span><br>
lol, you know what is going on here with the network connection? It’s Murphy’s law <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
<p>that is to say, the gateway + the workstation host both happen to have network cards that do not support Auto-MDIX (automatic medium-dependent interface crossover). I need a crossover cable to connect them. bummer! Took me hours to figure that out.</p>
<p>connected gateway to workstation host with 3 distinct cables: link not ready<br>
connected test-laptop to gateway: link up<br>
connected test-laptop to workstation host: link up</p>
<p>interesting indeed <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> then the proverbial lightbulb appeared above my head! At least that is my conclusion so far. now, I’m going to research if I can control this with the kernel module somehow, otherwise use a switch, or insert another network card supporting Auto-MDIX into one of the two rigs.</p>
<p>I thought I share it with you to provide a good laugh to you!</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/92">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/92</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-92</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Found a solution for the latter (<a href="https://github.com/Whonix/Whonix/commit/d6cf74e843e98f0b6760a4c678a6d1f486993c92">https://github.com/Whonix/Whonix/commit/d6cf74e843e98f0b6760a4c678a6d1f486993c92</a>).</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/91">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/91</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-91</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>There are other issues with the build environment.</p>
<p>[ul][li]Building in LXDE fails. Probably some device auto mounter gets in the way.[/li]<br>
[li]Likewise building in GNOME fails. Probably some device auto mounter gets in the way. We had a workaround in <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/BuildDocumentation_8">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Dev/BuildDocumentation_8</a> using “gsettings set org.gnome.desktop.media-handling automount-open false” but it doesn’t seem to work in wheezy (worked in jessie).[/li]<br>
[li]When building VM images when one hasn’t chosen en-US while installing, the following warning will be shown by apt-get:[/li][/ul]</p>
<p><code>perl: warning: Setting locale failed.
perl: warning: Please check that your locale settings:
        LANGUAGE = "",
        LC_ALL = (unset),
        LANG = "en_GB.UTF-8"
    are supported and installed on your system.
perl: warning: Falling back to the standard locale ("C").</code></p>
<p>And this also leads to debsums output in /usr/share/whonix/chroot-scripts-pre.d/20_sanity_checks where none is expected, breaking the build.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/90">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/90</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 23:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-90</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I don’t know if you’re following out other thread as well. Just FYI, much better error handling has been added:<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/forum/index.php/topic,52.msg505.html#msg505" class="onebox" target="_blank">https://www.whonix.org/forum/index.php/topic,52.msg505.html#msg505</a></p>
<p>The old script behavior was unbearable indeed.</p>
<blockquote>To make clear: I was not about criticizing Whonix,</blockquote>
Wasn't perceived as criticism. Not in any negative sense.
<blockquote>I tried to ping in both directions &gt; no connectivity.</blockquote>
About ping, I just updated this FAQ entry a bit:
https://www.whonix.org/wiki/FAQ#Why_can.27t_I_ping_the_Whonix-Gateway.3F
<p>Ping workstation host -&gt; gateway won’t work as long as the firewall is active. The other way around gateway ping -&gt; workstation however should work (quick test in a VM, though).</p>
<blockquote>I configured the workstation host, i.e. the Debian install with
...
and I'm trying to enable Debian repos during installation</blockquote>
I don't know. I never made friends with network settings during installation. There could even be bugs in the installer. What you could try is finishing without Debian repos during installation and see if you can manually get networking working at all. To exclude the possibility, that something is wrong with the gateway. (Or for a quick test boot a Live CD for that purpose and see if the gateway will proxy traffic for you.)
<p><code>address 192.168.0.11
netmask 255.255.255.0
gateway 192.168.0.10</code></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/89">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/89</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 22:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-89</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>Sure. Will disable it for Whonix 8 + 1 for physical isolation users. Do you wish to get credit in git commit logs?</blockquote>
Great, thanks. Getting credits isn't required here. I'm just reporting very minor things as a part of testing. Appreciate the offer though.
<blockquote>I can imagine that this is confusing. It must also look quite dilettantish, that your network is non-functional after installing. What we could add to physical isolation instructions in meanwhile "cp /etc/network/interfaces.whonix-orig /etc/network/interfaces" to get your old configuration back. The other option, editing /etc/network/interfaces.whonix before building and committing it to git seems even more awkward.</blockquote>
Actually I very much appreciate your efforts to automate this (as I appreciate Whonix overall). Not amateurish at all from my perspective. Escaping special configurations would certainly be the very best thing (but needs to be scripted. If I'm completely setup, I'm going to look at it again. Maybe I can contribute something here) with the current approach quite close to perfect. Disabling the automatic replacement of /etc/network/interfaces wouldn't be superior here. I'm completely on the same page here. Let's leave it as is - just mentioning it. Maybe you haven't noticed before. If someone, like me, needs to introduce "scary", i.e. non-std. things like "wpa-conf" he/she needs to bite the bullet - anyways a very minor issue that's easily fixed.
<blockquote>What do you think about my method of splitting Whonix into several packages?</blockquote>
Like that! To make clear: I was not about criticizing Whonix, just the testing process we have passed during the weekend. While my opinion isn't very much relevant here, you're doing a _great_ job with Whonix from my perspective.
---
Now, I'm sorry to bother again ;) I'm currently trying to install the Workstation host through the new gateway and I'm having issues here. This is most likely a silly mistake I make, but here it goes: I configured the workstation host, i.e. the Debian install with
<blockquote>IP/netmask: 192.168.0.11/24
Gateway/DNS: 192.168.0.10</blockquote>
and I'm trying to enable Debian repos during installation. Problem is: it seems to lack connectivity through the gateway, i.e. the host/debian install isn't able to reach the net through the gateway. May you please briefly help me troubleshooting here? Is the IP/netmask, Gateway/DNS configuration of the host that's installing as it's supposed to be? I checked for typos here, nothing found and gateway is at 192.168.0.10/24. Debian install is complaining about not being able to connect to the net, while gateway tells me "timesync fine, connected to Tor". I tried to ping in both directions &gt; no connectivity. Now, it's either me failing (stupid mistake), a faulty cable or something else. Any feedback? Thanks!
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/88">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/88</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 18:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-88</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“Cerberus, post:85, topic:67”][quote]For VM builds, no swapfile is automatically created. Do you propose shipping by default without a swapfile?<br>
It would easy to disable swapfile creation for physical isolation users.[/quote]<br>
Your decision after all. I would say disabling it would be good (although it doesn’t harm the machine). When building for physical isolation, the host/target is prepared including swapfile and/or -partition prior building. Thus I see no need to auto-create it. Not a big deal though - just reporting.[/quote]<br>
Sure. Will disable it for Whonix 8 + 1 for physical isolation users. Do you wish to get credit in git commit logs?</p>
<blockquote>We (just slightly) misunderstood each other here. It's not deleting the actual /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf file</blockquote>
Thanks, $DEITY!
<blockquote>but the line "wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf" within the actual /etc/network/interfaces, which is a symlink to /etc/network/interfaces.whonix after building.</blockquote>
whonix_(gateway|workstation)/etc/network/interfaces.whonix becomes your /etc/network/interfaces after building.
<p>Your /etc/network/interfaces before building becomes your /etc/network/interfaces.whonix-orig after building.</p>
<p>That’s why your wpa-conf line is lost, I think.</p>
<p>This inconvenience derives from the way how VM images are build. Having a “don’t replace /etc/network/interfaces when installing whonix-gateway-files” when variable BARE_METAL=1" in the code would be nice, but I wouldn’t know how to implement it. For Whonix 8 + 1 or even later, I plan to split Whonix’s source code into smaller source and Debian packages. Then whonix_(gateway|workstation)/etc/network/interfaces.whonix config files, could be put into a whonix-(gateway|workstation)-network-interfaces package, which is omitted for physical isolation users.</p>
<blockquote>Also not a big deal. I just consider it thorough bug reporting to mention it. Fixed it by reintroducing the wpa-conf and running</blockquote>
I can imagine that this is confusing. It must also look quite dilettantish, that your network is non-functional after installing. What we could add to physical isolation instructions in meanwhile "cp /etc/network/interfaces.whonix-orig /etc/network/interfaces" to get your old configuration back. The other option, editing /etc/network/interfaces.whonix before building and committing it to git seems even more awkward.
<blockquote>Basically "dpkg-diverting" configuration files shipped by conflicting packages.</blockquote>
Yes. It automates dpkg-divert this and their package seems quite stable. Also they have a good support mailing list.
<blockquote>As of suggestions: we may, at some point, introduce some awk/sed parsing of the existing (prior building) network configuration to avoid omitting something important like wpa-conf, i.e. noticing it's there and re-introducing it to /etc/network/interfaces_whonix. I'm going to think about that one. I mean, I actually assumed it would happen before building and it did exactly that. Newbies could be confused by that - thus I reported it to you. Although: newbies do not build physical isolation anyways :P</blockquote>
What do you think about my method of splitting Whonix into several packages?
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/87">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/87</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 14:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-87</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Quoting myself:</p>
<blockquote>Your decision after all. I would say disabling it would be good (although it doesn't harm the machine). When building for physical isolation, the host/target is prepared including swapfile and/or -partition prior building. Thus I see no need to auto-create it. Not a big deal though - just reporting.</blockquote>
Or better: What is your actual reasoning to introduce a swapfile when buliding for physical isolation? Maybe I miss something here.
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/86">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/86</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 13:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-86</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>For VM builds, no swapfile is automatically created. Do you propose shipping by default without a swapfile?
It would easy to disable swapfile creation for physical isolation users.</blockquote>
Your decision after all. I would say disabling it would be good (although it doesn't harm the machine). When building for physical isolation, the host/target is prepared including swapfile and/or -partition prior building. Thus I see no need to auto-create it. Not a big deal though - just reporting.
<blockquote>(And for modders sake: there is a build configuration to disable chroot / postinst.d scripts.)</blockquote>
(I think) it's also mentioned somewhere in the build instructions. Could be useful for further builds. Thanks for the hint.
<blockquote>This is very strange. I have no idea how this can happen. There is no result of "grep -r supplicant *" in Whonix's code. Perhaps by replacing /etc/network/interfaces and first boot, something automatically deletes /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf. But this also shouldn't happen, because by Debian policy, /etc is only for users and packages are not allowed to edit or even delete them (with the exception for initial creation).</blockquote>
We (just slightly) misunderstood each other here. It's not deleting the actual /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf file but the line "wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf" within the actual /etc/network/interfaces, which is a symlink to /etc/network/interfaces.whonix after building. My config (WAN part) prior building read:
[code]auto wlan0
iface wlan0 inet dhcp
wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf[/code]
afterwards it read:
[code]auto wlan0
iface wlan0 inet dhcp
pre-up /usr/bin/whonix_firewall[/code]
with the wpa-conf deleted/omitted. Also not a big deal. I just consider it thorough bug reporting to mention it. Fixed it by reintroducing the wpa-conf and running
[code]sudo service networking restart[/code]
<blockquote>Using config-package-dev (from jessie: https://packages.debian.org/jessie/config-package-dev). See also debian/*.displace files. config-package-dev helps to take ownership of files, which are owned by other packages, such as /etc/tor/torrc is owned by the "tor" Debian package. When upstream (Debian) releases upgraded, /etc/tor/torrc.whonix-orig gets upgraded, /etc/tor/torrc stays untouched. Only Whonix's package can update it. config-package-dev implementes this using symlinks and Debian maintainer scripts.</blockquote>
I understand. Basically "dpkg-diverting" configuration files shipped by conflicting packages. Thanks for explaining.
<blockquote>Whonix's focus is on virtual machine images. Physical Isolation is something that can be maintained as well with reasonable effort. I am not good at parsing/grepping/merging/grep/awk/sed/replace. To keep things simple and maintainable, config-package-dev seemed like the best solution. So upstream (Debian) can't mess up these files. And when there is need for a security update, new features or just better comments, it's simple to ship a new version of these files. I see for physical isolation users it's a more difficult, but whole physical isolation is more difficult.</blockquote>
I'm perfectly on the same page here. Thanks actually for implementing it that deliberated. dpkg-divert is the most clean way to deal with it (at least what I can currently think of).
<p>As of suggestions: we may, at some point, introduce some awk/sed parsing of the existing (prior building) network configuration to avoid omitting something important like wpa-conf, i.e. noticing it’s there and re-introducing it to /etc/network/interfaces_whonix. I’m going to think about that one. I mean, I actually assumed it would happen before building and it did exactly that. Newbies could be confused by that - thus I reported it to you. Although: newbies do not build physical isolation anyways <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue:"></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/85">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/85</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-85</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="83" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>1) I noticed that it creates a swap file at /swapfile1. Why is this?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>For VM builds, no swapfile is automatically created. Do you propose shipping by default without a swapfile?</p>
<p>It would easy to disable swapfile creation for physical isolation users.</p>
<p>(And for modders sake: there is a build configuration to disable chroot / postinst.d scripts.)</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="83" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>2) I mentioned earlier that the build script messed up my network configuration slightly. That is to say, it deleted my wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf line for the WAN interface (not a big issue).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is very strange. I have no idea how this can happen. There is no result of “grep -r supplicant *” in Whonix’s code. Perhaps by replacing /etc/network/interfaces and first boot, something automatically deletes /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf. But this also shouldn’t happen, because by Debian policy, /etc is only for users and packages are not allowed to edit or even delete them (with the exception for initial creation).</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="83" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m not sure how the script replaces the /etc/network/interfaces.whonix, most likely it completely re-writes it.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Using config-package-dev (from jessie: <a href="https://packages.debian.org/jessie/config-package-dev">https://packages.debian.org/jessie/config-package-dev</a>). See also debian/*.displace files. config-package-dev helps to take ownership of files, which are owned by other packages, such as /etc/tor/torrc is owned by the “tor” Debian package. When upstream (Debian) releases upgraded, /etc/tor/torrc.whonix-orig gets upgraded, /etc/tor/torrc stays untouched. Only Whonix’s package can update it. config-package-dev implementes this using symlinks and Debian maintainer scripts.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="83" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’m just saying that we may investigate how to preserve specifics in particular network configurations while building without actually erasing them, i.e. by carefully parsing them, merging them - haven’t thought about this for too long just yet. Just thinking it would be a potential improvement to the build process. Might be confusing to newbies otherwise.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The story behind this:<br>
Whonix’s focus is on virtual machine images. Physical Isolation is something that can be maintained as well with reasonable effort. I am not good at parsing/grepping/merging/grep/awk/sed/replace. To keep things simple and maintainable, config-package-dev seemed like the best solution. So upstream (Debian) can’t mess up these files. And when there is need for a security update, new features or just better comments, it’s simple to ship a new version of these files. I see for physical isolation users it’s a more difficult, but whole physical isolation is more difficult.</p>
<p>If you have any suggestions, I am eager to hear them.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/84">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/84</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 12:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-84</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/occq">@Occq</a><br>
I’m on the same page that logs are essential for troubleshooting. I refer to <span class="hashtag">#40</span> and after finally understanding the actual error, even much earlier. But, regarding the actual build error, everything is cool. You made a mistake. We all do. Period. I appreciate the way you dealt with it, i.e. briefly apologizing and that’s it.</p>
<p><span class="mention">@adrelanos</span><br>
Thanks for explaining thoroughly the whonix repositories. I’m going to re-subscribe to testing and switch to stable again when Whonix 8 will be released. As I understand it, it very much works like Debian stable, testing, sid from a release management perspective. As of you mentioning that Whonix and Debian repos are distinct things … see my writeup above.</p>
<p><span class="mention">@all</span><br>
I have another question + another remark regarding the build process:</p>
<ol>
<li>I noticed that it creates a swap file at /swapfile1. Why is this?</li>
<li>I mentioned earlier that the build script messed up my network configuration slightly. That is to say, it deleted my wpa-conf /etc/wpa_supplicant/wpa_supplicant.conf line for the WAN interface (not a big issue). I’m not sure how the script replaces the /etc/network/interfaces.whonix, most likely it completely re-writes it. I’m just saying that we may investigate how to preserve specifics in particular network configurations while building without actually erasing them, i.e. by carefully parsing them, merging them - haven’t thought about this for too long just yet. Just thinking it would be a potential improvement to the build process. Might be confusing to newbies otherwise.</li>
</ol>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/83">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/83</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 11:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-83</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="80" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Do you still have the 2000 lines of log I posted? If so, please send it back to me by email.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Done.</p>
<blockquote>I deleted it already and to make sure there's nothing in there, I'm going to read it whole through, manually. If there is something identifying in there, I'm getting back to you, if not, screw it.</blockquote>
This review is also a great contribution.
<blockquote>(2) I dislike not being taken seriously. I like Whonix and I would even contribute much more (if appreciated) but if I tell you that I haven't made a pebkac mistake (like forgetting to install "locales", checking out the wrong branches, typos in my modifications, etc.), I dislike being asked for another and another time. There is a reason I say that the build script is failing and it's not me as I have very carefully examined (in this very specific case) if it's my mistake before even posting that it's failing.
(to 2) being treated like a user/newbie, call it whatever you like - instead of a peer - contributed very much to a 2-day build-horror that could have been avoided if my very first mention of locale failing would have been taken seriously, looked at, thought about why it's producing errors. At the end of the day, the build instructions were plain wrong (UK) and nothing on my part and building this beast three times in a row on bare metal hardware with 3 re-installs is pita (unnecessary pita).</blockquote>
I am sorry about this. I am not a professional developer. I am a self-taught hobbyists and working on improving the build process. This is the first Free Software projects I am maintaining (my smaller ones such as VPN-Firewall don't really count). Due to time constraints (and perhaps also brain limitations) I won't be able to provide instructions/code that is near perfect for a testers-only release. And I am only steps away from not being able to produce near perfect product once stable. I mean, the Whonix 7 build instructions did break over time. A lot effort has been invested to make the build script more robust. Perhaps one day that goal can be reached.
<blockquote>I commented on the uuids. I know what a uuid is (again, I'm not stupid)</blockquote>
I don't know, that you know what they are about. And I don't expect anyone to know.
<blockquote>[quote]This isn't a game, where small differences in the gameplay don't matter. (...) Advanced Linux users as well as testers require a high frustration tolerance. Welcome to Free Software development. And you can always claim your money back, if you're not satisfied.[/quote]
How to comment here? I put it that way: would you contribute to a software project were you need to build something four times in a row, be treated like stupid: "Welcome to Free Software Development"? &lt; trust me, I'm way longer in the free software world than you (presumably) are and do not like to be treated arrogant. OK? Fact is, a volunteer tester loses 2 full working days to test your build, get questions asked like "are you sure you're not stupid and can read English?", i.e. have you installed "locales" - you asked me several times this question, last time via a command I understand (no worries), typos, faulty modifications ... at the end of the day it's nothing of that but your instructions and/or your script. If you want to work like that, fine, I can contribute to other projects then. If you'd like to start to talk to me respectfully, I'm gladly in.
<p>Most likely (at least part of the story) we get into conflict here as writing is such a bad medium for something like that. I can tell you that I do not feel treated the way I want here. Re-read what you said, especially the last quote and several other things along those lines - the tone is important here (I know my tone isn’t cool as well at the moment). Anyways, I hope we get in sync again as I’m not at all interested in this to be honest but in productive contribution (I’m sure you’re on the same page here).</p>
<p>To sum up: I make mistakes as everybody does but if I assure you that I did something correct, please do not ask me another and another time the same thing and let me re-install an OS 3 times. You know, I very much know what “sudo which update-locale ; echo $?” actually means. The very same as “do you have “locales” installed”? - are you kidding me? It’s a nice try, but you need to try harder here or better stop it and treat contributors like peers, not idiots.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is the way I diagnose bugs. I had absolutely no idea what could have caused it. That script worked for a long time. I can imagine, you really installed the grml_packages list, you really have locales installed and for some strange reason, “update-locale” is still not available. It’s unlikely (ex: hdd corruption), but not impossible. And when I tried it myself, I made a mistake and never noticed “United States” in instructions has changed to “United Kingdom”. So I tested with “United States” and never experienced that bug myself. After having excluded everything, my brain finally came up with an idea, which was the answer to this mystery.</p>
<p>If you take offense by “sudo which update-locale ; echo $?”, I can’t promise to do better. This is the way I diagnose bugs. I can promise, that it’s not my intention to offend anyone. For me, there is no point in offense. I’ll do this for the sake of coding for fun, for a good cause, and side effects. You’re welcome to contribute further. See my failure to communicate as deficiency in coding/social skills.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/82">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/82</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 11:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-82</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Let me rephrase that.</p>
<p>Running the script with the log option is essential for troubleshooting.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="73" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I heard several times during the last two days, that something stupid (“locales” not installed, possible typo, etc.) is the reason for a failing script while it’s the stupid script itself that’s failing (sorry, again, no offense intended really).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Occam’s razor.</p>
<p>It’s not in any way personal, it’s just the most practical way of dealing with things. It’s however not perfect as we saw.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/81">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/81</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 11:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-81</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>I and perhaps fortasse (webmaster) as well know as much as smf forum database as you do. If you tell us, how to do that, it can gladly be done. I've spend an hour already figuring out how to do it. Well, learned one thing or another in meanwhile. Seems like no one else on search engines ever asked how to do it. (And I doubt it's so trivial no one needed to ask.) I asked fortasse and stackexchange. With some nagging others it may be possible. If you want to speed up the process: 1. install smf locally 2. post something 3. delete it 4. check the database 5. delete from database 6. tell us how you did it.</blockquote>
Thanks for that. Do you still have the 2000 lines of log I posted? If so, please send it back to me by email. I deleted it already and to make sure there's nothing in there, I'm going to read it whole through, manually. If there is something identifying in there, I'm getting back to you, if not, screw it. I'm not talking about the uuids in particular (I know that these are gone after re-install) but after spotting them, I thought: omg! mac addresses maybe? I guess you understand where I'm coming from.
<blockquote>What parameters?</blockquote>
(1) posting logs that I'm not 100% certain (may) contain hardware ids by pgp/otr, by encrypted means. I mean, you know your build scripts, I do not. I'm just seeing that they're very verbose and I haven't checked 2000 lines of logs for hardware ids. If you can assure me that there are no hardware ids in there (not uuids) then fine. If not, I would prefer to have a look at again and then we can forget about it.
(2) I dislike not being taken seriously. I like Whonix and I would even contribute much more (if appreciated) but if I tell you that I haven't made a pebkac mistake (like forgetting to install "locales", checking out the wrong branches, typos in my modifications, etc.), I dislike being asked for another and another time. There is a reason I say that the build script is failing and it's not me as I have very carefully examined (in this very specific case) if it's my mistake before even posting that it's failing.
(to 2) being treated like a user/newbie, call it whatever you like - instead of a peer - contributed very much to a 2-day build-horror that could have been avoided if my very first mention of locale failing would have been taken seriously, looked at, thought about why it's producing errors. At the end of the day, the build instructions were plain wrong (UK) and nothing on my part and building this beast three times in a row on bare metal hardware with 3 re-installs is pita (unnecessary pita).
<blockquote>There is pgp e-mail available. Linked on the contact site. And I guess you overestimate those uuids. Those aren't hardware serials, they're software uuids. If you figure out how, you can change them without re-installation. They're gone after re-installation.</blockquote>
I commented on the uuids. I know what a uuid is (again, I'm not stupid) but seeing uuids in there at least implicates that mac addresses may be in there as well. Again, you know what your script logs, I do not. If other people carelessly post thousands of lines of logs to public forums without being aware of the actual contents, fine, I'm not and due to not reacting at me first mentioning of the locale fail, I was more or less forced to post it to not test a week with fail after fail. I hope you understand my point here.
<blockquote>This isn't a game, where small differences in the gameplay don't matter. (...) Advanced Linux users as well as testers require a high frustration tolerance. Welcome to Free Software development. And you can always claim your money back, if you're not satisfied.</blockquote>
How to comment here? I put it that way: would you contribute to a software project were you need to build something four times in a row, be treated like stupid: "Welcome to Free Software Development"? &lt; trust me, I'm way longer in the free software world than you (presumably) are and do not like to be treated arrogant. OK? Fact is, a volunteer tester loses 2 full working days to test your build, get questions asked like "are you sure you're not stupid and can read English?", i.e. have you installed "locales" - you asked me several times this question, last time via a command I understand (no worries), typos, faulty modifications ... at the end of the day it's nothing of that but your instructions and/or your script. If you want to work like that, fine, I can contribute to other projects then. If you'd like to start to talk to me respectfully, I'm gladly in.
<p>Most likely (at least part of the story) we get into conflict here as writing is such a bad medium for something like that. I can tell you that I do not feel treated the way I want here. Re-read what you said, especially the last quote and several other things along those lines - the tone is important here (I know my tone isn’t cool as well at the moment). Anyways, I hope we get in sync again as I’m not at all interested in this to be honest but in productive contribution (I’m sure you’re on the same page here).</p>
<p>To sum up: I make mistakes as everybody does but if I assure you that I did something correct, please do not ask me another and another time the same thing and let me re-install an OS 3 times. You know, I very much know what “sudo which update-locale ; echo $?” actually means. The very same as “do you have “locales” installed”? - are you kidding me? It’s a nice try, but you need to try harder here or better stop it and treat contributors like peers, not idiots.</p>
<p>Feel free to get rid of any bad emotions. Same opportunity for both of us. If you want to, let’s shake hands afterwards - my preferred outcome here.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/80">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/80</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-80</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>[quote=“Cerberus, post:77, topic:67”]That said, I have a question: During build I opted in to enable APT repository. After reboot whonixsetup asks me if I want to subscribe to stable/testers/developers repo. What am I supposed to do here? testers I assume? or even developers? does it need to be switched to stable later on or how does that work? I searched for documentation but haven’t find sufficient information. I’m going to look through the repo to find out. I guess making the wrong choice here would be fatal due to Debian stable/testing. I’m taking the chance and will select testers for now. Any feedback here?</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
<p>EDIT: Selected stable repo for now - until I’m told to select something else. I guess it won’t downgrade or something. Managed to fix the network configuration. Seems to work.[/quote]</p>
<p>Choose stable/testers/developers as you wish. You an always switch from one repository to another. Stable is supposed to be the most convenient, most stable, least contributing one. It won’t downgrade from testers to stable, though. Since the whonix_repository tool only configures up apt-key and apt sources.</p>
<p>Stable has least chance of breaking down. Stable is currently providing Whonix 7 packages. Fortunately, apt-get/dpkg won’t downgrade by mistake.</p>
<p>Testers is the same as this thread currently, testing things with the community before it gets migrated to stable.</p>
<p>Developers is just for me at the moment. I’ll upload my test packages there, test them on one and another machine. If they badly break, i.e. if they manual fixing is required afterwards, those won’t be migrated to the testers repository. When I am confident, they’re working well enough, they are migrated to the testers repository.</p>
<p>This has nothing to do with Debian stable vs Debian testing. The Whonix repository only provides Whonix’s Debian packages (<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Whonix_Debian_Packages">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Whonix_Debian_Packages</a>).</p>
<p>Please tell me if this answers everything.</p>
<p>Seems indeed undocumented. Should be added here:<br>
</p><aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Whonix-APT-Repository" target="_blank" title="04:56PM - 01 May 2020">Whonix – 1 May 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:579/411;"><img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/d/d8/Changerepositorygui234234.png" class="thumbnail" width="579" height="411"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Whonix-APT-Repository" target="_blank">Project-APT-Repository - Whonix</a></h3>

<p>Whonix ™ stable / testers / developers APT Repository. How to change from one suite to another? How to disable Whonix ™ APT Repository?</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>We can do this depending on how much other questions this may raise.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/79">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/79</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 09:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-79</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="73" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>[quote]I don’t know about the forum database.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>may you please make sure that it gets wiped then? I would really like to contribute to Whonix testing with logs and everything. Shared with a small group but doing this on a public forum is stupid to say the least. Wouldn’t want to be too paranoid but (1) posting the log was never needed as it’s perfectly clear that it’s your script that’s failing, not me - other than you assumed for the last 36 hours + 3 failed build runs (“locales” certainly is installed) and (2) I do not have control over your database and I do not want that information in there. So, if possible, please wipe it.[/quote]<br>
I and perhaps fortasse (webmaster) as well know as much as smf forum database as you do. If you tell us, how to do that, it can gladly be done. I’ve spend an hour already figuring out how to do it. Well, learned one thing or another in meanwhile. Seems like no one else on search engines ever asked how to do it. (And I doubt it’s so trivial no one needed to ask.) I asked fortasse and stackexchange. With some nagging others it may be possible. If you want to speed up the process: 1. install smf locally 2. post something 3. delete it 4. check the database 5. delete from database 6. tell us how you did it.</p>
<blockquote>No offense intended here (really) but this testing session just isn't worth it from my perspective.</blockquote>
Sad to hear.
<blockquote>Let's change some parameters and I'm gladly in.</blockquote>
What parameters?
<blockquote>That is to say: (1) exchanging logs by encrypted means (pgp, otr, whatever else) and (2) taking reports about failing scripts seriously.</blockquote>
There is pgp e-mail available. Linked on the contact site. And I guess you overestimate those uuids. Those aren't hardware serials, they're software uuids. If you figure out how, you can change them without re-installation. They're gone after re-installation.
<blockquote>I heard several times during the last two days, that something stupid ("locales" not installed, possible typo, etc.) is the reason for a failing script while it's the stupid script itself that's failing (sorry, again, no offense intended really).</blockquote>
Any command that exits with an unexpected exit code is considered a failure and the script exits. This ensures integrity of the build. This isn't a game, where small differences in the gameplay don't matter. Whonix makes these things uniform, i.e. timezone, username, hostname as well as locale. In case later any custom installed application leaks it, you're in the Whonix (and in many cases Tails etc.) anonymity set and better off.
<p>Whonix 8 + 1’s build script will have an undocumented feature to continue in case of unexpected exit codes.</p>
<blockquote>hope you don't mind my response but this needed to be said after 2 days of failures due to a faulty script</blockquote>
Well, the physical isolation instructions are meant to be used by advanced Linux users. It can probably never be convenient and simple. Advanced Linux users as well as testers require a high frustration tolerance. Welcome to Free Software development. And you can always claim your money back, if you're not satisfied.
<blockquote>Honesty is the best policy here I guess - with all due respect.</blockquote>
Honesty is fine. And I don't easily take offense, because I am not convinced of the hypothesis of free will.
<p>I’ve read the <a href="http://producingoss.com/">http://producingoss.com/</a> book by Karl Fogel. He advises to treat users as developers as well. I can’t provide the quality of robustness and simplicity you’re asking for. And without any help of testers, it would be simplest to just drop support for physical isolation at all.</p>
<p>But for my defense, I guess there are worse build environments.</p>
<p>How to build a Debian/Ubuntu installer cd from source code? I haven’t even found instructions on how to do it. Then I asked on stackexchange, and no one else knew either. Well, would I have been more serious about it, i.e. by meeting up with Debian developers, they would have probably told me.</p>
<p>Did you try to build Tails from source code? Last time I checked, their git repository was several gigabytes big. And since their forum and website shares the same git repository, it is difficult to keep up with changes they make in git, because most changes were simply irrelevant (website, forum). You need to build using squeeze (which I consider obsolete) and manually install build dependencies using backports (there is no script to automate it). And when you finally have your build environment, it requires a vagrant box (a virtual machine). So building Tails within a virtual machine is difficult, since you would have to build inside a nested VM. That vagrant box is a binary box based on Ubuntu. I didn’t want to use their binary box, not because I distrust it, but because I really wanted to build from source code for the sake of it. And I didn’t want to use a Ubuntu box, because I don’t trust and choose to boycott Ubuntu since they started messing up with amazon data leaks. And they have no instructions on how to build that vagrant box from source. So I would have required to learn vagrant first, then I gave up.</p>
<p>I do my best to do better. And I am not there yet where I want it to be.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/78">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/78</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 08:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-78</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Success! After re-installing with Region “United States” the build went through. So, I’m reporting a finished build of Whonix-Gateway, bare-metal on bare metal, terminal-only here, 7.7.8.9.</p>
<p>Now, while it messed up my network configuration (deleted my encryption settings), I guess I’ll be able to fix that manually.</p>
<p>That said, I have a question: During build I opted in to enable APT repository. After reboot whonixsetup asks me if I want to subscribe to stable/testers/developers repo. What am I supposed to do here? testers I assume? or even developers? does it need to be switched to stable later on or how does that work? I searched for documentation but haven’t find sufficient information. I’m going to look through the repo to find out. I guess making the wrong choice here would be fatal due to Debian stable/testing. I’m taking the chance and will select testers for now. Any feedback here?</p>
<p>Thanks!</p>
<p>EDIT: Selected stable repo for now - until I’m told to select something else. I guess it won’t downgrade or something. Managed to fix the network configuration. Seems to work.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/77">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/77</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 07:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-77</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="71" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
 adrelanos:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/cerberus">@Cerberus</a>, riseup currently down. Can’t send mail right now.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>No problem. Not needed currently. Thanks for saving the GPG key. Could be needed for further testing.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="74" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/o/49beb7/40.png" class="avatar"> Occq:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>My apologies to you too Cerberus. I wrote to set the country as UK and that, it seems, broke the script.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Really, no worries here. We all make mistakes. I’m more pissed about not taking thorough testing seriously, like mentioning stupid things like “locales” not installed, possible typos etc. as a possible reason for failure if it’s the script, the instructions or something related.</p>
<blockquote>We need a certain form for reporting build errors.
<p>Maybe this.</p>
<p>:::::::::::::::::::::::::<br>
If you are having problems, share the following:</p>
<p>Are you building in a VM or not?<br>
On what (guest) OS are you building?<br>
Which git tag?<br>
Workstation, Gateway, bare metal option?<br>
Share you build log file (through someSecureOption)<br>
::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::</p>
</blockquote><br>
Agreed!
<p>[quote=“Occq, post:75, topic:67”]I have to disagree there.</p>
<p>Posting the log is an essential diagnostic tool. Sure, the script failed but why it failed can only be seen from the log. Without it we’re are all just guessing.[/quote]<br>
I disagree here. The few lines I posted in <span class="hashtag">#40</span> perfectly identified the reason for the failing script. I selected them due to this fact as an excerpt after all. Posting 2000 lines with potentially identifying information on a public forum was not required. Also the error could have been identified way earlier if one wouldn’t concentrate on (im)possible silly user mistake like not being able to read two pages of build instructions. I mean, due to the pseudonymity involved on these forums we cannot be sure with whom we’re dealing with. I mean we cannot share how much experience we have, background, etc - if we could, we wouldn’t need to assume pebkac. I won’t tell you too much here, but I can 100% assure you, that pebkac isn’t very likely if I test something Linux-related due to experience. Git isn’t in my skillset I have to admit. SVN is. Thus I stumbled over the commit issue earlier on.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/76">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/76</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-76</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="73" data-topic="67">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/c/71e660/40.png" class="avatar"> Cerberus:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>posting the log was never needed as it’s perfectly clear that it’s your script that’s failing, not me</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I have to disagree there.</p>
<p>Posting the log is an essential diagnostic tool. Sure, the script failed but why it failed can only be seen from the log. Without it we’re are all just guessing.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/75">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/75</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-75</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>My apologies to you too Cerberus. I wrote to set the country as UK and that, it seems, broke the script.</p>
<p>We need a certain form for reporting build errors.</p>
<p>Maybe this.</p>
<p>:::::::::::::::::::::::::<br>
If you are having problems, share the following:</p>
<p>Are you building in a VM or not?<br>
On what (guest) OS are you building?<br>
Which git tag?<br>
Workstation, Gateway, bare metal option?<br>
Share you build log file (through someSecureOption)<br>
::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::::</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/74">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/74</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 23:58:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-74</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Cerberus]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>I don't know about the forum database.</blockquote>
may you please make sure that it gets wiped then? I would really like to contribute to Whonix testing with logs and everything. Shared with a small group but doing this on a public forum is stupid to say the least. Wouldn't want to be too paranoid but (1) posting the log was never needed as it's perfectly clear that it's your script that's failing, not me - other than you assumed for the last 36 hours + 3 failed build runs ("locales" certainly is installed) and (2) I do not have control over your database and I do not want that information in there. So, if possible, please wipe it.
<p>No offense intended here (really) but this testing session just isn’t worth it from my perspective. Let’s change some parameters and I’m gladly in. That is to say: (1) exchanging logs by encrypted means (pgp, otr, whatever else) and (2) taking reports about failing scripts seriously. I heard several times during the last two days, that something stupid (“locales” not installed, possible typo, etc.) is the reason for a failing script while it’s the stupid script itself that’s failing (sorry, again, no offense intended really).</p>
<p>hope you don’t mind my response but this needed to be said after 2 days of failures due to a faulty script and especially due to my log, presumably, in your database (something that wouldn’t be needed anyways as the actual build error is more than clear). Honesty is the best policy here I guess - with all due respect.</p>
<p>EDIT: I’m really sorry if this sounds harsh. It’s not at all meant that way, but - in all honesty - I can’t stand the testing procedure as is due to the reasons outlined. I hope we get in sync again and continue to be productive.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/73">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/73</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 23:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-73</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Occq]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>that cat entry is wrong (edited it).</p>
<p>I forgot that my latest installations are done through preseed.</p>
<pre><code class="lang-auto">d-i debian-installer/language string en
d-i debian-installer/country string US
d-i debian-installer/locale string en_US.UTF-8</code></pre>
<p>From that error I gained some wrong insights.</p>
<p>American English was chosen because I thought the majority of users have those settings. Thinking back, UK/American English is probably not that common.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/72">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/72</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 23:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-72</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/cerberus">@Cerberus</a>, riseup currently down. Can’t send mail right now.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/71">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/71</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 23:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-71</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/cerberus">@Cerberus</a>, I stored your gpg key.</p>
<p>[quote=“Occq, post:68, topic:67”]It seems I was wrong.</p>
<p>My apologizes for the faulty instructions.[/quote]<br>
Nevermind. I am happy your work.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/70">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67/70</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 23:48:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-67-70</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/testers-wanted-whonix-8-release-candidate-1-whonix-7-7-8-6/67.rss">Testers-wanted! Whonix 8 Release candidate #1 Whonix 7.7.8.6</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
