<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206</link>
    <description>What is so unreliable or unfinished in Whonix that [warnings about it being experimental software ](https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Warning#Whonix_is_a_Work_in_Progress)are warranted? Are the shortcomings mostly in usability and user friendliness or in features to do with security, privacy, anonymity?

Isn&#39;t it more secure to use Whonix than just Tor Browser? Yet Whonix scares the user with way more warnings. Saying that it may have grave bugs and vulnerabilites isn&#39;t an argument, because that is true of all software. When will it grow out of its experimental phase and be considered mature? It says [here](https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Warning#Missing_Whonix_Features)

&gt; While many issues listed below are planned for future implementation, a number will probably never get &quot;fixed&quot; because they are impossible to address in a software-only project.

Does this mean Whonix will forever be condemned to being alpha software? Most of the vulnerabilites on the linked list are common to all computer systems and some transcend them entirely. Whonix can&#39;t solve all computer security problems, no one system can. It shouldn&#39;t stay experimental until it gains self-consciousness.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 22:08:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This was done.</p>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-username="Patrick" data-post="1" data-topic="8994">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_2.png" class="avatar"><a href="//forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-virtualbox-15-0-0-8-9-point-release-vanguards-tcp-isn-leak-protection-extensive-hardening/8994/1">Whonix VirtualBox 15.0.0.8.9 - Point Release! - vanguards; TCP ISN Leak Protection; Extensive Hardening! <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/fire.png?v=9" title="fire" alt="fire" class="emoji"></a>
</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="https://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/6">Rebrand Whonix as a research project.</a></p>
<ul>
<li>old: “Whonix is experimental software. Do not rely on it for strong anonymity.”</li>
<li>new: “Whonix is a research project.”</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Quote <a href="https://www.whonix.org">https://www.whonix.org</a></p>
<blockquote>
<h4>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/What_we_do">Research</a> and Implementation Project</h4>
<p>Be wary of those confidently calling themselves all-knowing, all-perfect. Whonix is an actively maintained research project making constant improvements – no <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Warning">shortcomings</a> are ever hidden from users.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://github.com/Whonix/dist-base-files/blob/master/etc/update-motd.d/30_dist-base-files#L54">https://github.com/Whonix/dist-base-files/blob/master/etc/update-motd.d/30_dist-base-files#L54</a></p>
<hr>
<p>Other developments since:</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Whonix_Live" target="_blank" title="07:20AM - 05 March 2020">whonix.org – 5 Mar 20</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:120/66;"><img src="https://www.whonix.org/w/images/b/bf/Live_boot.png" class="thumbnail" width="120" height="66"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Whonix_Live" target="_blank">Whonix ™ Live Mode - Stop Persistent Malware - Whonix</a></h3>

<p>Whonix ™ Live Mode. Read-only mode. Make all writes go to non-persistent memory (RAM) instead of the hard disk. This is NOT an anti-forensics feature!</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/47">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/47</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 22:08:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-47</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="45" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/f/bc8723/40.png" class="avatar"> fish:</div>
<blockquote>
<p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/pano">@Pano</a> It’s great to see the community has enthusiasm and to hear from you. But I disagree with a lot of what you say about the documentation. There are so many things to consider it’s impossible to make it short and simple. I appreciate every word of it, even if some of it isn’t applicable to my Whonix. Privacy is hard.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Thank you for your feedback. That’s OK you disagree.</p>
<p>I find it very useful to have things explained in a concise way and for the specific cases I require (for example, one hypervisor, one Whonix version), and I write such summaries for myself (you can see one I did in the “Tor Bridges Documentation” thread).</p>
<p>I do that <em>because</em> privacy is hard, not <em>despite</em> it being hard.</p>
<p>Actually, being able to explain something in a clear and easy-to-follow way is an indication for me, that I reached a good grasp of the subject.</p>
<p>Such summaries perhaps are too subjective, or tailored for my needs - everyone has different backgrounds. They probably will not benefit others to the same degree. I, for example, don’t need an explanation how to save a file or about the different ways it can be edited, but I do require more background and remarks in linux networking issues. Someone else will have other priorities.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/46">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/46</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 12:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-46</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fish]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/patrick">@Patrick</a> I can appreciate the sentiments expressed by the main developer. If it’s not mature it just isn’t. But I still think the reasons for Whonix having experimental status need to be more clearly presented to (potential) users. What goals have not been met? Get rid of the many nonsense overambitious goals. Define the goals more clearly and not too many.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="23" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/f/bc8723/40.png" class="avatar"> fish:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Whonix must aim to be a fully torified operating system which does not allow anything running inside it to leak the real IP address.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>As I understand this is the main goal and Whonix does this well and reliably. Emphasize the strengths of Whonix as well as its weaknesses. Probably a sensible goal in the midterm would be to just make using Tor browser more secure and private in Whonix than doing so on the host. This is probably what most users do most in Whonix. Looks like it has already been met. <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/grinning.png?v=5" title=":grinning:" class="emoji" alt=":grinning:"></p>
<p>With many warnings and without an adequate explanation of what Whonix does, doesn’t and should do an impression may be created that it is barely working or not at all. That doesn’t look like the case to me. If using Whonix gives you more security, privacy and anonymity than just using Tor browser (or other Tor software), then users should be made to understand this. Even if Whonix is not prefect. A condition of course also being a sufficient study and understanding of the documentation. Then users will have no doubt about whether switching to Whonix today is recommended and a good idea. Can this question be answered at this time?</p>
<p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/pano">@Pano</a> It’s great to see the community has enthusiasm and to hear from you. But I disagree with a lot of what you say about the documentation. There are so many things to consider it’s impossible to make it short and simple. I appreciate every word of it, even if some of it isn’t applicable to my Whonix. Privacy is hard.</p>
<p><strong>Other</strong><br>
I think the Whonix documentation is so rich that it should be of great interest to anyone curious about privacy. They don’t have to be a Whonix user or an aspiring one. Maybe start considering or promoting the wiki also as a standalone knowledge resource. The same may be said of the forum actually, it’s a bit more like a news resource.</p>
<p>Regarding rates of contribution it may be <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1%25_rule_(Internet_culture)" rel="nofollow noopener"> just the way the world is</a>.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="33" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/e/8dc957/40.png" class="avatar"> entr0py:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I think it’s time to give <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/fish">@fish</a> back his thread.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>It’s not mine, what gives a thread its meaning is that everyone shares <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"> I didn’t mean extra discussion is bad, better messy than empty.</p>
<p><strong>The below would better fit in the closed <a href="https://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-and-tails-discussion/5223">Whonix and Tails Discussion</a></strong><br>
I don’t believe in Tails. The only thing it can do better than Whonix is forget everything locally. But when is that useful? If you’re using your own computer and want control over it, you use full disk encryption. Period. So Tails on your own computer brings nothing of benefit. Using someone else’s computer is firstly a security compromise and secondly a dying habit. Wireless networks are everywhere and most people have a network-capable device with them all the time. They’re getting cheaper, better, more common. Device sharing should therefore decline ever more. It may even become socially unacceptable, not fully without reason, mind my first point. Public computers for general use with unrestricted access are disappearing and the authorities certainly aren’t sorry about everyone being more traceable. They are also out of fashion which matters to the common user and there’s a hygiene problem. So why and when would you use Tails?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/45">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/45</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 11:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-45</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="43" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Yes, I appreciate the potential reusability of templates. But in many cases you need to be specific to be clear.</p>
<p>Now I also start to understand why the whole wiki is so cluttered and why it looks like something one  submits to a compiler (the blocks inside blocks inside blocks) - using too many templates is probably part of the reason.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree with you. In many cases the templates actually prevent wiki editors from making contributions because the edits would not make sense for all the pages concerned.</p>
<p>If the template needs to be removed from the chapter then you can do so. <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"></p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="42" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/0/ec9cab/40.png" class="avatar"> 0brand:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Your actual IP is not logged. It s referring to logging address 127.0.0.1(every user has that same IP)</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>After further consideration.</p>
<p>If you’re accessing <a href="http://Whonix.org">Whonix.org</a> you should assume the following (mass data collection by advanced adversaries).</p>
<p>You access Whonix by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Whonix <em>.onion</em> hidden service ( no exit node IP is logged since users stay inside the Tor network. Your external <em>real</em> IP  could not be logged)</li>
<li>
<a href="http://Whonix.org">Whonix.org</a> using Tor ( the exit node IP from which the user logged in from could be logged)</li>
<li>
<a href="http://Whonix.org">Whonix.org</a> over clearnet (your actual IP could be logged)</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/44">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/44</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 12:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-44</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>If I edit this template as I intended to, it will probably make no sense whatsoever when used in other pages. And it doesn’t make much sense in the way it is currently used here.</p>
<p>So, this template needs to be removed from this page altogether.</p>
<p>Yes, I appreciate the potential reusability of templates. But in many cases you need to be <em>specific</em> to be clear.<br>
Now I also start to understand why the whole wiki is so cluttered and why it looks like something one  submits to a compiler (the blocks inside blocks inside blocks) - using too many templates is probably part of the reason.</p>
<p>Again, nice principle, but when you force a structure over something that needs to be dynamic, problem.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/43</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 10:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-43</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="41" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I actually tried to edit it but it told me my IP will be logged (no) or I have to log in (to yet another account?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Your actual IP is not logged. It s referring to logging address 127.0.0.1(every user has that same IP)</p>
<p>Anonymous edits are welcome so no login is necessary. You can create a seperate Wiki account if you’d like.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="41" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>plus I couldn’t figure out how to edit the intro box. It’s elsewhere.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>You will find some of the content has its own template. This is done when its used in more than one place. Its more efficient when edits are needed. The only problem with this is it limits how it can be used.  Yes, its a PITA.</p>
<p>To find this template:</p>
<p>After the edit button is hit you will see this at the very bottom of the page.</p>
<p><strong>Templates used on this page:</strong> &lt;-- Click on this</p>
<p>(You will see a listing of all templates used on the page.)</p>
<p>This is the one you want) <em><strong>Template:Tor UDP (view source) (protected)</strong></em></p>
<p>There is a problem. You don’t have permissions to edit that template. Thats one of the reasons to copy the wiki page to a text editor. When you are done let torjunkie know so the template can be unlock. Then you can push the edits for review. BTW the templates are locked due to idiots using them for spamming the wiki.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/42</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 10:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-42</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="34" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_2.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>It’s always been a minority of a minority using this. An even smaller</p>
<p>minority using it for the right reasons or having a good reason for</p>
<p>using it. Let alone before all of it was documented, using it in sane</p>
<p>ways, that is using a fail closed mechanism if their use case demands one.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>There is a LOT of interest in using VPN with Tor. You can see it in many forums. People are doing it left and right, whether it’s done for good reasons or with a fail safe mechanism is another question. Plus there are sites blocking Tor exit nodes, where you have to use something, We discussed it in a recent thread. And in some cases you better use the same IP from one login to another or the site gets crazy.</p>
<p>Another use is when you need UDP. In one word (this is my 2 seconds explanation, not 2 minutes), Whonix doc’s solution for that is “VPN”.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="" height="">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tunnel_UDP_over_Tor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Whonix</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:640/426;"><img src="//forums.whonix.org/uploads/default/original/2X/1/1130f96f0b84e7e49f1715b5d39508eeba77e692.jpg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tunnel_UDP_over_Tor" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Tunnel UDP over Tor</a></h3>

<p>Workaround for Tunnelling UDP over Tor. Connection Schema: user -&gt; Tor -&gt; destination</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>By the way, that page is also awful (thankfully it’s very short), the introduction section is just absurd. It refers to itself as if it’s a remote page, and then tries to clarify it with “this page below”. Just to make sure. Monthy Python kinda humor? I actually tried to edit it but it told me my IP will be logged (no) or I have to log in (to yet another account? different account for this forum and for editing wiki?), plus I couldn’t figure out how to edit the intro box. It’s elsewhere.</p>
<p>The first section should be:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Tor software does not yet support UDP, [1] although Tor provides a DnsPort. This page details possible workarounds.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>instead of:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Tor software does not yet support UDP, [1] although Tor provides a DnsPort. If UDP is urgently required in Whonix, a limited workaround is provided. For the most secure method, see Tunnel UDP over Tor.<br>
(This page below.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There are other things that could be changed a the other sections.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/41</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 04:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-41</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="39" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/e/8dc957/40.png" class="avatar"> entr0py:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>You stole pano’s first edit!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Oops! Should I revert the edit? <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye.png?v=5" title=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:" class="emoji" alt=":stuck_out_tongue_winking_eye:"></p>
<p>Just made another edit to that chapter.(I’m my own worst critic)  I think it just needed to be clarified a little. The phrase ‘sensitive data’ or “sensitive info” can mean something different to each person.</p>
<p>I made sure readers understood the sensitive data that was referred to was external to Whonix-Workstation. Also added some info into footnote.</p>
<p>Let me know what you think</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/40</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 01:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-40</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[entr0py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/0brand">@0brand</a>! You stole pano’s first edit! <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=5" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/39</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-39</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="36" data-topic="5206" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/e/8dc957/40.png" class="avatar"> entr0py:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Whonix does not filter the content of outgoing traffic. Please edit the page.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Done!</p>
<p><a href="https://whonix.org/w/index.php?title=Security_in_Real_World&amp;oldid=33705&amp;diff=cur">https://whonix.org/w/index.php?title=Security_in_Real_World&amp;oldid=33705&amp;diff=cur</a></p>
<p>//cc <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/torjunkie">@torjunkie</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/38</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 23:17:51 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-38</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[onion_knight]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Very interesting read! It’s nice to see such activity on the forum! I encourage everyone with improvement suggestions to actually contribute, for example on the Wiki…</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/37</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 19:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-37</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[entr0py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Whonix does not filter the content of outgoing traffic. Please edit the page.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/36</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 17:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-36</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="34" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_1.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>No, related:</p>
<pre><code>  Whonix
</code></pre>
<p>Security in Real World</p>
<p>How Whonix defeats many notable “in the wild” anonymity attacks.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>From that link:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This security bug was used to craft an exploit which was able to break the Subgraph OS security model.[7] Since Subgraph does not contain Nautilus in an Oz sandbox, [8] once the malicious script was executed, it would have enabled access to much of the user’s data; PGP keys, SSH keys, stored email, documents, password databases, MAC addresses and nearby Wi-Fi access points.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>This sensitive information could be used by attackers to deanonymize the user. Whonix defeats this attack and others like it. Since Whonix-Workstation is isolated from the host and Whonix-Gateway, even if a malicious .desktop script is executed, no information can be gathered about the external IP address, hardware serials or sensitive user data.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>External IP address or serials, MAC addresses, Wifi data - that’s understood. But I don’t see anything in Whonix-Workstation stopping this script from sending the other data stored locally, such as the  PGP keys, SSH keys, stored email, documents, password databases etc.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/35</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 16:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-35</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>One can’t make everyone happy.</p>
<p>VPN / proxy / tunnel documentation is a complex beast indeed.</p>
<p>However, note on<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser#Bypass_Tor_Censorship" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser#Bypass_Tor_Censorship</a> we mention:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It is possible to combine Tor with tunnels like VPNs, proxies and SSH.<br>
The traffic can be sent through both Tor and the second tunnel, in<br>
either order. However, this is an advanced topic and appropriate only<br>
for special cases. Adding a second connection does not automatically<br>
improve security, but it will add significant complexity. The potential<br>
positive or negative effects on anonymity are being controversially<br>
debated. ( <a href="https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TorPlusVPN" rel="nofollow noopener">https://trac.torproject.org/projects/tor/wiki/doc/TorPlusVPN</a> )</p>
<p>The Whonix project remains technologically neutral in the anonymity<br>
discussion. The improper combination of Tor and another service may<br>
actually degrade a user’s security and anonymity. These configurations<br>
are difficult to set up and should only be attempted by advanced users.<br>
For the vast majority of Whonix users, using Tor in isolation  without a<br>
VPN or proxy  is the correct choice.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s always been a minority of a minority using this. An even smaller<br>
minority using it for the right reasons or having a good reason for<br>
using it. Let alone before all of it was documented, using it in sane<br>
ways, that is using a fail closed mechanism if their use case demands one.</p>
<p>We recently noticed that most users may need only censorship<br>
circumvention by remote servers which is way easier reached and now<br>
documented here:<br>
<a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser#Bypass_Tor_Censorship" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Tor_Browser#Bypass_Tor_Censorship</a></p>
<p>Please don’t use the VPN / proxy / tunnels documentation as a prime<br>
example to discuss how Whonix documentation should be structured.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/torjunkie">@torjunkie</a>:<br>
Qubes-like “Quick Guide” sections at the top of each relevant entry.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I like that.</p>
<p>What about this style?</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Easy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Easy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Disable_Easy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Disable_Easy</a></li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Advanced users and those in a hurry can just get it done.)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I think perhaps better these should target beginner type users?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If someone was ambitious, simply do this for the most relevant<br>
sections of the main wiki e.g. security-related, updating etc. Create a<br>
new wiki page - “Whonix Pocket Reference” or “Whonix Cheatsheet”.<br>
Categorize the entries as relevant.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>What about this style?</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Easy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Easy</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Disable_Easy" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Stream_Isolation/Disable_Easy</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Since I am a too technical person, I will most likely tend to the<br>
community judgment on which style is easiest for beginners (on separate<br>
page; or easy section on top of a page; or alternative suggested solution).</p>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>And you know what? now that I understand, if I need to explain it to someone, verbally or in writing, it would not take me 2 hours. It would take me exactly 2 minutes.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Then describe it in 2 min and put it on the Wiki, why don’t you just add your “2min” explanation ?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That would be cool.</p>
<blockquote>
<aside class="quote no-group" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Start by concentrating on the most common issue, and on the simplest solution! 80% of or more the readers need just that!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
</blockquote>
<p>Then we’ll have 20% frustrated users. Not sure that would be more or<br>
less than now and probably no way to know.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Was Whonix ever subject to an external security audit that was published?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>No, related:<br>
</p><aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.whonix.org/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="" height="">
      <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Security_in_Real_World" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Whonix</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:666/500;"><img src="//forums.whonix.org/uploads/default/original/2X/4/447a6b343d0931f6290c228436c177b801bd730f.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Security_in_Real_World" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Security in Real World</a></h3>

<p>How Whonix defeats many notable "in the wild" anonymity attacks.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<p></p>
<p>fish:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Saying not to rely on it for strong anonymity is surprising, is this<br>
also the case for Tor in general according to your criteria?<br>
Yes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>See:<br>
<a href="https://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long">https://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/34</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 14:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-34</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[entr0py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>This thread has grown to 3 topics:</p>
<ol>
<li>Whonix development status label</li>
<li>Documentation</li>
<li>Whonix vs Tails</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>I think it’s time to give <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/fish">@fish</a> back his thread.</strong></p>
<p>The Whonix vs Tails discussion is a good one to have. If I could, I would split this thread into multiple topics but it looks like individual posts are moving back and forth between topics. Here’s a new thread if you want to continue the discussion. <a href="https://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-and-tails-discussion/5223/1">Whonix and Tails Discussion</a>. Feel free to copy/paste from this thread. Hint: Many wiki pages are born from just these types of discussions.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/33</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 18:38:18 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-33</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[entr0py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="30" data-topic="5206" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Thanks torjunkie, looks good, whining and ranting is great but contributing can be fun too I guess.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/pano">@pano</a> It’s not that we don’t understand or even disagree with what you’re proposing. Please take 2 mins and glance at this thread from <strong>two years ago</strong>. <a href="https://forums.whonix.org/t/splitting-whonix-documentation-into-a-short-and-long-edition-for-better-usability/1861/10">splitting Whonix documentation into a short and long edition for better usability</a>. I even proposed an outline to streamline the docs. It never got done. Why? <strong>Because I didn’t do it.</strong> You know the saying… ideas are like assholes… I thought I had a good idea but why would I expect anyone else to do it? Every single person here is part-time, volunteer, and busy with a million things. If you have spare time to implement your ideas, we’ll welcome you!</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/32</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 18:22:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-32</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="29" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/a/a183cd/40.png" class="avatar"> Algernon:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Proxy before or after Tor is certainly not one of the common issues.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Of course it isn’t. The argument I am making is how a specific issue should be documented: in the scope of “Using a Proxy after Tor” page, the vast majority of users will be interested in doing that for the <em>Tor Browser</em>, and not for other applications (for example wget or curl or anything else).</p>
<p>If the page started with a clearly separate section just about that (in reality the case of Tor Browser is discussed in at least 3 different separate parts throughout the page), or better if there was a separate page just for “how to use proxy after <em>Tor Browser</em>”, it would solve the issue for 80% of users. And would be much shorter and simpler <em>without</em> sacrificing warnings or any important detail.<br>
Why 80%? Yes, also a gut feeling. But I think you will agree with me that the Tor Browser is, by far, the most used application in Whonix?</p>
<p>The discussion about Whonix vs. Tails can go on forever. Since you see I spend time with Whonix you can understand that I don’t think it’s inferior. I do think the point of “workstation does not see the IP” is emphasized too much. When you have many people relying on Whonix, and naturally those people have reasons to use this non-trivial setup, Whonix-Gateway becomes a very valuable target to exploit. But again this is off-topic.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/31</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-31</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Thanks torjunkie, looks good, whining and ranting is great but contributing can be fun too I guess.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/30</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 12:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-30</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Algernon]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>As already said by others: If you don’t like a specific wiki page, feel free to change it.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Start by concentrating on the most common issue, and on the simplest solution! 80% of or more the readers need just that!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Where do you get the number from? Proxy before or after Tor is certainly not one of the common issues. Where do I get this from? My gut feeling. So I could be wrong. If it would be relevant for 80% of the common users there would probably more complains and the respective wiki page look more polished.<br>
It is one of the inherent issues of such a project, that you don’t really know what the average user does or needs. Therefore you have to use common sense™, gut feeling … .</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The more you save the further away you get from security.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>True.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If you have a reference to a case of malware that was found in a Tails USB device in a hidden folder that will be an interesting read.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Would be pointless. As soon as you use your usb device you increased your attack surface by introducing an additional point of persistence. Why did you do that? For convenience. It is always the same tradeoff. Use your favorite search engine with something like: usb malware hidden partition (or any kind of other USB exploit). Sure it would be not the average ransomware but more likely a targeted attack. Though there is always some kind of trickle down effect where the average bad guy starts to use such tools and not just the nation state attacker.<br>
Tails was on the list of Zerodium so there is certainly a demand for such a thing. Whonix is not there yet, but if it gets used more and more it probably will.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I don’t see how FDE solves any of that.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>There is certainly a higher risk the more data you have. But how did the forensics guy got to your location? Why and how did he send you some  malware in the first place? If they exploited you once they likely can do it again since they expect you to hang around at certain places/websites. With Tails they will get your IP faster, connecting to a remote wifi will maybe slow them down but as <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/entr0py">@entr0py</a> said in another thread: when they know your rough location or wifi you connect to then correlating your traffic +  on/offline times etc starts.<br>
If TheMan knocks on your door then because they already have something. The more FDE is used the more will forensics people work on getting you while the PC is running. If they get the PC with Tails or Whonix while it is running you probably lost.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Unless you keep a completely fictitious identity inside each and every action this tracking can deanonymize you.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>True. So maybe it would be a wise decision to do that because:</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>some of those people will not maintain any OPSEC at all</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>If someone at the other f***s up neither Tails or Whonix can help you.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Attack surface. Tails users are discouraged from adding more applications</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Take a look at todays Tails website <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/wink.png?v=5" title=":wink:" class="emoji" alt=":wink:"> Guess what they did. Increasing the attack surface?</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Whonix, that does not have an amnesic issue</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>It does, see my last post.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Whonix-Gateway is mininal, but we have here 2 different systems that can be compromised, plus the host, plus the hypervisor. Is this a smaller or larger attack surface?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This is the good old attack surface vs virtualization discussion which has been going for years. My gut feeling (again) tells me the virtualization side sort of won. At least a certain project which initially was a proponent of “muh attack surface” started to introduce a hypervisor not too long ago. Hiding your hardware serials is going to be hard without virtualization. I really miss some kind of PC or SBC which shares exactly the same components and serial numbers <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/frowning.png?v=5" title=":frowning:" class="emoji" alt=":frowning:"><br>
If we say attack surface is only about lines of code then you are certainly right. You can come up with a gateway of maybe a few megabytes in size and also a workstation with just the browser for something like 300-400 mb (or maybe lower depending on the OS). Still way below what Tails has. You can also just use curl or wget for “surfing” and decrease your attack surface even more. However, now you maybe stick out of the crowd. Anonymity is hard. In the broader sense attack surface or lets says vulnerable people is also about certain tradeoffs like convenience. It is harder to debug such systems, make changes, maintenance over time … . Normal users are used to some kind of windows like gui … You can create a 99.9% secure™ system for 1% of the people or a 90% secure system for 90% of the people.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/29</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 11:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-29</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="25" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Easy solution, just dump everything in whatever format, when someone criticize, imply they’re lazy or stupid or what not.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>The easy solution would be for community members to actually contribute to the project and not just complain in the forum. You have all these ideas (a lot of them good) but you keep on making excuses as to why you won’t contribute.</p>
<p>Are you going to actually help out? Or do like most critics and just stir the pot a little and leave?</p>
<p>Here is what it comes down to. Put up or shut up!</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/28</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 09:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-28</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[torjunkie]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="25" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I gave the example of Tails documentation. 3-4 paragraph pages that give an answer to a specific problem are perfect. See what they do!</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Simple solution:</p>
<p>Qubes-like “Quick Guide” sections at the top of each relevant entry.</p>
<p>e.g. <strong>Create a sys-net DispVM in Qubes:</strong></p>
<p><strong>[dom0]:</strong> qvm-create -P &lt;pool_name&gt; --template service-dvm --class DispVM --label red disp-sys-net<br>
<strong>[dom0]:</strong> qvm-prefs service-dvm virt_mode hvm<br>
<strong>[dom0]:</strong> qvm-prefs disp-sys-net provides_network true<br>
[<strong>dom0]:</strong> qvm-prefs net-disp netvm “”<br>
<strong>[dom0]:</strong> qvm-pci<br>
<strong>[dom0]:</strong> qvm-pci attach --persistent net-disp :<br>
<strong>[dom0]:</strong> qvm-prefs disp-sys-net autostart true<br>
<strong>[dom0]:</strong> qubes-prefs clockvm disp-sys-net</p>
<p>etc.</p>
<p>(No descriptions at all, just a label e.g. “sys-net DispVM Creation”, and commands. Advanced users and those in a hurry can just get it done.)</p>
<p>If someone was ambitious, simply do this for the most relevant sections of the main wiki e.g. security-related, updating etc. Create a new wiki page - “Whonix Pocket Reference” or “Whonix Cheatsheet”. Categorize the entries as relevant.</p>
<p>Then, put the maintainer tab up there with your name on it. Update it as things change, are deprecated, are updated/upgraded etc. Win a gold star from the Whonix team and end the forum debates on this easily solvable problem.</p>
<p>I estimate you could do most of the important wiki pages on the main ToC in one day’s work, maybe two.</p>
<p>There’s enough verbiage in this thread, that 5-10 pages could have been completed in the wiki with the same word count applied to this topic alone.</p>
<p>Lots of ideas and people come through the forums, but maybe 1/200 people actually contribute by hitting the edit button or submitting Whonix code.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/27</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 08:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-27</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>fish, sorry for taking your thread off-topic.</p>
<p>I generally agree with everything you say here, Whonix should be promoted based on its actual benefits, rather than try to further undermine itself using titles such as “experimental” or “research project”.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="23" data-topic="5206">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/f/bc8723/40.png" class="avatar"> fish:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Whonix must aim to be a fully torified operating system which does not allow anything running inside it to leak the real IP address. If that goal has been reached say so very clearly! Then say what the project’s real shortcomings are. <strong>A proper security audit</strong> or something else, you’d know better than me</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Now this is interesting. Was Whonix ever subject to an external security audit that was published?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/26</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 04:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-26</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>That’s exactly the reason I gave the example of Tails documentation. 3-4 paragraph pages that give an answer to a specific problem are perfect. See what they do!<br>
You can just claim  everything is perfect or you can learn from projects that are, well, more successful and have more following, and, yes the quality of how you communicate stuff matters big time in that.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Whonix/anonymity is not easy. There is lots of technical information. Shortening the pages will not help anyone understand any better. It takes time, there is no way around that.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is where you get it wrong. Thing’s aren’t easy meaning the guide should strive to be as crystal clear as possible. Many pages in the wiki take a tricky subject and then make it even more complex than it should be. I suggest you read again the page (warning: it will take time) I refer to and see for yourself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wiki pages to cluttered - the pages are broken up into sections so I’m not sure what you mean. If I want to find out about bridges. I go to the bridges page and all the information is there. As it should.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>No, it is overwhelming to get a huge page, with sections inside sections, blocks inside blocks inside blocks, that contains many things that are irrelevant to any specific user (apart from being outdated sometimes or “unfortunately not working”), when you have a question about something very specific. Specifically if you want to understand Proxys after Tor in the case of Tor Browser, you have to collect info from many different areas of the page I mentioned, and skip many others in the way. Meaning, practically you have to go through everything to make sure you didn’t miss an important detail. And, average user will not even understand half of it.</p>
<p>You forget who reads it. If you wish to write specs for engineers only, then perhaps you’re right. If you truly to be accessible to people of different backgrounds, you need to make things <em>friendly</em>. I don’t know which planet you came from, Mr. Spock. Nobody here has any experience working with people? Easy solution, just dump everything in whatever format, when someone criticize, imply they’re lazy or stupid or what not.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you would like to help out that would be awesome! If you see a mistake in the wiki just hit the edit button.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I can write specific, well understood pages for common problems. But if you just stick them as sections in a 6,000 words page that will not be helpful to anyone.<br>
Why do you think places like StackOverflow are so popular and so useful? how many votes you think an answer there, that just sends a link to a 6,000 words page of any programming lanugage’s docs, will get?<br>
Think “one problem one page”. Of course this does not apply not to all issues in the world, but to common problems. And only such that can be clearly defined and isolated to a specific issue.<br>
Example: “How can I use Proxies after Tor with Tor Browser?”. In this page we DO NOT write about every other possible application under the sun, we don’t explain what is wrt, we don’t detail every approach that “doesn’t currently work”, and we don’t discuss the relationship between proxychain developers.<br>
Simple question -&gt; simple answer. And yes, there will still be place for proper warnings, as well as a link for more detailed documentation.<br>
Interesting?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/25</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 03:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-25</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/pano">@pano</a></p>
<p>I can understand your frustration and would agree that the wiki is a little confusing at times. The wiki could use a some readability edits here and there. But frankly that is not a priority nor should it be. As you have heard the project is low on resources and that dictates what get done and when. Now, its not that we don’t want to improve the readability of the docs. It just there are much higher priority edits.  Whats important to me is users have the information they need to stay safe. If they have a question or can’t find something they can find help on the forum.</p>
<p>As you keep on mentioning all the warnings, clutter, low resources etc. I’ll address that.</p>
<ul>
<li>Warnings on every page : they serve a very important purpose. Many of those are there to keep users from making mistakes. Many of which would have serious consequences so the warnings have to stay. If you can find a way to organize those a little better that would be great But they need to be blatantly obvious to readers.</li>
<li>TODOs - not going to waste mine or anyone else’s time with this.</li>
<li>Wiki pages to long for people with time restraints: Whonix/anonymity is not easy. There is lots of technical information. Shortening the pages will not help anyone understand any better. It takes time, there is no way around that. It will get easier once your more familiar with the wiki.</li>
<li>Wiki pages to cluttered - the pages are broken up into sections so I’m not sure what you mean. If I want to find out about bridges. I go to the bridges page and <strong>all</strong> the information is there. As it should.</li>
<li>Outdated information (yes there is). Solution: Whonix community gets off there butts and starts making contributions.</li>
<li>Not enough resources to [… ] - if the community would like better Whonix docs, features etc start contributing! If you have a good idea whats stopping you? If its more experienced community member(<strong>s</strong>) telling it will not work, there is a reason. You don’t think we have thought of this stuff before? The current wiki contribs don’t have the time, Period. We have a long list of edits that take priority. Would you like the old outdated info to be updated? Or would you rather have the wiki  look pretty?</li>
</ul>
<p>If you would like to help out that would be awesome! If you see a mistake in the wiki just hit the edit button. For larger wiki contribs I would suggest copying the chapter to a text editor and make the edit there. If you try directly editing the wiki you may lose your session data. Then you’ll have to start over and let me say I’m speaking from experience. For the most part the important thing is content. Once you compete that, torjunkie and I can help you with what to do next.</p>
<p>.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/24</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 02:01:22 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-24</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Whonix experimental for how long</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[fish]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Wow this thread has exploded. It’s nice to see lots of enthusiasm, but there’s a lot of discussion here that wasn’t at all the point of this thread. When organizational stuff comes up everyone starts counting the problems they see and the mood can quickly start to look bad, but that is actually a fake mood. I for one think Whonix is a great success! The community is wonderful and the mood here feels great! There is no place I know of, where important privacy questions are listened to and addressed like here. To gain knowledge you need to make a personal effort and study, there is no other way. People who don’t understand this always have a disproportionately loud voice. Sometimes the forum answers may seem incomplete, but that is almost always a false impression. Some reasons for this:</p>
<ul>
<li>the information is readily available if you just search</li>
<li>the sources provided contain the answers or are the proper starting point for further research</li>
<li>the question is hard and no one knows the answer</li>
<li>the problem has no perfect solution or not a better one than provided</li>
<li>the people who would need to most, don’t find explanations such as this one</li>
<li>the guide <a href="http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/smart-questions.html" rel="nofollow noopener">How To Ask Questions The Smart Way</a> is not familiar</li>
</ul>
<p>The regular answer-givers may sometimes feel that they are asked to write the too obvious, but that is just part and parcel of such a project. Especially if you work on it for years, users will come and go and questions will be repeated. This a sign of good health, the project seems vibrant and active to me. I think questions and suggestions may often come out harsh when they weren’t really meant so at all. Contributors are probably prone to such an impression, the postings above speak for this.</p>
<p>Whonix has the best documentation on privacy and anonymity, it’s like a treasure. There is so much to learn here and any privacy curious user would agree. I disagree strongly with some postings above, the documentation shouldn’t only be a set of instructions to follow. In places it is outdated or incomplete, but this is not a big problem. It is mostly very good and provides a uniquely rich resource on the topic of privacy. A big shout-out to everyone who put it together! <img src="//forums.whonix.org/images/emoji/twitter/heart_eyes.png?v=5" title=":heart_eyes:" class="emoji" alt=":heart_eyes:"></p>
<p>Whonix is the most universally useful from the trio of Qubes, Tails, Whonix. Tails is something you can use on occasion, but as the number of public computers continues to fall due to ever expanding wireless networks, its significance will diminish. Already now the use case for Tails is very limited and it will continue to shrink. I think Tails users are few and far between and the website reflects this. There’s virtually no documentation and the information provided is very scarce. The support is poor and insufficient because it allows for no discussion at all. You get a very brief email from someone lacking much time and so also interest in your question. Whonix is better than Tails in every aspect and hugely superior in terms of support. There is no comparison here.<br>
Switching to Qubes is such a big step that it is only suitable for professionals or very enthusiastic users. But these users are very capable and interested so it may seem like their community is strong. Whonix is what “beginners” i.e. less knowledgeable or committed users will use. It’s like an entry point to security and privacy focused operating systems. That is why an impression may arise that more support is asked for. Let’s not forget Whonix plays a very important role in Qubes itself, there is no tool to match.</p>
<p><strong>Back to the topic of discussion</strong></p>
<p>I’m not sure how best to convey that the project is mature and recommended for use but at the same time could greatly benefit from more help. Probably any project designation would be inadequate to do this. What prompted me to start the thread were some of the goals listed <a href="https://www.whonix.org/wiki/Warning#Missing_Whonix_Features" rel="nofollow noopener">here</a> which just don’t make any sense to me. Make users more clever? Make weak password stronger? Really? Just how do you propose to do that? Don’t let perfect be the enemy of good. Like I said at the start - Whonix can’t solve all computer security problems, no one system can.</p>
<p>I don’t feel experienced or knowledgeable enough about Whonix to say what the best designation would be at this time. But I feel that some of the goals are just dreams we all have about computer technology but that no one on planet earth has found a solution for yet. Whonix must aim to be a fully torified operating system which does not allow anything running inside it to leak the real IP address. If that goal has been reached say so very clearly! Then say what the project’s real shortcomings are. A proper security audit or something else, you’d know better than me. Giving it the experimental label makes it look like it’s under heavy development and very unreliable. Saying not to rely on it for (strong) anonymity is surprising, is this also the case for Tor in general according to your criteria? Whonix is actually the best tool out there for using Tor, from what I gather this is also your view. If using Whonix is more safe than just using Tor Browser this must be obviously declared. There is no virtue or benefit in false modesty. No one is better off for it.</p>
<p>I just think more accurately conveying the state of usability and reliability of Whonix would be good at some point. There shouldn’t be a rush, but it’s definitely worth thinking about. Look at all that I wrote, but even I’m not sure how much I can rely on Whonix, given all the warnings. You really need to look long and hard before you can know and I’m not there yet. You may feel such cautiousness is exactly right and exactly how you want users to think. But this will keep Whonix always on the fringe, when it could improve the security and privacy of so many new users. Some of them won’t be careful enough to stay anonymous no matter what tool they use.  Let’s not forget the target audience of Whonix is not huge to begin with. How many computer users run hypervisors, let alone for security? More users would make the project stronger, new contributors would appear. Let Whonix grow!</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206/23</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 22:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5206-23</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-experimental-for-how-long/5206.rss">Whonix experimental for how long</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
