<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>creating plain Debian images using Whonix build script / Non-Qubes-Whonix CLI only without desktop envirionment</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/creating-plain-debian-images-using-whonix-build-script-non-qubes-whonix-cli-only-without-desktop-envirionment/3544</link>
    <description>`--gui kde` is the default and works but `--gui none` is broken and unmaintained for a while now. The implementation of that was more like an after thought and broken by design. (`--gui none` added packages to a skip list and was not a mandatory switch. The new design will be more declarative, i.e. `--some-switch` will be mandatory and opt-in things rather than disabling stuff. Just now finished cleaning up that code.

`./whonix_build supports` currently

* `--flavor whonix-gateway`
* `--flavor whonix-workstation`
* `--flavor whonix-custom-workstation`

I am considering new switches.

* `--flavor whonix-gateway-kde` (installs non-qubes-whonix-gateway package)
* `--flavor whonix-workstation-kde` (installs non-qubes-whonix-workstation package)
* `--flavor whonix-gateway-cli` (installs non-qubes-whonix-gateway-cli package, yet to be added to anon-meta-packages, same as above package without dependency on anon-shared-desktop as well without dependency on anon-shared-desktop-kde package)
* `--flavor whonix-workstation-cli` (similar to above)
* `--flavor whonix-custom-workstation`

Rather I am wondering if the following makes sense:

* `--flavor whonix-gateway-custom` (where the to be installed meta package[s] must be manually given using an environment or build config variable)
* `--flavor whonix-workstation-custom` (similar to above)

For Whonix development purposes it sometimes would be helpful to have plain Debian images available for download.

* `--flavor whonix-plain-debian-kde-minimal` (just Debian without any Whonix packages installed)
* `--flavor whonix-plain-debian-kde-whonix` (coming with whonix-repository, guest additions, grub config packages for apparmor, screen resolution and verbosity installed)

It&#39;s rather hard finding some sensible naming scheme for these command line switches. Any suggestions? Perhaps no switches for the non-default configurations and having the user enter the meta packages desired to be installed?

I also worry that deploying a plain Debian image through whonix.org would be easily confused having to do anything with anonymity. Is there a way to prevent that?</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 18:50:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Development</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/creating-plain-debian-images-using-whonix-build-script-non-qubes-whonix-cli-only-without-desktop-envirionment/3544.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>creating plain Debian images using Whonix build script / Non-Qubes-Whonix CLI only without desktop envirionment</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p><code>--gui kde</code> is the default and works but <code>--gui none</code> is broken and unmaintained for a while now. The implementation of that was more like an after thought and broken by design. (<code>--gui none</code> added packages to a skip list and was not a mandatory switch. The new design will be more declarative, i.e. <code>--some-switch</code> will be mandatory and opt-in things rather than disabling stuff. Just now finished cleaning up that code.</p>
<p><code>./whonix_build supports</code> currently</p>
<ul>
<li><code>--flavor whonix-gateway</code></li>
<li><code>--flavor whonix-workstation</code></li>
<li><code>--flavor whonix-custom-workstation</code></li>
</ul>
<p>I am considering new switches.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-gateway-kde</code> (installs non-qubes-whonix-gateway package)</li>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-workstation-kde</code> (installs non-qubes-whonix-workstation package)</li>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-gateway-cli</code> (installs non-qubes-whonix-gateway-cli package, yet to be added to anon-meta-packages, same as above package without dependency on anon-shared-desktop as well without dependency on anon-shared-desktop-kde package)</li>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-workstation-cli</code> (similar to above)</li>
<li><code>--flavor whonix-custom-workstation</code></li>
</ul>
<p>Rather I am wondering if the following makes sense:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-gateway-custom</code> (where the to be installed meta package[s] must be manually given using an environment or build config variable)</li>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-workstation-custom</code> (similar to above)</li>
</ul>
<p>For Whonix development purposes it sometimes would be helpful to have plain Debian images available for download.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-plain-debian-kde-minimal</code> (just Debian without any Whonix packages installed)</li>
<li>
<code>--flavor whonix-plain-debian-kde-whonix</code> (coming with whonix-repository, guest additions, grub config packages for apparmor, screen resolution and verbosity installed)</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s rather hard finding some sensible naming scheme for these command line switches. Any suggestions? Perhaps no switches for the non-default configurations and having the user enter the meta packages desired to be installed?</p>
<p>I also worry that deploying a plain Debian image through <a href="http://whonix.org">whonix.org</a> would be easily confused having to do anything with anonymity. Is there a way to prevent that?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/creating-plain-debian-images-using-whonix-build-script-non-qubes-whonix-cli-only-without-desktop-envirionment/3544/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/creating-plain-debian-images-using-whonix-build-script-non-qubes-whonix-cli-only-without-desktop-envirionment/3544/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 18:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-3544-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/creating-plain-debian-images-using-whonix-build-script-non-qubes-whonix-cli-only-without-desktop-envirionment/3544.rss">creating plain Debian images using Whonix build script / Non-Qubes-Whonix CLI only without desktop envirionment</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
