<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Unable to connect to TOR (bootstrap)</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/unable-to-connect-to-tor-bootstrap/1349</link>
    <description>Whonix 11 Gateway and Workstation (latest release) won&#39;t be able to bootstrap TOR unless I switch Network Adapter from NAT to Bridge - then it will work just fine - under Windows 10. Debian Linux works fine when using Whonix 11 via VirtualBox.

OP - solution to this problem? Bridge can cause known security issue unless it&#39;s switched back to NAT otherwise Bridge will broadcast my network location to the rest of the node which I want to avoid.

LMK.

EDIT: nevermind, apparently only one program can request TAP driver at a time. Disconnect.me (desktop edition) was using TAP driver so VirtualBox wasn&#39;t able to request it because it was in use. Make sense now, now it&#39;s working just fine. Lesson learned. All I had to do is turn off Disconnect.me - that&#39;s it.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 20:01:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/unable-to-connect-to-tor-bootstrap/1349.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Unable to connect to TOR (bootstrap)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[omegamegaman]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Whonix 11 Gateway and Workstation (latest release) won’t be able to bootstrap TOR unless I switch Network Adapter from NAT to Bridge - then it will work just fine - under Windows 10. Debian Linux works fine when using Whonix 11 via VirtualBox.</p>
<p>OP - solution to this problem? Bridge can cause known security issue unless it’s switched back to NAT otherwise Bridge will broadcast my network location to the rest of the node which I want to avoid.</p>
<p>LMK.</p>
<p>EDIT: nevermind, apparently only one program can request TAP driver at a time. <a href="http://Disconnect.me" rel="nofollow noopener">Disconnect.me</a> (desktop edition) was using TAP driver so VirtualBox wasn’t able to request it because it was in use. Make sense now, now it’s working just fine. Lesson learned. All I had to do is turn off <a href="http://Disconnect.me" rel="nofollow noopener">Disconnect.me</a> - that’s it.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/unable-to-connect-to-tor-bootstrap/1349/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/unable-to-connect-to-tor-bootstrap/1349/1</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 20:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-1349-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/unable-to-connect-to-tor-bootstrap/1349.rss">Unable to connect to TOR (bootstrap)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
