<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reasonable setup</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187</link>
    <description>I am currently running VirtualBox on Windows and want to improve my setup.
I went though quite a lot of the recommendations in the wiki, but there&#39;s a limit to the time I can allocate to setting up stuff, I would like your opinion as to the following:

- Host: Debian Stretch
- Encryption of a hidden volume with TrueCrypt7.1a (or Veracrypt?) 
- Whonix VMs inside VirtualBox, in the encrypted volume - yes, I read that KVM is recommended but as I am already familiar with VB I prefer to stay with that at this point (unless it seriously undermines my security, and I didn&#39;t get this impression going through the wiki). The KVM installation guide immediately proceeds to fixing problems and  dealing with bugs..
- Connection, possibly through a remote public wifi with a directional antenna. Not sure about this one, plausible deniability will be a bit harder with such a setup..

I am interested to hear your opinions, I know where the wiki is or how to perform a web search ;-)</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 10:12:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>General Tor and Anonymity Talk</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="39" data-topic="5187" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I understand that now, I am still not clear though  about the advantage of immutable drives over always restoring the state to a particular snapshot.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>there is essentially no difference. immutable drives automate that process. other drive states require you to do that manually.</p>
<aside class="quote">
<blockquote>
<p>I previously thought deletion of the temporary data is done when the machine is powered off, but as you mentioned (and as I’ve seen when I tested the immutable drives) it happens only at the next activation of the machine - so performing an active step after shutdown is required anyway.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>if new data was immediately wiped after you shut down your virtual machine with immutable drives, you would never be able to update it.</p>
<aside class="quote">
<blockquote>
<p>For either of those cases - say we restored the machine to a previous state (for a normal drive), or just restarted it (in the case of an immutable drive) - doesn’t wiping available space help on the forensics front as well?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>it might. depending on the type of drive, there may be some issues. but a wipe of your free space through one method or another is a tactic used.</p>
<aside class="quote">
<blockquote>
<p>Even in Tails, when working on ongoing projects one will need to save data somewhere, and clear it when it’s not necessary any more, so wiping issues still need to be handled.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>disk wiping is an issue that involves a number of variables and generally involves a threat scenario where your computer or disk is obtained by an enemy. this is yet another example of where software alone is probably not enough.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/43">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/43</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 10:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-43</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Ok, and what about the case of wiping available space on a non-SSD HD, on the host, for the purpose of clearing previously saved VM states?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/42">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/42</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 06:02:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-42</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="40" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/g/df705f/40.png" class="avatar"> goldstein-otg:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If we’re talking about SSD,AFAIK no there is no easy way to securely delete Files on an SSD.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I wouldn’t trust anything to secure delete individual files on flash based storage.  There is nothing that can reliably do that.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.usenix.org/legacy/events/fast11/tech/full_papers/Wei.pdf">https://www.usenix.org/legacy/events/fast11/tech/full_papers/Wei.pdf</a></p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/41">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/41</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 01:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-41</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[goldstein-otg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote no-group" data-post="39" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>doesn’t wiping available space help on the forensics front as well?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>If we’re talking about SSD,AFAIK no there is no easy way to securely delete Files on an SSD.<br>
See:<br>
</p><aside class="onebox stackexchange">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://askubuntu.com/questions/794612/how-to-securely-wipe-files-from-ssd-drive" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">askubuntu.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
      <a href="https://askubuntu.com/users/367990/byte-commander" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
    <img alt="Byte Commander" src="//forums.whonix.org/uploads/default/original/2X/d/d6f092aa97f2eef0fe6d625f45dc4dc5d2db96ca.jpg" class="thumbnail onebox-avatar" width="128" height="128">
  </a>
<h4>
  <a href="https://askubuntu.com/questions/794612/how-to-securely-wipe-files-from-ssd-drive" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">How to securely wipe files from SSD drive?</a>
</h4>

<div class="tags">
  <strong>hard-drive, ssd, shredding, secure-erase</strong>
</div>

<div class="date">
  asked by
  
  <a href="https://askubuntu.com/users/367990/byte-commander" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">
    Byte Commander
  </a>
  on <a href="https://askubuntu.com/questions/794612/how-to-securely-wipe-files-from-ssd-drive" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">09:58AM - 04 Jul 16 UTC</a>
</div>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
<p></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only way to prevent the leakage of deleted files to someone with direct access to the drive is to encrypt them in the first place and keep the encryption key safe from prying eyes.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://lwn.net/Articles/480269" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">lwn.net/Articles/480269</a></p>
<p>This seems to fix the Issue but i haven’t looked into it.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/40">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/40</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 01:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-40</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="38" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/tempest/40/349_1.png" class="avatar"> tempest:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>i don’t want the point of immuitble drives to be misconstrued. it is not anti-forensic. files will be created for use sessions with immutible drives. they are simply erased when you start the virtual machine on another occasion. thus, if someone has decrypted your hd, file recovery of such sessions is possible. the immutible drive setup is only for mitigation of less advanced malware threats.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I understand that now, I am still not clear though  about the advantage of immutable drives over always restoring the state to a particular snapshot. I previously thought deletion of the temporary data is done when the machine is powered off, but as you mentioned (and as I’ve seen when I tested the immutable drives) it happens only at the next activation of the machine - so performing an active step after shutdown is required anyway.</p>
<p>For either of those cases - say we restored the machine to a previous state (for a normal drive), or just restarted it (in the case of an immutable drive) - doesn’t wiping available space help on the forensics front as well? Even in Tails, when working on ongoing projects one will need to save data somewhere, and clear it when it’s not necessary any more, so wiping issues still need to be handled.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/39">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/39</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 18:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-39</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="36" data-topic="5187" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>When running, the hidden operating system appears to be installed on the same partition as the original operating system (the decoy system). However, in reality, it is installed within the partition behind it (in a hidden volume).</p>
</blockquote>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>there’s an additional encrypted partition. again, that will be a red flag, particularly if it is noticed by an attacker that you have a 500 gig hd with approximately only 250 gigs available to your operating system.</p>
<aside class="quote">
<blockquote>
<p>But if we put that idea aside, what do you of the following instead:</p>
<ul>
<li>VirtualBox with immutable drives as you suggested. This should take care of say, basic forensics level.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>i don’t want the point of immuitble drives to be misconstrued. it is not anti-forensic. files will be created for use sessions with immutible drives. they are simply erased when you start the virtual machine on another occasion. thus, if someone has decrypted your hd, file recovery of such sessions is possible. the immutible drive setup is only for mitigation of less advanced malware threats.</p>
<p>if anti-forensics is of particular concern, tails is likely a better choice over others.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/38">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/38</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2018 13:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-38</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="31" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_1.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>If pano heavily disagrees</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>pano does not heavily disagree (pano would have appreciated a personal message though, instead of public flogging, it would have worked just as well). In any case, point taken, pano will keep it as technical as possible and will abstain from discussing wider issues.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/37">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/37</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:25:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-37</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="35" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/tempest/40/349_1.png" class="avatar"> tempest:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>if i’m not mistaken, this is relatively easy to determine as well. what’s the size of the hd? what’s the size of the partitions for the loaded os? not equal? red flag</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>If I understand correctly the whole disk size is accounted for. But I didn’t go into the details and I don’t have a good enough understanding of disk structure for that:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When running, the hidden operating system appears to be installed on the same partition as the original operating system (the decoy system). However, in reality, it is installed within the partition behind it (in a hidden volume). All read/write operations are transparently redirected from the system partition to the hidden volume. Neither the operating system nor applications will know that data written to and read from the system partition is actually written to and read from the partition behind it (from/to a hidden volume).</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But if we put that idea aside, what do you of the following instead:</p>
<ul>
<li>Host: Debian, with LUKS FDE  set at installation. This should take care of theft, loss, random visitors, fools.</li>
<li>VirtualBox with immutable drives as you suggested. This should take care of say, basic forensics level.</li>
<li>Sensitive data always saved on a separate USB drive, LUKS encryted. This adds a physical aspect - location of the USB when not plugged in.</li>
<li>Clear logs and history (where can I find everything that is saved by the VMs?), and use something like Nautilus-wipe regularly for deletion of files and clear “available space” in VMs as well as in the host.</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/36">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/36</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 11:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-36</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="29" data-topic="5187" data-full="true">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>A bit more on the subject of encryption.<br>
Veracrypt allows a hidden operating system:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/VeraCrypt%20Hidden%20Operating%20System.html" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/VeraCrypt%20Hidden%20Operating%20System.html</a></p>
<p>So with this setup, users has two systems that are encrypted: the decoy OS, that can be the one the user actually uses for normal activities (it actually should be used, to appear that it is used often), and the hidden OS.</p>
<p>Veracrypt boot loader does not know if there is a hidden system or not. It follows the same actions in both cases (try to use the password for one location, then another, even if there is no hidden volume).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>if i’m not mistaken, this is relatively easy to determine as well. what’s the size of the hd? what’s the size of the partitions for the loaded os? not equal? red flag. with veracrypt, you have an additional partition with encrypted information for such a set up. same risks as discussed before apply</p>
<p>again, at the end of the day, “plausible deniability” with encryption is more theoretical than practical. it involves a risk component that simply isn’t there if you are in the company of an attacker with no problematic data. minimizing risk is key here.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/35">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/35</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 20:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-35</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="31" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_1.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I was wondering how I should handle threads like this:</p>
<p><a href="//forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-and-tails-discussion">http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-and-tails-discussion</a></p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Its very difficult to know if a users posts are due to a lack of knowledge or they are arguing just for the sake of arguing.  Knowing what action should be taken (if any) is even more difficult. Regardless, there comes a point when continuing the thread would no longer benefit the community. The problem is this is also hard to know.</p>
<p>Part of the solution may be for the mods to communicate with each other when they see the beginnings of a potential issue. The longer it goes for, the more embolden the user gets. Intervene sooner and it never gets to that point (When I say intervene I mean communicate with the user). Then if it becomes a problem the mods can decide the best course of action. Always better to get feedback from each other before any action is taken (if possible).</p>
<p>Our job it to lessen Patrick’s workload so we need to start being more proactive. Keep in mind its very important that moderators actions ( or lack there of ) are consistent. This is why communication is vital. Plus jr mods could use a little  guidance from time to time as well.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="33" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/e/8dc957/40.png" class="avatar"> entr0py:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>adding per-forum stickied posts describing what type of posts are appropriate; and what information needs to be provided to get help. also include links to troubleshooting, faq, how to ask questions, unsupported, free support principle, free speech, etc.</p>
<p>marking posts with stackexchange-like tags when appropriate (too vague, off-topic, opinion-based, etc) and linking back to stickied posts</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Great idea! Can I help?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/34">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2018 00:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-34</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[entr0py]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>First, in <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/pano">@pano</a>’s defense, he hasn’t been destructive (by vandalizing threads or spamming) and he hasn’t issued personal attacks or insults. I think he’s well within forum rules as they stand. Some people ask questions to get answers, some people ask questions to give their own answers.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="31" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_1.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>What do I do?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Tell the moderators to do their job. It’s the moderator’s job to keep threads on topic and sufficiently focused. And to lock them when they become unproductive and run in circles. I’ve always erred on the side of free speech but that comes at a cost of time and aggravation. And most importantly, as Patrick said, leads to a buildup of FUD when the community gets exhausted by intentional or misinformed trolling. Speaking for myself, I’ll be more assertive going forward along with:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>adding per-forum stickied posts describing what type of posts are appropriate; and what information needs to be provided to get help. also include links to troubleshooting, faq, how to ask questions, unsupported, free support principle, free speech, etc.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>marking posts with stackexchange-like tags when appropriate (too vague, off-topic, opinion-based, etc) and linking back to stickied posts</p>
</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/33">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/33</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 16:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-33</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[goldstein-otg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="31" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_1.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>pano (and similar later accounts) can go on as is, I unsubscribe from</p>
<p>threads and do actual development, community deals with these</p>
<p>discussions if deemed useful</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I would “vote” for this, i think <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/entr0py">@entr0py</a> <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/0brand">@0brand</a> and <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/tempest">@tempest</a> are doing a great job in this discussion and if something useful comes out of these Posts one can create a task at phabricator to notify you.<br>
I think these Posts are important to show how professional our Moderators work and that even the unspecific Posts from Pano get a proper response.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="31" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/patrick/40/17_1.png" class="avatar"> Patrick:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>The feedback by pano at the moment doesn’t help to move the Whonix</p>
<p>project forward. It’s currently not in a format that is actionable.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I guess a “bad” example does help and shows other users how they should Post feedback and suggestions.</p>
<p>my 2 satoshis</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/32">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/32</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-32</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[Patrick]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <blockquote>
<aside class="quote" data-post="29" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>(It is interesting to note though that when discussing various solutions and protection mechanisms the adversary is deemed all-powerful, all-knowing with control over ISPs, VPNs, Entry and Exit relays, has absolute legal authority and what not. But when discussing Whonix components, the adversary is somehow reduced to a script-kiddie sending trojans by mail).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s impossible to tell if the motivation is an honest attempt to<br>
contribute or deliberate destructive trolling. While motivation matters<br>
(why I am writing this wall of text), in result, it doesn’t matter and<br>
is the latter.</p>
<p>I was wondering how I should handle threads like this:</p>
<p><a href="//forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-and-tails-discussion">http://forums.whonix.org/t/whonix-and-tails-discussion</a></p>
<p>I am under no obligation to read everything or to discuss every subject<br>
with everyone until it’s discussed until everyone is happy and agrees.<br>
It’s also not possible time wise as the project grows.</p>
<p>Question to the community:<br>
<em>What do I do? Just ignore, unsubscribe form such forum threads and hope<br>
the community will deal with it?</em></p>
<p>It takes far less time to can ask more questions and make allegations<br>
than to rebut them. So in a way, makings things dirty is a lot easier<br>
than cleaning up things. So while the usefulness is unclear, at best it<br>
takes away energy and time from the Whonix community and at worst<br>
everyone gives up and questions and allegations remain unchallenged and<br>
a source of FUD.</p>
<p>A huge backlog of analysis isn’t helpful either. Let’s do research,<br>
development and deployment at the Whonix project. But a ton of research<br>
that is theoretic, not well organized and not actionable actually takes<br>
away time from actual progress, development.</p>
<p>The feedback by pano at the moment doesn’t help to move the Whonix<br>
project forward. It’s currently not in a format that is actionable.<br>
Theoretic discussions are old and plentiful online. There are places<br>
where these are welcome and I can understand the mental fun of reading<br>
them and engaging in them. That’s in essence how I got interested in<br>
first security, later anonymity and then started working on Whonix.</p>
<p>In essence, what the Whonix project needs is clear, concise, well<br>
described, actionable tickets on <a href="http://phabricator.whonix.org">phabricator.whonix.org</a> and people who<br>
implement those.</p>
<p>If pano heavily disagrees, pano is free to move on to other endeavors in<br>
places where pano’s style of discussion is more appreciated. pano is<br>
also welcome to use or not use Whonix as everyone else including raising<br>
any opinion in other places which welcome such (own blog, other forum,<br>
public protest :), …).</p>
<p>Something similar happened with the Tails forum long time ago. In<br>
reaction, the Tails forum was closed. History won’t repeat in Whonix<br>
forums. Whonix’s forums purpose will be limited to Whonix user support<br>
and productive research and development. Won’t be a free speech platform<br>
side project.</p>
<p>Thoughts on by the community are welcome in public or private. Possible<br>
outcomes:</p>
<ul>
<li>pano (and similar later accounts) can go on as is, I unsubscribe from<br>
threads and do actual development, community deals with these<br>
discussions if deemed useful</li>
<li>pano (and similar later accounts) gets a warning to slow down (and if<br>
ignored account disabled)</li>
<li>suggestions…?</li>
</ul>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/31">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/31</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 11:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-31</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="29" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>(It is interesting to note though that when discussing various solutions and protection mechanisms the adversary is deemed all-powerful, all-knowing with control over ISPs, VPNs, Entry and Exit relays, has absolute legal authority and what not. But when discussing Whonix components, the adversary is somehow reduced to a script-kiddie sending trojans by mail).</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Some of the users you’re conversing with (enr0py) have a much better understanding of Whonix. Trying to incite a reaction is not how you get your point across. Its done by convincing users of your argument.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/30">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/30</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 10:21:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-30</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>A bit more on the subject of encryption.<br>
Veracrypt allows a hidden operating system:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/VeraCrypt%20Hidden%20Operating%20System.html" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/VeraCrypt%20Hidden%20Operating%20System.html</a></p>
<p>So with this setup, users has two systems that are encrypted: the decoy OS, that can be the one the user actually uses for normal activities (it actually should be used, to appear that it is used often), and the hidden OS.</p>
<p>Veracrypt boot loader does not know if there is a hidden system or not. It follows the same actions in both cases (try to use the password for one location, then another, even if there is no hidden volume).</p>
<p>So, in this case:</p>
<ul>
<li>Data saved by the OS should all be kept hidden. It’s not VirtualBox installed in a hidden partition while the OS saves data all over the place.</li>
<li>When forced to give the password (Veracrypt boot loader makes it obvious that there is something encrypted), user provides the password to the decoy system (those with theatrical tendencies can try to resist already at this stage, until it begins to really hurt LOL). The decoy system should seem legit enough, since it is actually being used daily for everything but the most sensitive activities. Or it can even contain enough info (embarrassing / confidential / grey area legal) the user is not happy but still willing to provide, to assist in plausible deniability.</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, if the adversary had concrete information that suggests more data should be stored elsewhere, this will not work. But it might in the cases adversary must collect evidence in order to take significant steps against user.</p>
<p>And no, it may also not work if the adversary can accurately correlate activity times etc.</p>
<p>(It is interesting to note though that when discussing various solutions and protection mechanisms the adversary is deemed all-powerful, all-knowing with control over ISPs, VPNs, Entry and Exit relays, has absolute legal authority and what not. But when discussing Whonix components, the adversary is somehow reduced to a script-kiddie sending trojans by mail).</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/29">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/29</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 08:55:41 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-29</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Yes, I had another look, and installing gnome-disk-utility made things much easier.<br>
I managed to encrypt a USB with it from Whonix-Workstation, as well as open it from another Debian VM.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/28">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/28</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 05:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-28</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>it’s not particularly complicated for fde. you can install it with an initial debian, ubuntu or other linux flavor install. it’s an option in the installer programs.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/27">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/27</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 05:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-27</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="10" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/e/8dc957/40.png" class="avatar"> entr0py:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>I’ll also emphasize that security theorycrafting often ignores the costs of complexity. You may want to consider that the chance of you corrupting / deleting / losing the password to your hidden volume(s) is greater than the probability that plausible deniability works in your favor.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>Started to look into LUKS, way too complicated and I can see why mistakes can easily be made there. Too much for me at this point, I still consider myself a beginner re everything that has to do with Linux, I will stick to TrueCrypt / Veracrypt.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/26">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/26</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 11:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-26</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[goldstein-otg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Onionshare or magic wormhole are another option and if you don’t have internet you could encrypt the data and put it on an sdcard and hide it or even swallow it.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/25">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/25</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 14:42:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-25</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>encrypt the data before you host it. trust of the server not needed.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/24">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/24</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 14:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-24</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="22" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/tempest/40/349_1.png" class="avatar"> tempest:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>if the internet is available in your destination, there is simply no need to run the risks of traveling with the data on your physical devices.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I agree, but then you move the problem elsewhere. Now you need to trust some kind of remote storage provider.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/23">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/23</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 13:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-23</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[tempest]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="21" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/p/3e96dc/40.png" class="avatar"> pano:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Now, when your adversary does have an authority over you, but, absent evidence the most they can do is some short time arrest or a trial that has reasonable chances to fail, while the content of your data, if revealed, can have much more serious consequences, this is a much more interesting discussion in my opinion.</p>
<p>In this case protection of the data is a higher priority than avoiding pissing off your adversary or making them “even more persistent” . Now what would you do in this case?</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>this is why i stress simply not having the data. if you have to travel with a computer, travel with a clean one. if the internet is available in your destination, there is simply no need to run the risks of traveling with the data on your physical devices.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/22">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 12:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-22</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[pano]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>I think that again people look at a specific scenario without realizing that in this case it doesn’t matter much what you do.<br>
If you’re dealing with an adversary that can torture you or lock you up indefinitely without any serious evidence or reasonable legal proceedings, just because you are a suspect for some reason (or because the way you behave), then they can do it no matter what you do, whether you use encryption or not, whether you carry any sort of device at all or not. They can lock you up and torture you until you give up your secrets regardless of any digital data stored or not stored somewhere. This isn’t a question of encryption or technology. The discussion in this case is superfluous.</p>
<p>Now, when your adversary does have an authority over you, but, absent evidence the most they can do is some short time arrest or a trial that has reasonable chances to fail, while the content of your data, if revealed, can have much more serious consequences, this is a much more interesting discussion in my opinion.</p>
<p>In this case protection of the data is a higher priority than avoiding pissing off your adversary or making them “even more persistent” . Now what would you do in this case?</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/21">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 11:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-21</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[goldstein-otg]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="14" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/0/ec9cab/40.png" class="avatar"> 0brand:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>Kali linux has a nuke patch for cryptsetup which nukes all key slots when a certain password in entered</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>I remember reading from the Kali devs (can’t find it atm) that they don’t think that this is really a good/safe option in most Cases.</p>
<aside class="quote" data-post="19" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/letter_avatar_proxy/v2/letter/0/ec9cab/40.png" class="avatar"> 0brand:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>This would likely get you in more legal trouble if officials found out so its not really plausible. Plus they may copy the HDD before entering the password for further analysis later on.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>This, even if you had a attacker this stupid to let you “nuke” the disk, they would be even more eager and persistent to lock you up, plus its common like <a class="mention" href="http://forums.whonix.org/u/0brand">@0brand</a> said to copy the Disk before anything happens.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/20">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 10:46:55 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-20</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reasonable setup</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[0brand]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <aside class="quote" data-post="18" data-topic="5187">
<div class="title">
<div class="quote-controls"></div>
<img alt="" width="20" height="20" src="//forums.whonix.org/user_avatar/forums.whonix.org/tempest/40/349_1.png" class="avatar"> tempest:</div>
<blockquote>
<p>this patch is pretty much security theater.</p>
</blockquote>
</aside>
<p>You could use this when asked for your password when crossing a border checkpoint.</p>
<p>This would likely get you in more legal trouble if officials found out so its not really plausible. Plus they may copy the HDD before entering the password for further analysis later on.</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/19">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 09:45:58 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-5187-19</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/reasonable-setup/5187.rss">Reasonable setup</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
