<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>TUNNEL_FIREWALL (VPN connection established but Tor not bootstrapped)</title>
    <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/tunnel-firewall-vpn-connection-established-but-tor-not-bootstrapped/6282</link>
    <description>Hello, I&#39;m trying to setup the Whonix Gateway VPN firewall. It&#39;s not the first time that I use the firewall therefore I am already familiar with the process. The VPN connection on the gateway is up and running (as clearnet user I can connect to the internet) but I am not able to fully connect to Tor. I think that I was able to make a connection to Tor twice though (I could see connections with arm) but I still had issues with whonixcheck and sdwdate. Neither whonixcheck nor I was able to check for apt updates. sdwdate was simply not able to synchronize the time at all. If I connect without a VPN then it all works just fine. I already tried another VPN service but I had the same issue and I tried to change the time manually which also did not work.

Do you have any ideas what else I could try? I&#39;m using the latest Whonix Gateway version in Virtualbox. I also tried Whonix 13 (same results)</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 13:51:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <category>Support</category>
    <atom:link href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tunnel-firewall-vpn-connection-established-but-tor-not-bootstrapped/6282.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
        <title>TUNNEL_FIREWALL (VPN connection established but Tor not bootstrapped)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[5zwnx6ffjpo9]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[
            <p>Hello, I’m trying to setup the Whonix Gateway VPN firewall. It’s not the first time that I use the firewall therefore I am already familiar with the process. The VPN connection on the gateway is up and running (as clearnet user I can connect to the internet) but I am not able to fully connect to Tor. I think that I was able to make a connection to Tor twice though (I could see connections with arm) but I still had issues with whonixcheck and sdwdate. Neither whonixcheck nor I was able to check for apt updates. sdwdate was simply not able to synchronize the time at all. If I connect without a VPN then it all works just fine. I already tried another VPN service but I had the same issue and I tried to change the time manually which also did not work.</p>
<p>Do you have any ideas what else I could try? I’m using the latest Whonix Gateway version in Virtualbox. I also tried Whonix 13 (same results)</p>
          <p><a href="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tunnel-firewall-vpn-connection-established-but-tor-not-bootstrapped/6282/1">Read full topic</a></p>
        ]]></description>
        <link>http://forums.whonix.org/t/tunnel-firewall-vpn-connection-established-but-tor-not-bootstrapped/6282/1</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 13:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.whonix.org-post-6282-1</guid>
        <source url="http://forums.whonix.org/t/tunnel-firewall-vpn-connection-established-but-tor-not-bootstrapped/6282.rss">TUNNEL_FIREWALL (VPN connection established but Tor not bootstrapped)</source>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
